<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>"Herman" Yeast Starter</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Breads</cat>
        <cat>Cakes</cat>
        <cat>Cookies</cat>
        <cat>Sourdough</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>package</unit></amt>
        <item>Active dry yeast</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Warm water (105-115 F)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  In large bowl mix flour, sugar, yeast and salt. Gradually stir in the
  water; beat or whisk until smooth. Cover with towel; set in warm (80 - 80
  deg F) draft-free place - the kitchen or other warm room in summer or in
  cold weather on top of insulated furnace or radiator, on a buffer such as a
  folded heavy towel or pillow. Stir 2 or 3 times a day for about 3 days or
  until starter is bubbly an produces a yeasty aroma. Transfer to larger
  bowl, large jar or plastic container. Cover partially (tilt lid or punch
  holes in plastic cover); refrigerate. Makes about 1-1/2 to 2 cups starter,
  depending on thickness. It can be creamy or as thick as dough because of
  room conditions, the age of "Herman" and other variables. *Note about
  "Herman"* Herman is a "cultured" dough you add to new dough to give it
  distinctive flavor or texture it otherwise wouldn't have. But unlike other
  starters that require constant feeding, stirring and using, this one
  doesn't make a slave of you. You replentish "Herman" only after you use it.
  And if it's longer than 14 days, put it in the freezer until you're ready.
  The flavor of this starter evolves as it ages- mildly sweet when young,
  more like sourdough when older. Care and Feeding of "Herman" The starter
  should be used within 14 days and replenished or fed immediately after each
  use.  To feed starter, stir or whisk in 1 cup each flour and milk and 1/2
  cup sugar; misture need not be completely smooth. Wait at least 24 hours
  before using again.  If you do not plan to use the starter within 14 days,
  cover tight and freeze. Freezing slows down the fermentation, so let stand
  at room temperature several hours or till thawed and bubbly before reusing.
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
