<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>"Irish Coffee" Pudding</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Irish</cat>
        <cat>Desserts</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>8</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Very strong coffee</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Powdered gelatine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Irish whiskey*</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>10</qty>
          <unit>fluid ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Whipping cream</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Crushed walnuts</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  *You can also use Irish Mist.  -- Separate the yolks from the whites of
  eggs.  In a bowl, cream with yolks with the sugar.  Heat the coffee until
  hot but not boiling:  add the gelatine and dissolve it in the coffee. Add
  this mixture to the yolks and sugar.  Beat well and put the bowl over a pot
  of boiling water.  Continue beating until mixture begins to thicken. remove
  from heat, and when the bowl has cooled a little, place it over cracked ice
  and continue stirring. When the mixture is on the point of setting, whip
  the cream and fold it in. Add the whiskey or Irish Mist. Lastly, fold in
  the well-beaten egg whites. Pour into a souffle dish that has a double
  thickness of parchment paper tied around it:  the paper should come up 3
  inches above the top of the souffle dish.  Oil a jam-jar or bottle and
  press it down into the center of the pudding.  Leave to set. Remove the
  paper collar by easing around the circumference with a knife dipped in hot
  water.  Remove the jar or bottle, and fill the center with: 1 cup heavy
  cream, whipped, sweetened with 1 T granulated sugar. You can also decorate
  the exposed sides of the pudding with crushed walnuts, pressed on with the
  palm of your hand.
  Posted to MM-Recipes Digest  by scotlyn@juno.com (Daniel S Johnson) on Mar
  11, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
