<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>"Soy Vey!" Challah</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Bread</cat></categories>
      <yield>12</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Soy milk; room temperature</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Honey</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2 1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Yeast</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Bread flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Soy flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Soybean oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg yolk (you can use egg substitute if you prefer)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Poppy seeds (for topping)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg white (for glaze)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  From: mackey.1@osu.edu (Lynda Mackey)
  
  Date: 29 Sep 1994 21:46:42 GMT
  This recipe won first place in a special competition at the Ohio State Fair
  this year: Cooking with Ohio's Soy Foods, sponsored by the Ohio Soybean
  Council. It also received an "award of Excellence" rosette.
  
  You can also use this recipe in a bread machine, either by going through
  the whole cycle, or by using the dough setting and shaping the dough into a
  large braid, which is what I usually do.. If you're not wild about soy, you
  can change the soy milk to water, and the soy oil to another kind of oil.
  Instructions:
  
  1. Mix the soy milk, honey, and yeast and set it aside for 10 minutes.
  
  2. Combine the bread flour and soy flour in a large bowl.
  
  3. Add the oil, eggs, and egg yolk to the milk, honey, and yeast mixture.
  Stir with a wooden spoon until blended.
  
  4. Add the flours to the liquid mixture, stir until a dough is formed, and
  turn the dough out onto a floured board.
  
  5. Knead until dough is smooth and elastic, about 10 minutes.
  
  6. Form into a ball, coat with a bit of soybean oil, and place in a covered
  bowl.
  
  7. Let rise until doubled in bulk, about an hour.
  
  8. Punch the dough down, knead about 3 minutes, and braid or shape into any
  desired form.
  
  9. Transfer to a greased baking sheet. Cover and let rise until doubled,
  about
       45    minutes.
  
  10. Preheat oven to 375 degrees.
  
  11. Beat the egg white with a folk. Use a brush to coat the top of the
  loaf. Sprinkle poppy seeds on top of loaf.
  
  12. Bake at 375 degrees for 20 minutes.
  
  13. Cool on a rack.
  
  REC.FOOD.RECIPES
  
  From rec.food.cooking archives.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
