<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>A Better Burger</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/4</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>100 percent ground chuck</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground black pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Hamburger buns and desired toppings</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  1. Break up chuck to increase surface area for seasoning. Sprinkle salt and
  pepper over meat" toss lightly with hands to distribute seasoning. Divide
  meat into four equal portions (5 ounces each)- with cupped hands,
  
  toss one portion of meat back and forth to form loose ball. Pat lightly to
  flatten into 1 -inch-thick burger, 3 1/2 to 4 inches across, using
  fingertips to create pocked, textured surface. Repeat with remaining
  portions of meat.
  
  2. If grilling, heat enough coals to make hot fire. When coals are hot and
  covered with white ash, spread them in single layer. Position grill rack
  
  and lid-, heat until rack is very hot, about 5 minutes. Place burgers on
  
  rack-, cover and grill, turning once, to desired doneness as follows: 3
  minutes per side for rare, 4 minutes per side for medium-rare, 5 minutes
  
  on first side and 4 minutes on second side for medium, and 5 minutes per
  
  side for well done. If pan-broiling, heat skillet over medium-high heat.
  
  When skillet is hot (drops of water flicked into it evaporate immediately),
  add parties and cook, turning once, to desired doneness, using same times
  as if grilling. Serve immediately with buns and desired
  
  toppings.
  
  Cook's Illustrated, July/Aug. 1995, Page 15. Credit: Pam Anderson with
  Karen Tack.
  
  Nationality: USA Course: entree Season:any Method: grilled
  
  Start to Finish 1 hour Preparation 5 minutes Attention 45 minutes Finishing
  a minute or less
  
  Converted from Mangia!, Cook's Illustrated 1993-1995 Cookbook
  
  NOTES : You can grill this burger, or pan-broil it in a twelve-inch
  cast-iron or nonstick skillet or a stovetop grill pan.
  Recipe by: Cook's Illustrated, July/Aug. 1995, Page 15
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest by "Hobbs, D B                 USO"
  &lt;hobbs@lbcapo1.uso.unisys.com&gt; on Mar 10, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
