<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>A Big Pot of Greens</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>bunches</unit></amt>
        <item>Turnip; collard, or mustard greens, (or a combination)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Dried small; red peppers, (up to 4)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Chicken stock or water; (up to 2)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt pork; optional</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar; optional, (up to 2)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Tear off thick stems and place greens in the sink. Cover with water.
  Sprinkle a small amount of salt over greens and stir. Allow water to settle
  a few minutes. Carefully lift out greens and place in a colander or large
  bowl. (If you have a double sink, the other side works great.)
  
  Rinse out sink to eliminate any grit that may have dropped from greens.
  Return greens to sink and cover with water again. Allow any remaining grit
  to settle and unplug drain so that water runs out.
  
  Tear large leaves into pieces and place in a large stockpot, Dutch oven or
  saucepan with a lid. Without shaking off too much water, add greens to pan,
  along with whole, dried red peppers.
  
  It may be difficult to get all the greens in the pan, but cram them in.
  Cover pan with lid and place over medium heat. Cook just until leaves wilt
  and greens fit easily into pan.
  
  Add just enough water or chicken stock to almost cover greens. If desired,
  add salt pork. Bring liquid to a boil, reduce heat and simmer until greens
  are tender, about 30 minutes. Stir in sugar during last 10 minutes of
  cooking.
  
  Makes 10 servings.
  
  Posted to recipelu-digest by molony &lt;molony@scsn.net&gt; on Mar 10, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
