<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Abalone Meuniere Mandarin</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Chinese</cat>
        <cat>Seafood</cat>
        <cat>Ceideburg 2</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>5</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>(7 1/2-ounce) cans Mexican abalone</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>8</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Shrimp</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Fat pork</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Water chestnuts, minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit>pinches</unit></amt>
        <item>Chives</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Ginger water, to taste (see note)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Salt and MSG</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>ounce</unit></amt>
        <item>Maize (corn) flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Chive and ginger oil (see note)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs, beaten</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>5/8</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Shaoxing wine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Chicken stock</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  The following four recipes are from a Chron article called "Foreign
  Intrigue" by Alice Cuneo that featured recipes from various
  consulates in the City.  This first one is from the Consulate of the
  People's Republic of China.  It's a sophisticated (but uncomplicated)
  banquet dish featuring abalone, shrimp and porkfat.
  
  Abalone stuffed with minced shrimp, from Shen Xuliang of the Chinese
  consulate.
  
  Trim the abalone, removing rough parts, and cut into flat rounds. Chop
  shrimp and fat pork to a paste consistency; stir in the water
  chestnuts, chives and ginger water.  Season with salt and MSG.
  
  Create the abalone "sandwiches" by spreading an abalone round with
  shrimp paste, then topping with another round.  Dredge "sandwiches"
  in maize flour and set aside.
  
  Heat chive and ginger oil in a wok over medium heat, swirling the oil
  to coat all sides of the wok.
  
  Dip the abalone "sandwiches" in the flour, then in eggs.  Fry in the
  hot oil until abalone is tender and golden.  Add Shaoxing wine,
  chicken stock, salt and MSG.  Bring to a simmer, adjust the
  seasonings and simmer for 3 to 4 minutes.  Serve immediately.
  
  NOTE:  Chive and ginger oil is oil in which chives and ginger have
  been cooked.  To make at home, heat 4 ounces oil in a wok set over
  medium heat. Toss in 1 or 2 tablespoons fresh snipped chives and 3
  slices fresh ginger. Stir-fry until fragrant, then proceed with
  recipe.  (Remove ginger slices before serving.)
  
  Ginger water is available in Chinese markets.
  
  From the San Francisco Chronicle, 6/15/88.
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/cberg2.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
