<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>About Pickling</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Info</cat>
        <cat>Pickles</cat>
        <cat>Joy</cat>
        <cat>Jw</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients/>
    <directions>
      <step>  Although many vitamins and minerals are leached away in the process,
  pickles remain popular as piquant side dishes and relishes long after
  more efficient food preservation techniques such as refrigeration,
  freezing and canning surplanted this pioneer mainstay as a primary
  food storage method.
  
  Short Brine Pickling:
  
  In this process the vegetables are soaked in brine 24 hours to draw
  out moisture but they are not fermented. To keep, they must have
  boiling hot vinegar poured over them which penetrates and preserves
  as well as crisping them. The final step after jarring and sealing is
  a 15 minute boiling water bath to kill any enzymes. If pickles show
  evidence of fermentation after being stored away [bubbles or leakage]
  either discard or immediately re-pickle.
  
  Because of the acids involved use stoneware, pottery, glass and
  enamel or stainless steel kettles. For stirring and transferring use
  a long handled stainless or wooden slotted spoon. Make sure all
  equipment is clean and grease free. Pickles should be stored in
  sterilized glass jars with glass lids. For sterilizing techniques,
  refer to "About Jams, Jellies and Preserves". [Posted by me last week]
  
  Fruits and vegetables should be very fresh, in prime condition without
  blemishes or bruises and scrubbed dirt free.
  
  Garlic should be blanched 2 minutes before adding or removed before
  jarring.
  
  Spices should be whole not ground and in a removable spice bag.
  
  Water should be low iron, low sulphur and soft. It can be softened
  with up to 1 tablespoon calcium oxide [lime] per quart. If your water
  supply is inadequate buy distilled water or collect rain water.
  
  Salt should be additive free Pickling salt. Regular table salt will
  cloud the liquid.
  
  Vinegar should be 6% acetic acid. Use white distilled vinegar not
  cider, wine or flavored vinegars.
  
  Lime water or cherry and grape leaves in the liquid will make pickles
  crisp. Use alum sparingly if at all and do not use the Copper Sulfate
  called for in old fashioned recipes as it is mildly poisonous in
  excessive amounts.
  
  Pickles should be stored at least 6 weeks to achieve maximum flavor
  and although they will keep for years should be consumed within one
  year as the flavor will deteriorate over time.
  
  This is based on extracts from the Joy of Cooking with amendments and
  additions by Jim Weller.
  Posted to MM-Recipes Digest V3 #235
  
  Date: Wed, 28 Aug 1996 21:56:51 -0500
  
  From: pickell@cyberspc.mb.ca (S.Pickell)
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
