<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>About Gardenburger(R)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Vegetarian</cat>
        <cat>Rice</cat>
        <cat>Brandnames</cat>
        <cat>Gardenburge</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Gardenburger® patty</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  * Serve as a burger, sandwich, pita, or wrap. * Top with grilled mushrooms,
  onions and bell peppers on sourdough. * Stuff in baked potato skins with
  low fat cheese, dijon mustard and fresh chives. * Serve open face on whole
  wheat sourdough with tomato and melted low fat cheese. * Dice and stir into
  scrambled egg-substitute or bake into a quiche.
  
  GARDENBURGER® Veggie MedleyTM
  
  * Serve with cucumber, lettuce, tomato and red onion on foccacia. * Grill
  and dice on salads and soups instead of croutons. * Add grilled eggplant
  and zucchini on an oat bun. * Dice with sprouts, water chestnuts and
  vegetables for a new twist on stir fry. * Grill and dice in whole wheat
  pita bread with feta cheese, olives and low fat yogurt dressing.
  
  GARDENBURGER® Zesty BeanTM
  
  * Serve with avocado slices, salsa, cilantro and butter lettuce in a wrap.
  * Grill and dice on tortilla chips with shredded low fat cheese and salsa
  for tasty GardenNachos. * Grill and dice in tacos, burritos, tostados and
  enchiladas. * Stir into chili or toss on a taco salad. * Serve with
  egg-substitute and salsa for low fat Huevos Rancheros.
  
  GARDENSAUSAGETM
  
  * Serve on a whole wheat English muffin or bagel with tomato and an egg
  substitute. * Try as a savory sandwich with lettuce, pickles and onions on
  sourdough. * Grill and dice into scrambled egg-substitute with veggies and
  low fat cheese. * Grill and dice on pizza, soups and salads. * Grill and
  slice into wedges and serve with hot mustard and whole grain crackers.
  
  Busted by kitPATh href= http://www.foodshow.com/ &gt;visitor's window
  &gt;gardenburger exhibit. See also &gt;http://www.gardenburger.com
  
  Recipe by: Gardenburger Home Page Exhibit Directory
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest V1 #975 by KitPATh &lt;phannema@wizard.ucr.edu&gt; on
  Dec 30, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
