<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>About Yeast Breads - Ingredients</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Crocker</cat>
        <cat>Info</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients/>
    <directions>
      <step>        1 x  See Below
  
  Flour: All-purpose flour is the most widely used flour. It contains a
  special protein called gluten the structure builder of bread. When mixed
  with liquid and kneaded or beaten, the gluten stretches and gives
  elasticity to the dough by trapping bubbles of gas formed by the yeast.
  Some flours, such as rye and whole wheat, lack sufficient gluten and
  usually are used in combination with all-purpose flour. Self rising flour,
  which already contains leavening and salt, is not often recommended for
  yeast breads. However, all recipes were tested with self rising flour;
  adjustments are indicated when necessary.
  
  Yeast: Yeast is a live plant that gives off a gas that makes dough rise: It
  is very sensitive-too much heat will kill it, but cold will stunt its
  growth. Yeast is available in several forms: regular active dry yeast,
  quick-acting active dry yeast and compressed yeast. All of our recipes have
  been tested with dry yeast. Most of the recipes follow the traditional
  method of dissolving the yeast in warm water (105 to 115F). However, some
  recipes yield better results by mixing the yeast with the flour, then
  beating in very warm water (120 to 130F).
  
  Liquids: Water or milk are the most commonly used liquids. Water gives
  bread a crisper crust; milk, a velvety texture and added nutrients.
  
  Sweeteners: Sugar, honey or molasses provide "food" for the yeast, enhance
  flavor and help brown the crust.
  
  Salt: A flavor agent that is needed to control the growth of the yeast and
  prevent overrising, which can cause the bread to collapse.
  
  Fat: Added to contribute to tenderness and flavor.
  
  Eggs: For flavor, richness and color, eggs are sometimes added.
  
  Source: Betty Crocker's Cookbook, 6th Edition
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
