<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>About Coffee</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Beverages</cat>
        <cat>Crocker</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>See Below</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Start with a thoroughly clean coffee maker. Wash after each use with hot,
  soapy water and rinse well with hot water; never scour with an abrasive
  pad. When cleaning an automatic coffee maker, follow the manufacturer's
  directions.
  
  Always use fresh coffee and freshly drawn cold water. Never use hot water,
  especially in automatic coffee makers; it changes percolating time.
  
  Serve steaming-hot coffee as soon as possible after brewing. If coffee must
  stand any length of time, remove grounds and hold coffee at serving
  temperature over very low heat.
  
  Keep ground coffee tightly covered.
  
  PREPARATION METHODS Automatic: Follow manufacturer's directions for
  selecting grind of coffee (special ones are available), measuring and
  brewing the coffee and holding the coffee at serving temperature.
  
  Drip: Measure cold water and heat to boiling. Preheat coffeepot by rinsing
  with very hot water. Measure drip-grind coffee into filter paper in cone or
  into filter section of coffee-pot depending on the type of drip pot used.
  Pour measured fresh boiling water into upper container; cover. When
  dripping is completed, remove upper container and filter section.
  
                 COFFEE CHART Strength For each serving* of Brew Ground
  Coffee         Water Weak 1 level tb 3/4 cup Medium 2 level tb 3/4 cup
  Strong           3 level tb 3/4 cup *Best general recommendation.
  
  Source: Betty Crocker's Cookbook, 6th Edition
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
