<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>About Tea</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Beverages</cat>
        <cat>Crocker</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>See Below</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  The tea you buy is a delicate blend of some 20 to 30 varieties. Quality
  varies according to the soil, climate and altitude in which it is grown and
  the age and size of the leaves when they are picked.
  
  Broadly classified, there are three types: black, oolong and green.
  
  Black tea derives its color from a special processing treatment in which
  the leaves are allowed to oxidize. This turns the leaves black and produces
  a rich brew.
  
  Oolong tea is semioxidized. Its leaves are brown and green. It brews light
  in color.
  
  Green tea is not oxidized, thus the leaves remain green. The brew is pale
  green in color.
  
  PREPARATION METHOD Whether you use loose tea or tea bags, the preparation
  method is the same:
  
  Start with a spotlessly clean teapot made of glass, china or earthenware.
  Add rapidly boiling water; allow to stand a few minutes, then pour out.
  
  Heat cold water to a full rolling boil.
  
  Add tea or bags to the warm pot, allowing 1 teaspoon of loose tea or 1 tea
  bag for each cup of tea desired. Pour boiling water over tea (3/4 cup for
  each cup of tea); let stand 3 to 5 minutes to bring out the full flavor.
  Stir the tea once to ensure uniform strength.
  
  Do not judge the strength of tea by its color; You must taste it.
  
  Strain the tea or remove tea bags. Serve with sugar and milk or lemon if
  desired.
  
  Prepare instant tea, a concentrate, according to the directions on the jar.
  
  Source: Betty Crocker's Cookbook, 6th Edition
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
