<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>About Red Mulberry</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Info</cat>
        <cat>Fruits</cat>
        <cat>Jw</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients/>
    <directions>
      <step>  How to Recognize: The only mulberry native to Canada, it is a short-
  trunked deciduous tree under 30 feet in height. The bark is reddish brown,
  separating in long, flaky plates. The yellowish green leaf blades are
  large, up to 5" long, widest below the middle and have hairy undersides.
  They are simple with pointed tips and the stems are long with 3 prominent
  veins at the base of each leaf. Male and female flowers are borne in
  separate clusters appearing with or before the first leaves. The fruits are
  dark red to black compact aggregates which resemble blackberries.
  
  White mulberry is an Asian tree whose foliage is used for silkworm feed and
  has been introduced as an ornamental and is an escapee throughout eastern
  North America. It has lustrous smooth leaves and whitish or reddish fruit.
  
  Where to Find: Southernmost Ontario in moist, rich soils often mixed with
  other hardwoods.
  
  How to Use: Harvest easily by spreading sheets under the tree and shaking
  the branches gently. Juicy and sweet when ripe; delicious raw, in fruit
  beverages, or in baked desserts. Alone or in combination with acid fruits
  such as gooseberries or cherries. Can be frozen or dried like raisins. Use
  as in blackberry and raspberry recipes.
  
  WARNING: Be careful not to eat raw fruit before it is ripe. Unripe fruit
  and the milky sap in the leaves and stems are toxic and can cause gastric
  upsets. The leaves and stems may also cause dermatitis if touched by
  susceptible individuals. From: Edible Wild Fruits and Nuts of Canada,
      published by the National Museums of Canada,
      ISBN 0-660-00128-4
  
  Posted by: Jim Weller
  Posted to MM-Recipes Digest V3 #190
  
  Date: Mon, 8 Jul 1996 23:14:17 -0500
  
  From: pickell@cyberspc.mb.ca (S.Pickell)
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
