<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Abraysham Kabaub ( Silk Kebab)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Desserts</cat></categories>
      <yield>30</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>SYRUP</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Granulated sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Lemon juice</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Saffron threads (optional)</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>OMELET</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>8</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Eggs</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>pinch</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>TO FINISH</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Oil</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Finely chopped pistachios *</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Ground cardamom</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  *Note: Instead of pistachio nuts, walnuts may be used if desired. Dissolve
  sugar in water in heavy pan over medium heat. Bring to the boil, add lemon
  juice and saffron and boil for 10 minutes. Cool and strain into a 25 cm (10
  inch) pie plate.  Keep aside. Break eggs into a casserole dish about 20 cm
  (8 inches) in diameter. The size and flat base are important. Add salt and
  mix eggs with fork until yolks and whites are thoroughly combined - do not
  beat as eggs must not be foamy. Heat oil in an electric frypan to 190 C
  (375 F) or in a 25 cm (10 inch) frypan placed on a thermostatically
  controlled hot plate or burner. Have ready nearby a long skewer, the plate
  of syrup, a baking sheet and the nuts mixed with the cardamom. A bowl of
  water and a cloth for drying hands are also necessary. Hold dish with eggs
  in one hand next to the pan of oil and slightly above it. Put hand into
  egg, palm down, so that egg covers back of hand. Lift out hand, curling
  fingers slightly inwards, then open out over hot oil, fingers pointing
  down.  Move hand across surface of oil so that egg falls in streams from
  fingertips.  Dip hand in egg again and make more strands across those
  already in pan.  Repeat 3 to 4 times until about an eighth of the egg is
  used.  There should be a closely meshed layer of egg strands about 20 cm (8
  inches) across.  Work quickly so that the last lot of egg is added not long
  after the first lot. Rinse hands quickly and dry. Take skewer and slide
  under bubbling omelet, lift up and turn over to lightly brown other side.
  The first side will be bubbly, the underside somewhat smoother. When golden
  brown lift out with skewer and drain over pan. Place omelet flat in the
  syrup, spoon syrup over the top and lift out with skewer onto baking sheet.
  Roll up with bubbly side inwards. Finish roll should be about 3 cm (1 1/4
  inches) in diameter.  Put to one side and sprinkle with nuts. Repeat with
  remaining egg, making 7 to 8 rolls in all. Though depth of egg diminishes,
  you will become so adept that somehow you will get it in the pan in fine
  strands. When cool, cut kabaubs into 4-5 cm (1 1/2 to 2 inch pieces and
  serve. These keep well in a sealed container in a cool place.
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
