<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Adult Monster Pasta - Part 1</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Sun-dried</cat>
        <cat>Pasta</cat></categories>
      <yield>8</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Olive oil; divide</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh garlic; mince, divide</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sun-dried tomato pieces; chop, (drain if in oil)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Dry white wine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Whipping cream or heavy cream</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Salt and fresh ground pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Wild mushrooms; trim, slice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Red or yellow bell pepper; dice fine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh chives; snip, divide</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Parmesan cheese; grate, divide</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Monster pasta</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Eggs</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Beets; roast</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Spinach; saute</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Semolina flour; divide</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pinch</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  In a large skillet, heat 1 tb of the olive oil over medium heat. Add 1 tb
  of the garlic and cook until tender, 1-2 minutes; do not brown. Add the
  sun-dried tomato and stir with garlic. Add the white wine, cooking until
  reduced by half, about 5 minutes. Stir in the whipping or heavy cream;
  continue cooking until thick enough to coat the back of a spoon, about 8
  minutes. Season with salt and pepper. Remove from the heat. Puree the sauce
  in batches. Place about half the sauce in a blender and close the cover,
  leaving the small, removable feeder cap in the center slightly open to let
  heat escape. Place a kitchen towel over the cover. Hold the feeder cap in
  place and pulse mixture and puree until smooth. (Pureeing a hot mixture can
  cause a heat buildup that can blow the lid off a blender.) Pour the pureed
  sauce into a bowl and repeat procedure with remaining sauce. Reserve all
  sauce. In a large nonstick skillet, heat the remaining 1 tb olive oil over
  medium heat. Add the remaining 1 tb garlic and cook until tender, 1-2
  minutes; do not brown garlic. Add the mushrooms, cooking until golden,
  about 5 minutes. Add the red or yellow pepper, cooking until just warmed,
  about 3 minutes. Add the reserved sauce. Stir in 2 tb of the chives and
  adjust seasonings if necessary; keep warm. In a large pot of boiling salted
  water, cook Monster Pasta until al dente, about 3 minutes. Drain in a
  colander. Add the pasta to the skillet with the sauce and mix gently to
  combine. To serve, evenly divide and mound the pasta in the centers of
  eight warm, rimmed soup plates. Evenly divide the remaining 2 tb chives
  over each serving. Sprinkle each serving with 1 tb tb of Parmesan cheese
  and serve. 627 cal; 31 gr fat; 45% fat. Continued in Part 2. Source: The
  Detroit Free Press. MM Waldine Van Geffen vghc42a@prodigy.com.
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest by "M. Hicks" &lt;nitro_ii@email.msn.com&gt; on Feb 4,
  1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
