<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Aioli</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Sauces</cat></categories>
      <yield>2</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Cloves of garlic, peeled</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Pine nuts</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Potatoes, boiled, peeled and</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Juice of a lemon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Olive oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg, lightly beaten</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>   Combine the garlic and nuts in a blender or food processor and puree. Add
  the potatoes, and puree. Pour potato mixture into a bowl and, using a
  whisk, beat in the lemon juice, a bit at a time. Gradually add the olive
  oil in a thin stream while continuing to beat so oil combines with potato
  mixture. When oil has been absorbed, add the egg and beat well. Giovanni de
  Bourbon-Sicily, French Vogue Note: If you omit the raw egg, you still get a
  nice sauce. According to an ancient proverb, "Garlic is as good as 10
  mothers." If the latest flu bug has hit your house--and whose has
  escaped--you may be ready to test claims for garlic's medicinal powers.
   Since 1983, the National Library of Medicine has gathered 125 scientific
  papers on the therapeutic potential of garlic. They've found some
  interesting material. It's clear that allicin, the smelly compound in
  garlic, is an antibiotic--but only if taken raw. Heat destroys the elements
  that have antibiotic properties. Raw or cooked, garlic can also work as a
  decongestant and expectorant for common colds and bronchitis. Regularly
  eating raw garlic seems to act as a deterrent for these ailments, according
  to Dr Irwin Ziment. A Dr Abdullah, who eats a couple of raw garlic cloves a
  day, claims he has not had a cold since 1973. Admittedly, eating raw garlic
  won't help your social life but Kyolic, a deodorized garlic compound from
  Japan, may allow you to have good health and good friends. I've also heard
  of fresh garlic imported from Japan that supposedly is deodorized. If any
  of you have found it in local stores, let us know. It would be interesting
  to hear if it lives up to the claims made for it.
   Since having the flu is no fun, this may be a good time to take your
  chances and share some pungent garlic dishes with friends and family--for
  health's sake. It's easy to add minced fresh garlic to hummus or tabbouleh,
  Mid-Eastern dishes you can buy in many deli's and natural food stores. If
  you're brave, you can try my grandmother's cold cure. Spread a slice of
  black bread with butter, then layer thin slivers of raw garlic all over the
  bread. Eat this and it'll cure what ails you...or keep everyone so far away
  that no germs will reach you! Aioli is a milder way to enjoy raw garlic.
  This French condiment, a sort of mayonnaise, is a puree of garlic, boiled
  potatoes, olive oil and egg. Serve it with chicken, grilled fish, dolloped
  into soup and on vegetables.
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
