<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Al's Chicken Schnitzel</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Poultry</cat>
        <cat>Main dish</cat></categories>
      <yield>3</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>kilogram</unit></amt>
        <item>Chicken Breasts</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Eggs</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Bread Crumbs(Krummies etc)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  All MEASUREMENTS and CURRENCY mentioned below in in METRIC and Australian
  currency. In 1 kg you usually get 3 breasts so cut them in half as
  described below and 2 halfs usually make a filling meal.Costs about $10 to
  serve a family since adult can have 2 halfs with mashed potato and mini
  carrots etc and children can have 1. This is my first Recipe so here goes.
  
  Cut Chicken Breasts down the middle into 2 parts. Use Spiked Mallet to beat
  chicken till its a mit thinner so it cooks better.Also trim any skin or get
  skinless breasts to reduce amount of calories.
  
  Get 3 plates.On the first plate sift flour on to plate. On second
  plate,beat eggs and pour onto a deep plate. On third put the bread crumbs
  on it.
  
  Dip or cover breasts in flour.Shake off excess.Coat breast with egg either
  by brushing on or dipping on plate.Then cover in bread crumbs and put on
  plate.
  
  On this is done you are ready to cook them.Now I usually cook mine so that
  the bread crumbs brown but dont get burnt so the schnitzel is very
  soft.Since I'm not an experienced cook but have to do the cooking for the
  family (Im 15) I dont know if Im undercooking them or what but they taste
  best that way.Just cook them and when the look cooked cut in half and if
  the meat is white(like chicken sould look not the colour of an uncooked
  fillet) they are cooked.I cook on medium heat in a frypan with some oil.
  Serving Suggestions: In the Colder months this meal is best served with
  Mashed potato and gravy as well as carrots and any other vegetables you
  like.
  
  In the Warm months my very favourite is a Schnitzel Burger. I put the
  lettuce on the bottom,Beetroot next,then the scnitzel,then a thin pineapple
  ring,and mayo.Excellent in summer months.2 of these make a filling and
  tasty meal.
  
  Well there you go.And comments and critisism would be appreciated. CYA!
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
