<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Albuquerque Chili</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Vegetable</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>STEP 1</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Onion; chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Fresh tomatoes; peeled and chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Fresh Anaheims; chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Fresh red bell peppers; chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>6</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Carrots; chopped (optional)</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>STEP 2</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Dried Anchos; stems and seeds removed</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Dried Passillas; stems and seeds removed (up to)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>12</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Dried Japones; stems removed (adjust heat level to your liking) (up to)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Fresh Habaneros; stems removed (adjust heat level to your liking) (up to)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>12</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Cloves garlic (I like lots of garlic in this recipe)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Cubic inch fresh ginger root; chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Bottle brown ale or dark beer</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  SirWill1 &lt;SirWill1@omni.voicenet.com&gt;
  
  STEP 1: Put all ingredients in a large pot with a tablespoon or two of oil.
  Cook until browning just begins.
  
  STEP 2: Pour beer into blender and start a high speed vortex going.  Keep
  it covered as you drop in first the ginger and garlic and get them good and
  liquefied, then add the peppers.  Add more beer (or some of the juices from
  the vegetables you're cooking) if it gets too thick.  When it's all nicely
  liquefied, pour it into the pot.
  
  Simmer an hour or so and give it a taste test.  You might want to add a can
  of tomato paste, maybe a tsp of Kitchen Bouguet, or some herbs.  I usually
  find myself tossing in a bit of allspice and cinnamon, maybe half  a tsp of
  each, and sometimes some herbs (rosemary, sage, oregano, dill,  even a
  little mint and/or fresh dill. I've also sliced scallions crosswise into
  little circles and added them late so they stay crisp and flavorful.
  
  Meat is optional.  When I add meat I use about a half pound each of chopped
  sirloin and chopped turkey cooked together in a separate pot until well
  cooked, then I drain all the fat off in a colander and wash it  down with
  hot water before adding it to the mix. Keeps the whole thing fairly low in
  fat.
  
  Another variation is to pour off and reserve the juices from the original
  pot of veggies before adding the blended chiles and use it for a soup
  starter.
  
  Let it simmer at least another two to three hours.
  
  Note -- no salt!  Be good to your cardiovascular system!  If there's
  something missing, try a little cumin or coriander or a bit more allspice
  and/or cinnamon!
  
  I use this as a spaghetti sauce or a topping for nachos.  It lasts forever
  (I've kept it as long as three weeks) in the bottom of the fridge in  tight
  tupperware containers and gets better with age.
  
  CHILE-HEADS ARCHIVES
  
  From the Chile-Heads recipe list.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe
  Archive, http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
