<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Alioli (Garlic-Oil)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Sauce</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Cloves (large) fresh garlic</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pinch</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Olive oil</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  haworth_pedro@prc.com     phaworth@gmu.edu
  
  Yesterday I was digging through an old footlocker with memories and I came
  across a recipe that I was given by the cook at the boarding school where I
  studied in Barcelona.  This stuff, as I remember, is really, really good on
  light colored meats, i.e. chicken,  rabbit, pork, fish, etc.  I translated
  it from Catalan (I was a little rusty) and initially came up with a really
  strange translation, but this is what I settled on: by Jordi Pijoan (he
  always reminded me of Einstein, but with a cleaver) Escola Internacional,
  Sta. Clara, Barcelona, Espana
  
  1. In a mortar crush the four cloves of garlic to a pulp, seasoning them
  lightly with a pinch of salt.
  
  2. Once they form a paste, with your *left* hand (that's what the recipe
  says) slowly drip olive oil into the mortar while with your right hand you
  continue stirring and crushing the mixture with the pestle, keeping in mind
  to always move the pestle in the same direction at a consistent pace.
  Continue this procedure until a fine paste, with good consistency, is
  formed.
  
  If for any reason the alioli does not thin (that is, if the paste does not
  become very fine), or if it becomes too light after it has been mixed,
  remove it from the mortar and place in it a piece of bread to soak up the
  excess oil. You then remove the bread and place the garlic back in the
  mortar and begin to *slowly* drip oil and mix in a consistent fashion.
  
  I remember making a batch several years ago where I also added a chiltepe,
  but I really can't remember how it turned out.  I'm going to try it tonight
  and I'll let you guys know.  Please feel free to experiment and please,
  please, post results, suggestions, etc.!!!
  
  CHILE-HEADS ARCHIVES
  
  From the Chile-Heads recipe list.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe
  Archive, http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
