<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Almond Letters Messapine</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Baking powder</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>COLD water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Almond paste</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs; slightly beaten</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs whites; slightly beaten</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Referred to by family members as just Messapine. It is a traditional treat
  at Christmas. Mother mixes up the pastry and dough and invites one of the
  daughters to help her roll it out the following day. The notable
  differences in our recipes are the addition of baking powder and the way it
  is rolled out. Some of the younger family members use your method but there
  is a significant loss to the traditional flakiness of the pastry. Well
  worth the effort and a fun evening for mother and daughter.
  
  Pastry Dough: Sift together the flour and baking powder. Cut in the butter
  till it is fine as meal. Add the COLD water and mix into a smooth dough.
  Cover and refrigerate.
  
  Filling: Blend the almond paste and sugar in a blender or food processor.
  Add the eggs to the almond sugar mixture and mix thoroughly. Cover and
  refrigerate.
  
  REFRIGERATE both the pastry and filling overnight. To prepare for baking:
  Remove filling from fridge and allow to warm to room temperature. Keep
  dough refrigerated. Divide the dough into 8 parts. Shape each part into a
  ball and roll into a very large rectangle. The pastry should be almost
  paper thin. Carefully spread the filling evenly over the pastry: Divide the
  filling into 8 portions. The filling is sticky and the fragile pastry tears
  easily. Use small dollops of filling and spread with a spatula. Roll up
  like a jelly roll. Starting from a long side. Place on large baking sheets.
  Brush with egg slightly beaten egg white and sprinkle with sugar. Bake at
      425    degrees F. for 25 minutes.
  
  Posted to TNT Recipes Digest by "Jackie VanderVeen" &lt;jackie@lasal.net&gt; on
  Feb 14, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
