<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Almond Mushroom Pate</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Appetizer</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Margarine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>small</unit></amt>
        <item>Onion; chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Clove garlic; minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sliced mushrooms</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Tarragon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Blanched whole almonds</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Lemon juice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Soy sauce</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>dash</unit></amt>
        <item>White pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Cream cheese; Kefir cheese, or Neufchatel cheese (optional)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Garnish: slivered or finely chopped almonds; fresh parsley sprigs; pimiento strips; or sweet red pepper strips; optional</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Date: Sun, 03 Mar 1996 20:39:06 -0500
  
  From: Walt Gray &lt;waltgray@mnsinc.com&gt;
  In a large skillet, melt margarine. Add onion, garlic, and mushrooms. Saute
  until tender but not browned. Add tarragon, stir until it is softened.
  
  Pour mixture into a bowl of food processor. Add remaining ingredients.
  Process until mixture is smooth. Add cheese if you prefer a more spreadable
  consistency. Spoon into a serving bowl. Top with garnish of your choice.
  Makes
    1-1/2    cups.
  
  People who do not like ordinary pate seem to love this one. Vary the herbs
  and substitute the vegetables as you wish. Serve with water crackers, thick
  slices of crusty French bread, thin slices of whole wheat bread, or
  unsalted whole wheat crackers. May be frozen.
  
  VARIATIONS: ~ Substitute other vegetables for the mushrooms (maybe
  broccoli.) ~ Substitute 1/2 t fennel for the tarragon and 1 c whole pecans
  for the
  
  almonds ~ vary the flavor by using other seasonings such as basil, oregano,
  dillweed,
  
  curry powder, or nutmeg.
  
  MM-RECIPES@IDISCOVER.NET
  
  MEAL-MASTER RECIPES LIST SERVER
  
  MM-RECIPES DIGEST V3 #64
  
  From the MealMaster recipe list.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
