<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Almond Meringue Crisps</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Cookie</cat></categories>
      <yield>30</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Sliced almonds</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>5</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Caster (granulated) sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Egg whites</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/8</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Cream of tartar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/8</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Almond extract/essence</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Icing (confectioners') sugar</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>CHOCOLATE GANACHE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>6</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Plain (bittersweet) chocolate broken into 4 pieces</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3 1/2</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>(fl) double cream</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Caster sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Unsalted butter</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  From: yu105639@laurel.yorku.ca (William Ing)
  
  Date: 29 Dec 1994 13:11:41 -0500
  From Marcel Desaulniers' Death By Chocolate; The last word on a consumming
  Passion.  This recipe starts is divided into two parts; Almond Meringue
  Crisps for the base and a Chocolate Ganache as the topping.
  
  Equipment: Measuring spoons, 2 baking sheets, food processor with metal
  blade, electric mixer with balloon whisk, rubber spatual, greasproof paper,
  piping bag, double boiler, cling film, whisk, 2 pint/1.5L saucepan, small
  stainless steel bowl, medium star nozzle..... or equivalent.
  
  Preheat oven to 325F/170C/Gas 3.  Lightly toast almonds on a baking sheet
  in oven for 5 minutes. Let cool to room temp. Reduce oven temp to
  225F/100F/ Gas 1/4
  
  Coarsely process toasted almonds with 1oz/28g sugar into 1/8" size pieces
  and set aside until needed.
  
  Line two baking sheets with greaseproof paper.  Create meringue by whisking
  egg whites on medium speed with balloon whick until frothy (approx 1 min).
  Add cream of tartar and salt and increase speed to high until whites begin
  to stiffen, then gradually add 4oz/113g caster sugar. The egg whites should
  form peaks that are stiff but not dry. Add almond essence and whisk on high
  for an additional 30 seconds. Remove from mixer and using a rubber spatula,
  fold in the chopped almonds and cornflour.
  
  Fill a piping bag (with no nozzle) with the meringue.  Pipe 30 - 1.5"
  mounds of meringue onto the paper-covered baking sheets (~15 per sheet).
  Make an indentation into the centre of each meringue by dipping your thumb
  in some icing sugar and then into the centre of each meringue. Place
  meringues in the preheated oven and bake for 30 minutes. Reduce temperature
  to 200F/100C/ Fas 1/4 and bake for an additional 2 hours. Remove from oven
  and allow to cool for 20 min before handling.
  
  While  crisps are cooling, prepare ganache.  heat 1" of water in the bottom
  half of a double boiler over medium heat.  Place the plain chocolate in the
  top half of the double boiler.  Tightly cover the top with cling film and
  allow to heat for 5-6 minutes.  Remove from heat and stir until smooth.
  
  Heat the  double cream, 1 tsp of sugar and nbutter in a saucepan over
  medium high heat. Bring to a gentle boil. Pour boiling cream over the
  melted chocolate and stir until smooth. Transfer teh ganache from the
  boiler to a small stainless steel bowl. Cover wtih cling film and
  refrigerate until firm (~20min). Transfer ganache to a piping bag fitted
  with a medium sized star nozzle. Pipe approx. 1.5 tsp of ganache into the
  center of each almond meringue crisp.
  
  REC.FOOD.RECIPES ARCHIVES
  
  /COOKIES
  
  From rec.food.cooking archives.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
