<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Almond Brussels Sprouts Soup (Atlas)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>*nava atlas</cat>
        <cat>Lowfat</cat>
        <cat>Soups</cat>
        <cat>Vegetarian</cat>
        <cat>Mcrecipe</cat></categories>
      <yield>8</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Blanched almonds</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Olive oil</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Onion; chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Celery stalk; chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Clove garlic; minced</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Potato; peeled and diced</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Dry white wine</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Tomato; diced</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/2</qty>
            <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
          <item>Brussels sprouts; trimmed and coarsely chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2 1/2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt substitute; seasoned</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>SERVE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Lemon juice; or more to taste</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Salt and pepper</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Slivered almonds; for garnish, OR chopped, optional</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Chopped fresh parsley; for garnish</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>OPTIONAL RELISH</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Extra virgin olive oil</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Reserved sprouts; thinly sliced</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Slivered almonds</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Coarsely ground pepper</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Lemon zest</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Fresh lime juice; or to taste</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Place the almonds in a food processor. Process until very finely ground.
  Continue to process until the mixture almost resembles a nut butter,
  stopping the machine and scraping down the sides with a plastic spatula
  from time to time.
  
  Heat the oil in a soup pot. Add the onion and saute over medium heat until
  it is golden. Add the celery, garlic, potato, wine, tomato, and about two
  thirds of the brussels sprouts (reserve and set aside the remainder). Add
  enough water to barely cover the vegetables. Bring to a simmer, then add
  the almond butter and seasoning mix. Simmer gently, covered, over low heat
  for 35 to 40 minutes or until all the vegetables are tender. Remove from
  the heat.
  
  Transfer the solid ingredients to a food processor and puree, in batches if
  necessary, until smooth. Transfer back to the soup pot and return to low
  heat. Thin with a small amount of water if the soup is too thick.
  
  In a separate saucepan, steam the reserved brussels sprouts in about 1/2
  inch of water until they are bright green and crisp-tender. Add them to the
  soup along with lemon juice, and salt and pepper to taste. Serve the soup
  at once, or allow to stand for an hour or so before serving, then heat
  through as needed. Garnish each serving with some chopped or slivered
  almonds if desired and fresh parsley.
  
  Calories: 164; Total fat: 8 g; Protein: 4 g; Carbohydrate: 16 g;
  Cholestetol: 0 g; Sodium: 31 mg.
  
  REVIEW : Soup would feed 8 with salad and fruit; or 4 as is. RELISH: Thinly
  slice the reserved sprouts; heat oil in small wok-like saute pan. When very
  hot, quickly saute the sliced Brussels sprouts. Add coarsley ground pepper
  to taste and 2 tbs slivered almonds. When aromatic; reduce heat to warm;
  stir in up to 1/4 tsp lemon zest. Just before serving, add 1 or 2 tbs fresh
  lime juice. Ladle soup into wide bowls. Scatter relish on top. Serve hot.
  
  McNutritional information per serving: 138 Calories, 5.5 g protein, 12.9 g,
  carbohydrate, 7.9 g fat, 0 mg cholesterol, 96 mg sodium (49.2% cff)
  
  &gt;Edited by Pat Hanneman (Kitpath) 98Mar
  
  Recipe by: VEGETARIAN SOUPS FOR ALL SEASONS, by Nava Atlas
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest by KitPATh &lt;phannema@wizard.ucr.edu&gt; on Mar 17,
  1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
