<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Almond Biscotti with Variations</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Cookie</cat></categories>
      <yield>30</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sweet butter; melted</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Brandy</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Vanilla</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Almond extract</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Unsalted almonds; chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Baking powder</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  From: waring@infomail.com (Sam Waring) (COLLECTION)
  
  Date: 12 Apr 1994 15:17:00 -0400
  Preheat oven to 350~.  Mix sugar with butter, brandy, vanilla, almond
  extract, nuts and eggs.  Mix well.
  
  Stir in flour, baking powder and salt.  Form into a long loaf (or loaves),
  place on a cookie sheet and bake for 20-30 minutes or until firm and softly
  cakelike.  Remove from oven and let cool slightly.
  
  When cool enough to handle, slice into 1/2 inch diagonal slices and return
  to cookie sheet. Bake for 15-25 miutes, turning once, until both sides are
  brown-flecked and toasted.  Cool thoroughly and store in an airtight jar.
  Makes 2-3 dozen.
  
  Variation 1 (Mandlebrot): increase sugar to 1-1/4 cups.  Diced dried
  apricots may by added.
  
  Variation 2: for a clasic anise-flavored biscotto, substitute Pernod, Ouzo
  or Anisette for the brandy and omit the almond extract.  Several
  tablespoons of anise seeds may be added for additional oomph.
  
  Variation 3 (Hazelnut biscotti): use hazelnuts in place of almonds.  A
  hazelnut liqueur may be used instead of brandy.  Omit the almond extract.
  
  Variation 4 (Mediterranean biscotti): use rosewater instead of brandy.
  Substitute unsalted pistachio nuts for the almonds, and add 1/4 - 1/2 cup
  diced figs to the dough.
  
  Variation 5 (Ginger-flavored biscotti): to the basic dough, add 1 Tbsp
  powdered ginger, a generous dash of cloves and cinnamon, 1 or 2 Tbsp of
  candied ginger and 1/4 cup raisins, if desired.  Omit the almond extract.
  
  Variation 6 (Paximatha): this Greek rusk dates back to the 5th century,
  virtually unchanged.  Substiture 1/2 to 3/4 cup toasted sesame seeds for
  the almonds. Omit the almond extact and flavor the dough with 1 tsp
  cinnamon and
      1/2    tsp cloves.
  
  Variation 7 (Fekkas):  a Moroccon twice-baked cookie.  Substitute orange
  flower water for the brandy.
  
  Variation 8; Pine nuts may be used instead of almonds, though the richness
  may be less desirable than the crunch of the toasted almonds.  Candied
  fruits, too, may be added, 1/4 to 1/2 cup assorted fruits blended into the
  dough before baking.
  
  Variation 9 (Chocolate Dipped): melt 1/2 pound semi-sweet chocolate in the
  top of a double boiler over just simmering water.  If it "seizes" or
  "tightens", add 2 Tbsp of unsalted buter and it should smooth out again.
  Dip only one side of each cookie (the chocolate won't seal in the moisture
  that way).
  
  From: shelley.rodgers@f202.n161.z1.fidonet.org (Shelley Rodgers)
  
  REC.FOOD.RECIPES ARCHIVES
  
  /COOKIES
  
  From rec.food.cooking archives.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
