<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Almond Praline Cheesecake</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>8 -10</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Whole blanched almonds</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Vegetable oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Cold water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter; room temp.</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Cream cheese; room temp.</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sour cream</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Vanilla</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs; room temp. &amp; slightly beaten</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Since THE day for sweethearts is coming up I thought maybe I'd get us
  started on recipes for Valentine's Day....from "The Perfect
  Cheesecake"....serves 8-10.
  
  1. Place oven rack in center of oven; heat to 350°. Place almonds in single
  layer in ungreased shallow baking pan. Bake, shaking pan occasionally, til
  almonds are golden, about 6min. Remove almonds from pan; cool completely.
  
  2. Brush a baking sheet very lightly w/ oil; reserve.
  
  3. Combine 1-1/4C of sugar and the water in heavy non aluminum 1-1/2qt pan.
  Cook over medium heat til sugar is dissolved. Cover pan; simmer 3min.
  Uncover pan. Cook over medium heat, swirling syrup constantly, til it
  begins to smell fragrant and to color slightly.
  
  4. Add 1-1/4C of almonds to syrup and stir quickly w/ metal spoon. Continue
  cooking, stirring gently once or twice, only til mix is golden. Immediately
  pour onto reserved baking sheet; cool praline to room temp.
  
  5. Coat bottom and sides of 8x3" cheesecake (not springform) pan w/ butter.
  Refrigerate pan.
  
  6. Cut cream cheese into 1" cubes; place in large mixer bowl. Beat at
  medium speed, scraping down sides of bowl as needed, til smooth. Gradually
  beat in remaining 1/2C sugar, the sour cream and vanilla. Continue beating,
  scraping down sides of bowl as needed, til mix is smooth.
  
  7. Continue beating at medium speed while gradually adding eggs, about 1/4C
  at a time, to cheese mix, beating well and scraping down sides of bowl
  after each addition.
  
  8. Break cooled praline into small pieces. Grind in small batches in motar
  &amp; pestle or food processor til coarsely chopped; fold thoroughly into
  cheese mix.
  
  9. Pour batter into prepared pan; spread top smooth. Gently rotate pan
  several quarter turns to settle batter.
  
  10. Place pan in 13x9x2" baking dish or pan. Pour hot tap water into dish
  til it reaches a level halfway up outside of cheesecake pan. Bake in center
  of oven at 350° til center of cake is set and top is light brown, about
  1-1/2hours.
  
  11. Remove pan immediately from water; transfer to wire rack away from
  drafts. Let cool undisturbed til sides and bottom of pan are completely
  cooled to room temp.
  
  12. To unmold, carefully loosen sides of cheesecake w/ sharp thin knife.
  Center an inverted serving plate over cheesecake; invert and tap bottom of
  pan gently to release cake; remove pan.
  
  13. Refrigerate cake uncovered overnight or at least 8hrs. Cover cake
  loosely w/ plastic wrap; refrigerate til serving time.
  
  14. Chop remaining 1/2C almonds. Sprinkle almonds in border around top of
  cake. Serve cake cold.
  Posted to KitMailbox Digest  by "Dan/Trina D." &lt;itisme@swbell.net&gt; on Feb
  07, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
