<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Almond Macaroons</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Cookie</cat></categories>
      <yield>24</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Recipe almond paste (below)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Powdered sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour (up to)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Raw egg whites (see instruction 2)</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>ALMOND PASTE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Ground almonds (measure after grinding)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sifted powdered sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Raw egg whites (see note)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Almond extract</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  From: "Marian Russell" &lt;mrussell@sgit.iaea.or.at&gt;
  
  Date: 3 May 1995 07:34:25 -0600
  After 20 years of carrying around a recipe I cut out of a newspaper, I
  tried making almond paste and almond macaroons. The newspaper recipe was
  TOO SWEET and not specific enough about how to make the dough (the cookies
  were too thin and dry). This is the updated recipe and, if I do say so
  myself, it's quite good! The cookies are chewy and taste like the best
  almond macaroons I've ever eaten anywhere else.
  
  1. Soften almond paste with the back of a tablespoon and work in the dry
  ingredients.  Mix well.
  
  2. Begin adding egg whites, preparing them one at a time in case you don't
  need all of them.  Blend well after each addition.  Use only enough egg
  white to make a soft dough that will HOLD ITS SHAPE when dropped from a
  spoon.
  
  3. Drop 2 inches apart on a brown-paper-covered baking sheet.  Pat tops
  lightly with fingers dipped in cold water.
  
  4. Bake at 150 degrees C (300 degrees F) for 18 to 20 minutes, or until set
  and delicately browned.
  
  5. Remove from paper with a spatula onto wire racks to cool.
  
  Almond Paste:
  
  1. Combine the ground almonds with the sugar, then blend in the egg whites
  and almond extract.
  
  2. Mold into a ball and age for four days in a tightly covered container in
  the refrigerator. Note: If you have 1/2 cup of egg whites and you don't
  want to throw the extra 1/4 cup away, simply use the whole 1/2 cup for this
  recipe and add fewer egg whites for the almond macaroons.
  
  REC.FOOD.RECIPES ARCHIVES
  
  /COOKIES
  
  ALMOND PASTE TAKES 4 DAYS!!
  
  From rec.food.cooking archives.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
