<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Alo-Balo Polo (Steamed Rice with Sour Cherries and Chicke</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Middle east</cat>
        <cat>Iran</cat>
        <cat>Chicken</cat>
        <cat>Rice</cat>
        <cat>Time/life</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Cherries, sour; fresh, ripe,</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>;pitted (about 2 pounds)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>6</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Olive oil</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2 1/2</qty>
            <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
          <item>Chicken</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>medium</unit></amt>
          <item>Onion; peeled and cut into</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>;1/8 inch thick slices</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Rice, iranian; imported or</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>;other uncooked long, soaked</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>;and drained</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>8</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Butter; melted</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Saffron threads; pulverized</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>;with a mortar and pestle or</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>;the back of a spoon, and</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>;dissolved in 1 tablespoon</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>;warm water</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>SILVER XPRESS MAIL SYSTEM 5</title></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>    Combine the cherries and sugar in a 2 to 3 quart saucepan, and, stirring
  gently, bring to a boil over high heat.  Reduce the heat to low and simmer
  uncovered for 2 or 3 minutes, or until the cherries have softened somewhat
  and given off most of their liquid.  Remove from the heat.
    In a heavy 3 to 4 quart casserole, heat the olive oil over moderate heat
  until a light haze forms above it.  Pat the chicken completely dry with
  paper towels and sprinkle it inside and out with salt. Brown the chicken in
  the hot oil, turning it frequently with a large spoon or tongs and
  regulating the heat so that the bird colors quickly and deeply without
  burning.
    Place the chicken on a plate and add the onion slices to the oil
  remaining in the casserole.  Stirring frequently, cook for about 10
  minutes, or until the slices are richly browned.  Return the chicken and
  all of the juices which have accumulated on the plate to the casserole, add
  the « cup of water and bring to a boil over high heat. Reduce the heat to
  low, cover tightly and simmer for about 30 minutes, or until the chicken is
  tender.
    Transfer the chicken to a plate, set aside 2 tablespoons of the cooking
  liquid and discard the onion slices.  When the bird is cool enough to
  handle, cut it into 6 or 8 serving pieces.
    Meanwhile, bring 6 cups of water to a boil in a heavy 4 to 5 quart
  casserole with a tightly fitting lid.  Pour in the rice in a slow, thin
  stream so the water does not stop boiling.  Stir once or twice, boil
  briskly for 5 minutes, then drain the rice in a sieve.
    Pour the reserved chicken cooking liquid and 4 tablespoons of the melted
  butter into the casserole and stir them together.  Add half of the rice
  and, with a spatula or spoon, smooth it to the edges of the casserole. Cook
  uncovered over moderate heat for 5 minutes, then remove the casserole from
  the heat and add the chicken and half of the reserved cherries. Spread the
  remaining rice on top and pour in all the remaining cherries and their
  cooking liquid.  Cover tightly and cook over low heat for 15 to 20 minutes,
  or until the rice is tender.
    To serve, spoon about a cup of the rice into a small bowl, add the
  remaining 4 tablespoons of melted butter and the dissolved saffron and stir
  until the mixture is bright yellow.  Place a layer of rice on a heated
  platter.  Arrange the chicken on top of it, cover the chicken with the
  remaining rice and cherry mixture.  Sprinkle the saffron rice on top. With
  a metal spatula, lift the rice crust from the bottom of the casserole and
  arrange small pieces of it around the edge of the platter.
  
  92 of 116
  
  Source: Time Life Series: Middle Eastern Cooking  "circa  69"
  
  MMed by: earl.cravens@salata.com Beach, CA * 310-543-0439 28.8k (1:102/125)
  Ä Area: International Cooking
  ÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄ Msg#: 66 Date: 24 Mar 95
  23:22:00 From: EARL CRAVENS Read: Yes Replied: No
    To: ALL                                          Mark: Save Subj: T/L Mid
  East 093-116
  ÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄÄ
  ÄÄÄ
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/mmdjaxxx.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
