<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Aloha for Six Lime Custard with Mango Sauce</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Desserts</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Whipping cream</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Grated lime rind</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg yolks</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Granulated sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Mango</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Passion fruit liqueur or coconut liqueur</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Lime juice</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  This recipe should be made one day before serving for maximum flavour.
  
  In small saucepan, heat whipping cream and lime rind over medium-high heat
  just until bubbles form around edge of pan, about 4 minutes; let cool to
  room temperature. In large bowl, whisk egg yolks with sugar until sugar is
  dissolved, scraping down side of bowl. Pour cream mixture through strainer
  into egg mixture.
  
  In 13x9-inch baking dish, place 6 ramekins or 3/4-cup custard cups. Pour
  custard evenly into ramekins. Pour enough hot water into baking dish to
  come halfway up sides of ramekins. Cover tightly and bake in 350F=180C oven
  for 50 minutes or until knife inserted at edge comes out clean. Uncovered,
  let cool in water bath to room temperature. Remove ramekins from water and
  place on tray; cover and refrigerate for 1 day or until properly set and
  thoroughly chilled. [Custard can be refrigerated for up to 2 days.]
  
  About 1 hour before serving, remove custards from refrigerator; set aside.
  Peel and dice mango; place in bowl. Gently stir in passion fruit liqueur
  and lime juice; cover and set aside. To serve spoon gruit evenly over
  custards and serve immediately.
  
  Variation: If you wish to omit the liqueur in the sauce, substitute 2 tb
  lime juice and omit the 1 ts lime juice in recipe.
  
  Per serving: 460 calories, 5 g protein, 40 g fat, 19 g carbohydrate
  
  Dinner menu: Aloha For Six: Party Planner Info Aloha For Six: Golden Curry
  Macadamia Nuts Aloha For Six: Chicken Salad With Soft And Crispy Noodles
  Aloha For Six: Ginger-Glazed Pork Tenderloins Aloha For Six: Citrus Sweet
  Potatoes Aloha For Six: Stir-fried Broccoli And Sweet Onions Aloha For Six:
  Lime Custard With Mange Sauce; or Aloha For Six: Coconut Cookies
  
  Source: Canadian Living Magazine March 1996 by Karen Barnaby
  
  [-=PAM=-] PA_Meadows@msn.com
  
  Posted to MM-Recipes Digest V4 #175 by "KAR" &lt;bluekat@gate.net&gt; on Jul 7,
  1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
