<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Aloha for Six Chicken Salad with Soft and Crispy Noodles</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Salads</cat>
        <cat>Poultry</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Chicken breasts [3/4lb] skinless, boneless</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
          <item>Linguine noodles</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Snow peas, thin diag slice</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sweet red pepper, thin slice</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Red onion, thinly sliced</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>12</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Leaf lettuce leaves</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Chow mein noodles</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Roasted peanuts, chopped</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>MARINADE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Lime juice</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>pinch</unit></amt>
          <item>Pepper</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>small</unit></amt>
          <item>Garlic cloves, minced</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>DRESSING</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Vegetable oil</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Lime juice</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Soy sauce</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Granulated sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Marinade: In bowl, combine lime juice, salt, pepper and garlic; add chicken
  turning to coat. Place on lightly greased baking sheet; bake in 350F=180C
  oven for 15-20 minutes or until no longer pink inside. Cover and
  refrigerate for at least 1 hour or up to 8 hours.
  
  Dressing: In small bowl, whisk together oil, lime juice, soy sauce, sugar
  and salt; cover and refrigerate for up to 8 hours.
  
  In a large pot of boiling salted water, cook linquine for 8-10 minutes or
  until tender but firm; drain and refresh under cold water. Drain well and
  place in large bowl.
  
  Slice chicken diagonally into thin strips; add to cooled linguine along
  with snow peas, red pepper and onion. Pour dressing over top, toss to coat
  well. Place 2 lettuce leaves on each plate; divide salad evenly among
  plates. Surround each salad with chow mein noodles. Sprinkle with peanuts.
  
  Per serving: 335 calories, 19 g protein, 16 g fat, 28 g carbohydrate Good
  source iron
  
  Variation: substitute 3/4 lb cooked baby shrimp for the chicken; just toss
  with the marinade before adding to linguine and vegetables.
  
  Dinner menu: Aloha For Six: Party Planner Info Aloha For Six: Golden Curry
  Macadamia Nuts Aloha For Six: Chicken Salad With Soft And Crispy Noodles
  Aloha For Six: Ginger-Glazed Pork Tenderloins Aloha For Six: Citrus Sweet
  Potatoes Aloha For Six: Stir-fried Broccoli And Sweet Onions Aloha For Six:
  Lime Custard With Mange Sauce; or Aloha For Six: Coconut Cookies
  
  Source: Canadian Living Magazine March 1996 by Karen Barnaby
  
  [-=PAM=-] PA_Meadows@msn.com
  
  Posted to MM-Recipes Digest V4 #175 by "KAR" &lt;bluekat@gate.net&gt; on Jul 7,
  1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
