<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Amazing Orange-Vanilla Cake Roll</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Try it</cat>
        <cat>Cakes</cat></categories>
      <yield>10</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>WOMAN'S DAY; 3/12/1996</title></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>VANILLA FILLING</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>16</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Cream cheese, light; room</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Temp</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Eggs; room temp</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Milk</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Vanilla extract</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>ORANGE CAKE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>5</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Eggs; room temp</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Orange peel, grated; fresh</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Vanilla extract</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Butter; melted</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar, powdered</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>CANDIED CITRUS SLICES; GARNI</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Oranges</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Clementines</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Kumquats</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>Prep:</qty>
            <unit>30</unit></amt>
          <item>minutes.  Bake: 20 minutes.  Total cost: $3.95. The cake bakes</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>right</qty>
            <unit>on</unit></amt>
          <item>top of the filling, which is then rolled up inside. The cake can</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  be baked up to 1 week ahead.
  
  Preheat oven to 375 F.  Lightly grease 15-1/2"x10-1/2" jelly roll pan. Line
  bottom and sides with waxed paper; grease paper.
  
  Filling: Beat cream cheese and sugar with electric mixer until smooth. Beat
  in eggs, milk, and vanilla JUST until blended. Spread evenly in lined pan.
  
  Cake: Beat eggs, sugar, orange peel, and vanilla in large bowl with
  electric mixer on high speed 8-12 minutes, until very thick, pale, and at
  least tripled in volume. (Eggs are the only leavening in this cake, so it
  is very important to beat them to maximum volume. Use a large, deep, narrow
  bowl rather than a wide one. An 8-cup glass measure is perfect.) Sprinkle
  with flour. Fold until just blended. Add butter and fold until just
  blended. Spread evenly over filling in pan. Bake 19-21 minutes, until cake
  springs back when touched in center.
  
  While cake bakes, spread clean kitchen towel (not paper or terry cloth) on
  countertop.  Sift powdered sugar through small strainer over towel,
  covering an area the size of the cake.
  
  Invert hot cake onto towel.  Remove pan and carefully peel off paper.
  Starting at one narrow end, neatly roll up cake, using towel as an aid.
  Cool completely on wire rack. Wrap and refrigerate up to 1 week. When ready
  to serve, garnish with candied citrus slices.
  
  Candied citrus slices: choose fruit with thin skin for best results. We
  used three varieties to vary size of slices. Use leftovers to garnish other
  desserts or as an accompaniment to ham or poultry.
  
  Scrub skins.  Slice in 18"-thick rounds.  Bring water and sugar to boil in
  wide skillet.  Add one citrus type at a time in a single layer. Reduce heat
  and simmer uncovered 20-40 minutes, until translucent. Remove to bowl with
  slotted spoon; repeat with remaining fruit. Pour syrup over slices; add a
  little water if syrup is too thick. Refrigerate up to 3 months.
  
  Per serving: 329 cal, 10 g pro, 41 g car, 13 g fat, 176 mg chol, 258 mg
  sodium.Exchanges: 2 starch, 2/3 other car, 1/2 medium-fat meat, 2 fat.
  
  Tyops courtesy of Sylvia Steiger.
  
  Nutritional information per serving:  xx calories, xx gm protein, xx mg
  cholesterol,  xx gm carbohydrate, xx mg sodium, x.x gm fiber, xx gm fat ( x
  gm sat,  x gm mono,  x gm poly), x.x mg iron,  xx mg calcium, x% of
  calories from fat.
  
  Brought to you by MMCONV and Sylvia Steiger, CI$ 71511,2253, Internet
  sylvia.steiger@lunatic.com or du_steiger@venus.twu.edu, homepage:
  http://ourworld.compuserve.com/homepages/SylviaRN, moderator of GT Cookbook
  and FringeNet Lowfat &amp; Luscious echoes
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
