<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Ambrosia Sorbet</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Dessert</cat>
        <cat>Chilled or</cat></categories>
      <yield>8</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Pineapple puree; from half a fresh pineapple</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh orange juice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Coconut extract</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Part-skim ricotta cheese</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flaked coconut; unsweetened</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Makes 1 quart, serving 8, at 65 cals. Time varies from 1 to 5 hours,
  depending upon freezing method.
  
  If using fresh pineapple: cut the rind, eyes, and core from the pineapple.
  Cut the flesh into chunks and puree them in a food processor fitted with
  the steel blade. You should have about 2 cups of puree. (Unsweetened
  pineapple chunks, pureed.)
  
  Add the orange juice, coconut extract, and ricotta and process briefly.
  
  Chill the mixture and freeze in an electric or hand-cranked ice-cream
  machine, following the manufacturer's instructions.
  
  To make the sorbet in your freezer, transfer the mixture to a bowl and
  place in the freezer. When the liquid has frozen solid, about 2 to 3 hours,
  remove it from the freezer and, with a fork, break it into large chunks.
  Place the chunks in a food processor and process with the metal blade until
  smooth and creamy. Return to the bowl and freeze for at least 30 minutes
  more.
  
  Toast the coconut: Set oven at 350F. Spread coconut on a baking sheet and
  toast in the oven for about 10 minutes, or until lightly colored, stirring
  or shaking 2 or 3 times.
  
  To serve, place scoops of sorbet in dessert dishes and sprinkle with the
  toasted coconut. PER SERVING: 46.0 cals, 1.5 g fat (28.3% cff)
  
  &gt;From (1990) Edward J. Safdie, New Spa Food: Hearty, healthy Recipes, from
  the Norwich Inn and Spa. NY: Clarkson Potter. Pat H. McRecipe 28 Oc 96.
  
  Recipe by: New Spa Food (1990)
  
  Posted to Digest eat-lf.v097.n302 by KitPATh &lt;phannema@wizard.ucr.edu&gt; on
  Nov 28, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
