<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Amy Scherber's Baguette</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Breads</cat></categories>
      <yield>3 14</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Active dry yeast</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>(2 ounces) very warm water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>105 to 115 degrees F</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>(13 1/2 ounces)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Unbleached all purpose flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>(4 1/2 ounces) cake flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>(see note)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2 1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Kosher salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Plus 1 tablespoon, (10</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>1/2ounces) cool water - 75</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Degrees F</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Combine the yeast and the warm water in a small bowl and stir with a fork
  to dissolve the yeast. Let stand for 3 minutes. Combine the flours and salt
  in a large bowl. Pour the cool water and the yeast mixture over the flour,
  and mix with your fingers to form a shaggy mass. Move the dough to a
  lightly floured work surface and and resilient, but not too smooth at this
  point. Let the dough rest on the work surface for 20 minutes, covered with
  plastic wrap or a light towel. (This rest period is the autolyse.)
  
  Knead the dough for 6 to 8 minutes. Don't overknead it: The dough should be
  smooth, stretchy, and resilient. Place the dough in a lightly oiled bowl,
  turn it in the bowl to coat with oil, and cover it with plastic wrap. Let
  rise at room temperature ( 75 to 77 degrees F) for 1 1/2 to 2 hours, or
  until nearly doubled in volume.
  
  Gently deflate the dough and fold it over itself in the bowl. Reshape it
  into a ball and cover with plastic wrap. Let it rise for 1 1/4 hours or
  until it has nearly doubled again. Gently deflate the dough again, reshape
  into a round, cover, and let rise for about 1 hour. Place the dough on a
  very lightly floured surface and divide it into 3 equal pieces (about 10
  ounces each). Gently stretch one piece into a rectangle, leaving some large
  bubbles in the dough. Fold the top third down and the bottom third up as if
  you were folding a business letter. Now form the loaf into a log by rolling
  the dough over from left to right and sealing the seam with the heel of
  your palm. Fold the dough over about 1/ 3 of the way each time, seal the
  length of the loaf, then repeat. You want to gently draw the skin tight
  over the surface of the baguette while leaving some air bubbles in the
  dough. Seal the seam, being careful not to tear the skin of the dough or
  deflate its airy structure. Set aside on the work surface to relax before
  elongating it, and repeat the shaping process with remaining pieces of
  dough.
  
  Now elongate each baguette, starting with the first one you shaped, by
  rolling it back and forth on the work surface. Begin with both hands over
  the center of the loaf and work them out to the ends until the loaf reaches
  the desired length. (Don't get carried away, or the baguettes won't fit in
  your oven!) Place the finished loaves on a peel or upside down baking sheet
  lined with parchment paper spring, resulting in loaves with a light, airy
  crumb and more flared cuts.
  
  Thirty minutes before baking, preheat the oven to 500 degrees F. Place a
  baking stone in the oven to preheat, and place an empty water pan directly
  under the stone. Use a very sharp razor blade or lame to make 3 to 5
  slashes, depending on the length of your loaves, on the top of each
  baguette. The cuts should run from one end of the loaf to the other, rather
  than across it, and the blade should be held at a 30 degree angle to the
  loaf so that the cuts pop open in the oven. Be careful not to press down
  too hard, or you may deflate the loaves. Using a plant sprayer, mist the
  loaves.
  
  Gently slide the loaves onto the preheated stone, or place the baguette
  mold in the oven. Pour 1 cup of very hot water into the water pan and
  quickly close the oven door. After 1 minute, mist the loaves and oven walls
  6 to 8 times and close the door. After 2 more minutes, spray the loaves and
  the oven walls again.
  
  Bake for 12 minutes, then lower the oven temperature to 400 degrees F and
  bake for 25 to 30 minutes longer until the loaves are golden brown and
  crisp. Move them to a rack to cool.
  
  Enjoy your baguettes still slightly warm with some soft, ripe French cheese
  and a glass of wine.
  
  Yield: 3 - 14 inch loaves.
  
  Note: If cake flour is not available, you can use the same amount of
  unbleached all-purpose flour, but cake flour will give the baguette a
  lighter texture. BAKERS' DOZEN AMY SCHERBER SHOW #BD1A55 Copyright, 1996,
  TV FOOD NETWORK, G.P., All Rights Reserved
  Posted to Bakery-Shoppe Digest V1 #230 by Bill &lt;thelma@pipeline.com&gt; on Sep
  11, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
