<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>An Unknown Grandma's "Chicken 'n Dumplin's (</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>American cl</cat>
        <cat>Casseroles</cat>
        <cat>Chicken</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>3-lb chicken; (or favorite pieces)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>pint</unit></amt>
          <item>Cream or milk</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Salt and pepper; to taste</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Celery with leaves</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>small</unit></amt>
          <item>Onion; quartered</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>medium</unit></amt>
          <item>Carrot; peeled and quartered</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>FOR THE DUMPLING DOUGH</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Shortening; that's crisco</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Egg</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>5</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Water</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Recipe by: Posted to RFC Preparation Time: 0:30 First, cut the chicken in
  half. Right down the middle. Makes it easier to cook. In fact, I cut the
  halves in half. If you want you can just get a couple packages of your
  favorite chicken parts (more expensive than a whole chicken, however). Wash
  chicken good under running water. Put chicken into a stewing pot with
  enough water to cover the chicken about two inches. Bring it to a boil,
  reduce the heat, and let it simmer until done, about 30 minutes. While it's
  cooking, every once in a while skim the foam off the top of the water with
  a spoon and sling it into the sink, then turn the chicken in the pot once
  in a while. While it's cooking, make the dumplings. Mix flour, salt,
  shortening. Crumble it in your hands until it looks like flour "bee-bees".
  Add egg and water and mix it well. Pat it into a big circle, dust it with
  flour, and roll it out to about 1/8-inch thickness Let it rest 15 minutes.
  By now the chicken should be done. Remove the onion, celery stalk and
  carrot pieces &amp; discard. Take it out of the pot and let it cool until you
  can handle it. Remove the meat from the chicken and discard all the skin,
  bones and some unknown stuff. Chop the meat into bite-sized pieces. Bring
  the broth back to a boil. Cut the dumplings into strips about 1-inch wide
  (I use a pizza cutter to do this). Pick up the strips one at a time and
  pinch off pieces and drop them into the boiling broth. Every so often, stop
  and stir to make sure they're not sticking together (I use a wooden spoon
  to do this). When all the dumplings are in the broth, let the whole thing
  cook about five more minutes, then test a dumpling to see if it has the
  texture you want. It should be done by now, but if the dumpling is still
  raw in the middle, let it all cook a little longer. Finally, add about
  half-teaspoon of salt and taste to see if it needs more. Now add the cream
  or milk and dump the chicken back into the bowl and dust it with black
  pepper.
  
  "Okay, Edward, pay attention. You're going to get some posts for dumpling
  recipes that have BAKING POWDER in them. You're going to IGNORE those,
  right? You're from Auburn, right? Auburn is the 51st state, right? Auburn
  was one of the states that seceded from the Union, right? And what's the
  definition of the Union? "A bunch of states where people put baking powder
  in flour and call it dumplings." That's the definition of the Union. Well,
  if it has baking powder in it, it ain't dumplings, it's biscuits, and the
  dish ain't "chicken 'n dumplin's", it's "Chicken Flavored Number of notes
  exported: 6
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest V1 #1056 by "M. Hicks" &lt;nitro_ii@email.msn.com&gt;
  on Jan 29, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
