<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Anchor Bar Hot Wings</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Appetizers</cat>
        <cat>Poultry</cat></categories>
      <yield>12</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Chicken wings</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Read below</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  The key to good Buffalo Wings is how you prepare them as well as the
  ingredients and the handling of the wings. The most successful wings served
  up here in Buffalo are what they call "Grade A Grinders." Fresh wings that
  are very large and meaty.  Usually, you cannot get them in a frozen
  package, but can get them from a poultry dealer. Once you find them make
  sure they are absolutely fresh. Wash them in cold water, split them at the
  joint and remove the tips. Place them on a rack on a pan and refrigerate
  overnight to let the blood and water drain out of the wings. THIS IS A REAL
  KEY.  Drying the wings under refrigeration will help to make them a much
  crispier product, once deep fried. Next, use a deep fryer or a very heavy
  deep pot with a thermometer and add the oil. Peanut oil is very good, or a
  commercial product such as can be found at a restaurant cash and carry
  called Mel Fry. Heat the oil up SLOWLY, to 365F, and depending on the size
  of the fryer, deep fry the dry wings 6-8 minutes in small batches, until
  thoroughly done and golden brown. Hold the cooked wings in a warm oven if
  necessary. A combination of melted margarine and hot sauce in the ratio of
  1 part margarine to 3 parts hot sauce will add the right zing. The key here
  is to add just enough sauce to coat the wings - the more sauce you add, the
  hotter they will be.  For the very brave, 1 part margarine to 3 parts hot
  sauce and 1 part Tabasco is referred to as "Suicidal Wings" by the late and
  dear Don Bellissimo, who owned the Anchor Bar. Working quickly, place the
  deep fried wings in a large bowl and add the sauce mixture, shaking to coat
  them. There are many good hot sauces to use; the one they use is either
  Durkee Franks Red Hot Sauce or Wingers Original, again found in a
  restaurant cash and carry. Celery sticks and chunky blue cheese dressing
  (Ken's Buffalo Style Blue Cheese is a popular one) and plenty of napkins.
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
