<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>And More Homemade Tamales</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Mexican</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>10</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Meat-venison roast/pork</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Roast mix -- any roasts</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>10</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Massa 3/4 can</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Jar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Reg  jar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Jar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Lard -- (the big can)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Chili powder</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Garlic powder</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Cumin</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Boil the meat with garlic powder until mushy.  Drain broth and flake mushy
  meat. Season  with all the cumin and salt.  Add 1/2 cup of the broth back
  to make the consistancy more mushy. (you can do this step the day before)
  Mix the lard, salt and chili powder to the Massa. Add in enough of the
  broth to make the Massa spreadable. Take one package of corn husks which
  have been soaked for 30 minutes in water and separate. To make the tamales,
  spread some Massa mixture (about 1 or 2 tablespoons) over the corn husk,
  about 1/4 inch thick, starting about 2 inches from the bottom of the husk.
  This part will have no Massa and will be folded over the tamale to seal it.
  Put about 1 tablespoon of filling into the tamale, roll, fold over the
  empty corn husk to seal. When you have made about 2 to 3 dozen, stand
  upright in a pan with either a steamer or wadded aluminum foil to keep the
  tamales straight, open end up. Put about 2 inches of water in the pan and
  pour more broth INTO the open ends of the tamales to soak. Cover and steam
  for 45 minutes to an hour. (Increase or decrease steam time depending on
  how many tamales are in the pan) The great part of this recipe is tasting
  the batch you just made to see if it is tasty. Increase the heat by adding
  a diced jalapeno or serano pepper. The chili powder adds enough heat to
  spice them, but children can still eat them. The peppers are for the
  die-hard dragons in the group. Also, if you don't get the Massa salty
  enough you should adjust that.  Vary each batch, label, wrap 6 to a package
  with freezer paper and enjoy!
  
  Recipe By     :
  
  From: Ladies Home Journal- August 1991
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/mmdja006.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
