<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Andouille Sausage Making</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Sausages</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Yd large sausage casing</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Approx (2-3 in wide)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Lean fresh pork</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Pork fat</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3 1/3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Finely minced garlic</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh grnd black pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/8</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Cayenne</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/8</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Chili powder</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/8</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Mace</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/8</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Allspice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Dried thyme</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Paprika</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground bay leaf</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sage</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>5</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Liquid hickory smoke</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Andouille was a great favorite in nineteenth-century New Orleans. This
  thick Cajun sausage is made with lean pork and pork fat and lots of garlic.
  Sliced about 1/2 inch thick and greilled, it makes a delightful appetizer.
  It is also used in a superb oyster and andouille gumbo poplular in Laplace,
  a Cajun town about 30 miles from New Orleans that calls itself the
  Andouille Capital of the World.
  
  Soak the casing about an hour in cold water to soften it and to loosen the
  salt in which it is packed.  Cut into 3 yard lengths, then place the narrow
  end of the sausage stuffer in one end of the casing. Place the wide end of
  the stuffer up against the sink faucet and run cold water through the
  inside of the casing to remove any salt. (Roll up the casing you do not
  intend to use; put about 2 inches of coarse salt in a large jar, place the
  rolled up casing on it, then fill the rest of the jar with salt. Close
  tightly and refrigerate for later use.)
  
  Cut the meat and fat into chunks about 1/2 inch across and pass once
  through the coarse blade of the meat grinder. Combine the pork with the
  remaining ingredients in a large bowl and mix well with a wooden spoon. Cut
  the casings into 26 inch lengths and stuff as follows: Tie a knot in each
  piece of casing about 2 inches from one end. Fit the open end over the tip
  of the sausage stuffer and slide it to about 1 inch from the wide end. Push
  the rest of the casing onto the stuffer until the top touches the knot.
  (The casing will look like accordian folds on the stuffer.) Fit the stuffer
  onto the meat grinder as directed on the instructions that come with the
  machine, or hold the wide end of the stuffer against or over the opeoning
  by  hand. Fill the hopper with stuffing. Turn the machine on if it is
  electric  and feed the stuffing gradually into the hopper; for a manual
  machine, push the stuffing through with a wooden pestle. The sausage casing
  will fill and inflate gradually.  Stop filling about 1 1/4 inches from the
  funnel end and slip the casing off the funnel, smoothing out any bumps
  carefully with your fingers and being careful not to push the stuffing out
  of the casing.  Tie off the open end of the sausage tightly with a piece of
  string or make a knot in the casing itself. Repeat until all the stuffing
  is used up.
  
  To cook, slice the andouille 1/2 inch thick and grill in a hot skillet with
  no water for about 12 minutes on each side, until brown and crisp at the
  edges.
  
  (about 6 pounds of 20 inch sausage, 3 to 3 1/2 inches thick)
  
  Paul A. Meadows - Concepts In Drug Education Ottawa, Ont K1S 5J6 FAX
  613-565-3759
  
  ~~~ Rec.food.recipes is moderated; only recipes and recipe requests are
  accepted for posting. Please read the "Posting Guidelines" article first.
  Submissions go to recipes@rt66.com; questions/comments go to
  tfdpress@acpub.duke.edu. Please allow several days for your submission to
  appear. Xref: news.demon.co.uk rec.food.recipes:7473 Path:
  news.demon.co.uk!peernews.demon.co.uk!news.sprintlink.n t!news.clark.n t!ra
  hul.net!a2i!mack.rt66.com!mack.rt66.com!not-for-mail From:
  af656@freenet.carleton.ca (Paul A. Meadows) Newsgroups: rec.food.recipes
  Subject: Andouille Sausage Followup-To: rec.food.cooking Date: 16 Apr 1995
  21:34:04 -0600 Organization: Engineering International Inc., Public
  Internet Access Lines: 47 Sender: phill@mack.rt66.com Approved:
  phill@rt66.com Message-ID: &lt;199504100404.AAA27777@freenet2.carleton.ca&gt;
  Reply-To: af656@freenet.carleton.ca (Paul A. Meadows) NNTP-Posting-Host:
  mack.rt66.com
  
  MM: Andouille(2) Sausage Making
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
