<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Anise-Almond Biscotti</title>
      <categories>
        <cat/></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Whole almonds</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2 1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Baking powder</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter; softened</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs; lightly beaten</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Vanilla extract</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Anise seeds</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  To toast almonds, preheat oven to 350øF. Spread almonds in a single layer
  on a baking sheet and toast, turning occasionally, for 10 minutes. Set
  aside to cool, then roughly chop. Sift together flour, baking powder and
  salt in a small mixing bowl. Set aside. Cream butter and sugar with an
  electric mixer in a large mixing bowl until fluffy; then beat in eggs and
  vanilla. Gradually add flour mixture, mix until combined, then stir in
  chopped almonds and anise seeds. Dough will be stiff. Transfer dough to a
  lightly floured work surface, then, using your hands or a rolling pin,
  shape into one long roll, about 3 inches by 13 inches. Line baking sheet
  with parchment paper or aluminum foil (shiny side up). Transfer dough roll
  to baking sheet, flatten slightly, then bake until golden brown, about 35
  minutes. Remove from oven--do not turn oven off--and set aside until cool
  enough to handle, about 15 minutes. Using a serrated knife, cut roll, on
  the diagonal, into 1/2 inch thick slices. Place slices flat on baking sheet
  and bake, turning once, until golden brown, about 5 minutes per side. Do
  not over bake: Biscotti will feel soft in the middle but will become crisp
  and hard as they cool. Allow to cool completely on pan. Biscotti will keep
  in a sealed container for up to 4 weeks.  Makes about 2 dozen
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest V1 #180
  
  Date: Sat, 3 Aug 1996 09:22:20 +1000
  
  From: sherae@zeta.org.au (Sheri McRae)
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
