<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Ann Kathleen Mckay's Strawberry Cake a la Dacquoise</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Cakes</cat>
        <cat>Desserts</cat>
        <cat>Masterchefs</cat>
        <cat>Frisco</cat>
        <cat>Relf</cat></categories>
      <yield>16</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Genoise, 9-inch **</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Buttercream **</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Eau de Vie Framboise (raspberry brandy)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Creme fraiche</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Cream, heavy</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pint</unit></amt>
        <item>Strawberries</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Strawberry leaves, and flowers</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>12</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Fraise des bois with stems (wild strawberries) (optional)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>       ** Recipes for this ingredient are elsewhere in this database.
  
       Cut one of the two 9-inch genoise in two.  These "half-layers" will be
  the top two layers of the cake.  The whole genoise will be the bottom.
  Sprinkle each of the three genoise layers lightly with 2 tablespoons of
  Framboise.
  
       Flavor 2 cups of buttercream with 1 tablespoon of Framboise.
  
       Whip the creme fraiche and heavy cream together to form stiff peaks.
  Add 1/4 cup of creme anglaise and 1 tablespoon Framboise and continue
  whipping until stiff peaks form again.
  
       If the strawberries are small, slice them in half lengthwise.  If they
  are larger, slice them crosswise into 1/2-inch slices.
  
       Spread the full thick layer of genoise (which will be the bottom of
  the cake) with one-third of the buttercream.  Arrange sliced berries around
  the perimeter of the cake, with the cut side out. Continue to cover the
  bottom of the cake with half of the berries and spread with half of the
  whipped cream-creme anglaise mixture.
  
       Repeat the same process for the second layer of genoise then place the
  final layer on top and spread with a thin layer of buttercream. Smooth
  nicely.
  
       With a small star tip on a pastry pipe, make an attractive border
  around the top of the cake with the remaining buttercream.  (You can add
  food coloring to the buttercream at this point if desired.)
  
       Arrange the fraise des bois (wild strawberries with their stems) along
  the perimeter of the cake then garnish with strawberry leaves and flowers.
  
       Refrigerate for 2 - 4 hours before serving.
  
       Preparation time:  1 1/2 hours
  
       Source: Great Chefs of San Francisco, Avon Books, 1984
  
       Chef:  Bruce LeFavour, Rose et Le Favour, St. Helena,
       :      Napa Valley, California
  
       Pastry Chef:  Ann McKay
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/mm-gc-sf.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
