<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Anne's Cappuccino Squares</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Candies</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>FIRST LAYER</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour; all purpose</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Confectioner's sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Butter; softened</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Instant coffee crystals dissolved one by one in Hot water Butter for greasing pan</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>SECOND LAYER</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Confectioner's sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Instant coffee crystals dissolved in</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Hot water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Egg; lightly beaten, at room temperature</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Butter; softened</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Milk</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>TOP LAYER</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>White chocolate; 4 squares</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Butter</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Semisweet chocolate;2 sq-opt</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Preheat oven to 350F. FIRST LAYER: Grease 8 inch square cake pan with
  butter. Mix together thoroughly flour, confectioner's sugar (icing sugar),
  softened butter and coffee dissolved in hot water. (You can use food
  processor or electric mixer). Press mixture evenly into pan bottom. Bake 10
  minutes in preheated 350F oven. Cool on wire rack. SECOND LAYER: Meanwhile
  in large bowl, combine confectioner's sugar (icing sugar), 1 Tbsp coffee
  crystals dissolved in 2 Tbsp hot water, softened butter and 1 egg (lightly
  beaten with a fork at room temperature.) Mix until thoroughly combined.
  (can use food processor or electric mixer). Put milk in pot over medium
  heat and scald (heat until bubbles appear around sides but milk is not a
  rolling boil). Add mixture from bowl and heat 7 minutes over medium heat ,
  stirring frequently at first, constantly after the mixture bubbles. (If
  mixture starts to stick on bottom, lower heat slightly). Let cool slightly,
  then pour over first layer. Tilt pan to cover base layer evenly. Chill in
  refrigerator half an hour or more till set. THIRD LAYER: Combine 4 oz white
  chocolate with 1 Tbsp butter in double boiler and melt (or melt 1 -1 1/2
  minutes in microwave on High and stir ). Spread over chilled second layer
  with spatula or blunt knife (layer will be quite thin). OPTIONAL MARBLED
  EFFECT: Melt 2 oz semisweet chocolate in double boiler (or in microwave 1 -
  1 1/2 minutes on High and stir). Pour melted semisweet chocolate into small
  ziploc bag and seal. Snip corner of bag with scissors. Squeeze out
  horizontal lines of semisweet chocolate onto white chocolate layer. With a
  blunt knife, swirl the two chocolates together to create a marbled effect.
  Chill. Before the third layer is completely set, score into bars.
  VARIATION: Mocha Squares: substitute semisweet chocolate for white
  chocolate (this variation is easier as the middle layer and semisweet
  chocolate are similar in colour.) MAKES: approx 32 bars (they are very
  sweet, therefore the bars should be small)
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
