<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Annie Mae Jones' Yeast Rolls</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Breads</cat>
        <cat>Rolls</cat></categories>
      <yield>24</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>5 1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>packages</unit></amt>
          <item>Yeast,dry</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Milk</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Butter,at room temperature</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Eggs</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>CONFECTIONERS' SUGAR GLAZE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Confectioners' sugar,sifted</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Orange juice</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  1. In a large bowl thoroughly mix 2 cups of the flour, the sugar, yeast and
  salt.
  
  2. Combine milk, water, and butter in a saucepan. Place over low heat and
  stir until butter is melted. Mixture should be just warm, about 115-120'F.
  on thermometer.
  
  3. Gradually add milk mixture to dry ingredients and eat for 2 minutes at
  medium speed of electric mixer, scraping bowl often. Add eggs and beat
  well.
  
  4. With a wooden spoon stir in sufficient additional flour (3 to 3-1/2
  cups) to make a soft dough. turn out on a lightly floured board and knead
  about 10 minutes, or unil satiny and smooth. Form into a ball and place in
  a warm bowl that has been generously greased with soft butter at room
  temperature. Turn to coat all sides with butter. Cover and let rise in a
  warm place until double in bulk, about 1 hour.
  
  5. Punch down and shape into small balls. Place about 1/2" apart on greased
  baking sheets and again let stand free from drafts in a warm place until
  double in bulk.
  
  6. Bake in preheated 350'F. oven for 25-30 minutes, or until lightly
  browned.
  
  7. Serve warm.
  
  8. If necessary, undercook rolls just slightly; then reheat just before
  serving.
  
  9. If desired, you may fold in about 1 cup lightly floured raisins to dough
  during final kneading. Then frost rolls while warm with Confectioners'
  Sugar Glaze.
  
  *** CONFECTIONERS' SUGAR GLAZE ***
  
  Combine sugar with 1 tablespoon orange juice. Add sufficient additioal
  orange juice to make a medium-thin glaze. From: Earl Shelsby Date: Sun,
  09-2
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
