<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Aphrodisiac Omelet</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Good</cat>
        <cat>Morning</cat>
        <cat>America</cat></categories>
      <yield>2</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>5</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs; fresh from the nest of a virgin hen</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Beluga caviar; if possible from the baltic sea</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>slices</unit></amt>
        <item>Norwegian smoked salmon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Fresh country butter</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Chopped chives</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Toast</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Ever so delicately, you break the eggs into a fine porcelain bowl—porcelain
  for reasons of elegance, nothing more—and beat lightly, adding salt and
  pepper. You warm the butter in the omelet pan sacred to every good cook,
  and as soon as the butter begins to turn the tint of warm Caribbean skin,
  you pour in the eggs. When the omelet is half cooked on the bottom, loosen
  it with infinite gentleness, whispering encouragingly, because if you are
  rough, it will lose its enchanting disposition; add the chives and salmon
  and fold it over, exactly as you would close a book. To free it entirely,
  experts move the skillet back and forth with the pulsing syncopation of a
  good dancer, and then, with a sudden flip of the wrist, toss it up in the
  air and catch it, now reversed, so it will cook to a golden brown on both
  sides—although I admit that every time I've tried that move, the omelet has
  landed on my head. These gyrations are pure exhibitionism, because when you
  make an omelet, as when y! ! ou make love, affection counts or more than
  technique.
  
  Serve your omelet on your most beautiful plates, already warmed in the
  oven. Spoon on the caviar, and beside this triumph place the warm toast and
  sour cream. After a night of passion, this is the breakfast indicated for
  making love, no holds barred, the rest of the day.
  
  Notes: An Omelet For Two
  
  "Appetite and sex are the great motivators of history,” writes
  internationally acclaimed author Isabel Allende. “All of creation is one
  long uninterrupted cycle of digestion and fertility.” Check out Allende's
  recipe of love: the Aphrodisiac Omelet .
  
  Air date April 22, 1998
  
  To order GMA recipes or to subscribe yearly please call: 1-800-543-4GMA
  Single recipes $3 / Yearly $14.95
  
  MC formatted using MC Buster 2.0d &amp; SNT on 4/26/98
  
  Recipe by: Adapted from Isabel Allende's Aphrodite (HarperFlamingo, Ma
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest by Barb at PK  &lt;abprice@wf.net&gt; on Apr 26, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
