<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Apple Puff Pastry Tartlets</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Unbleached all-purpose flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>10</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Cold butter -unsalted; cut into 1/2 inch dice, 2 tablespoons of 10 kept separate</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Cold tap water; plus 1 tbl more (per 3 tbl) if necessary</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Apples; sliced paper thin</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Cinnamon sugar</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  1. For the dough, place flour in work bowl of food processor fitted with
  
  steel blade-, add the 2 tablespoons butter, pulse until butter is absorbed,
  about 10 to 12 pulses of 1 second each.
  
  2. Add remaining butter pulse once or twice to distribute. Dissolve salt in
  water and add to flour mixture-, pulse 3 or 4 times,until dough just starts
  to form a rough ball-do not overprocess. If mixture remains very dry, add a
  teaspoon of water at a time and pulse again.
  
  3. Turn dough onto floured work surface and shape into rough rectangle,
  then place on top of sheet of well-floured plastic wrap measuring at least
  6-by-9 inches. Lightly flour top of dough and cover with another sheet of
  wrap. Press dough with rolling pin to flatten, then roll back and forth
  several times with rolling pin to make 6-by-9-inch rectangle of dough.
  
  4. Peel away plastic wrap and invert dough onto floured work surface, long
  side facing you. Peel away second piece of wrap.Fold top third of dough
  down and bottom third up, to make2-by-9-inch rectangle, then roll up dough
  from one end like a jellyroll. Press dough into square, wrap in plastic,
  
  and refrigerate 1hour, or until firm.
  
  5. On a floured surface, roll dough into a 1 5-by-1 0-inch rectangle.Cut
  
  into 3- to 3 1/2-inch disks, squares, or diamonds. Arrange on a
  parchment-lined cookie sheet, about 2 inches apart on all sides,and prick
  with a fork.
  
  6. Top each dough shape with apple and a sprinkling of cinnamon sugar.
  
  7. Bake at 350 degrees until golden and crisp, 25 to 30 minutes. Cool
  slightly-, serve warm.
  
  Makes 12 to 15 3-inch tartlets.
  
  Cook's Illustrated, Mar./Apr. 1994, Page 15. Credit: Nick Malgieri.
  
  Nationality: USA Courses: dessert, pastry Season:any Method: baked
  
  Start to Finish 1 1/2 hours Preparation 5 minutes Attention 1 1/2 hours
  Finishing 5 minutes
  
  Converted from Mangia!, Cook's Illustrated 1993-1995 Cookbook
  
  Recipe by: Cook's Illustrated, Mar./Apr. 1994,  Page 15.
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest by "Hobbs, D B                 USO"
  &lt;hobbs@lbcapo1.uso.unisys.com&gt; on Mar 16, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
