<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Apple-Prosciutto Chicken</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Apples</cat>
        <cat>Cheese</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Skinless boneless chicken breasts; halved</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Apple; finely chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/8</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Apple pie spice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>5</qty>
          <unit>slices</unit></amt>
        <item>Prosciutto or boiled ham</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Apple pie spices</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Green onions; finely chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Margarine or butter</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>All-purpose flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>dash</unit></amt>
        <item>Pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Milk</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Shredded provolone cheese; two ounces</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Hot cooked rice; optional</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Rinse chicken and pat dry. Placeone chicken breast half, boned side up
  between 2 pieces of clearplastic wrap and pound lightly with the flat side
  of a meat mallet to form a rectangle about 1/4" thick. Remove plastic wrap
  and repaeat with rest of chicken. In a small bowl, combine the chopped
  apple and apple pie spice. For filling, place one prosciutto or boiled ham
  slice on top of each chicken breast half. Spoon one-fourth of the apple
  mixture over each prosciutto slce. Fold in sides and roll up each breast
  half, starting from a narrow end. Secure with wooden toothpicks or
  non-metal skewers. Arrange chicken rolls, seam side down, in an 8" round
  Microwave-safe baking dish. Sprinkle with additional apple pie spice. Cover
  with plastic wrap and turn back one corner to vent steam. Cook on High for
  6-8 minutes or for low wattage ovens for 7-9 minutes or until chicken is
  tender and no pink remains, giving the dish a half-turn and rearranging the
  rolls after 4 minutes. Remove toothpicks. Cover to keep warm. For sauce: in
  a 2 cup glass measure combine green onion and margarine or butter. Cook,
  uncovered on High for 30-40 seconds or until margarine is melted. Stir in
  flour and pepper. Stir in milk. Cook uncovered on High for 2-3 minutes or
  until thickened and bubbly, stirring after every minute until sauce starts
  to thicken, then stirring every 30 seconds. Stir in cheese and cook,
  uncovered on High about 30 seconds or until heated through, stirring once.
  Serve sauce over chicken and rice. Conventional oven directions: Prepared
  stuffed breasts as directed. Place seam side down, in a 19x6x2" baking
  dish. Bake, uncovered, in a 350ø oven for 25-30 minutes or until tender and
  no pink remains. Remove toothpicks. Meanwhile, in a small saucepan, cook
  green onion in margarine or butter until tender, but not brown .stir in
  flour and pepper. Add 2/3 cup milk all at once. Cook and stir until
  thickened and bubbly; cook and stir for 1 minute more. Stir in cheese until
  melted. Serve as directed. MC formatting and posting on Kitmailbox by
  bobbi744@sojourn.com.
  
  Recipe By     : Lansing State Journal/bobbi744@sojourn.com
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest V1 #232
  
  Date: Tue, 01 Oct 1996 15:57:21 -0400
  
  From: Robertal Banghart &lt;bobbi744@sojourn.com&gt;
  
  NOTES : Per serving; 315 calories, 116 mg. cholesterol, 12 g. fat. 43 g.
  protein, 427 mg. sodium, 6 g. carbohy
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
