<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Apple Pie (Sweet 'n Low)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Pies</cat>
        <cat>Diabetic</cat></categories>
      <yield>8</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>McIntosh apples, peeled, and thinly sliced (7 cups)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Lemon juice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter Buds Sprinkles</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>packages</unit></amt>
        <item>Sweet'N Low (or 1-1/4 ts bulk)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>All-purpose flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground cinnamon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/8</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground allspice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Sheets phyllo dough, thawed</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Nonfat frozen vanilla yogurt optional</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Preheat the oven to 375 F. Spray a 9-inch pie pan with nonstick cooking
  spray.
  
  In a large bowl, toss the apples with the lemon juice. In a small bowl,
  combine the sugar, Butter Buds, Sweet'N Low, flour, cinnamon and allspice.
  Add to the apples and toss to coat. Lightly spray one sheet of phyllo dough
  with nonstick cooking spray. Fold in half and spray again. Place in the pie
  pan with one edge hanging over the pan. Repeat the process with the
  remaining 3 sheets of dough, overlapping in the pan to cover the bottom
  completely. Spoon the apple mixture into the pan. Fold the edges of the
  dough over to cover the apples. Spray with nonstick cooking spray. Bake 35
  minutes, or until the dough is crisp and the apples are tender when pierced
  with a sharp knife. Cool slightly before serving.
  
  Serve with nonfat frozen vanilla yogurt, if desired.
  
  Variation: Seven cups of sliced fresh peaches or pears, or fresh
  blueberries, may be substituted for the apples. (Makes 1 9-inch pie,
        8    servings)
  
  Per serving (1/8 pie): 115 calories, 1 g protein, 29 g carbohydrate, 1 g
  fat, 1 g saturated fat, 0 mg cholesterol, 65 mg sodium.
  
  Diabetic exchanges: 1/2 starch, 1-1/2 fruit
  
  From Sweet 'N Low Formatted by R. Thompson
  Posted to MM-Recipes Digest  by "Chat Cat" &lt;maintech@ne.infi.net&gt; on Mar
  01, 98
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
