<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Apple-Glazed Barbecue Chicken</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>can</unit></amt>
        <item>(6 ounce) frozen apple juice concentrate, thawed</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Reduced-sodium ketchup</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Packed brown sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Cider vinegar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Dried thyme</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/8</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Hot-pepper sauce</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Boneless; skinless chicken breast halves (4 ounces each)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  by Prevention Magazine, http://www.healthyideas.com
  
  Before After Calories 317 159 Fat (g.) 10 2 % Calories from Fat 28% 11%
  Cholesterol (mg.) 69 46
  
  In a small saucepan, combine the apple juice concentrate, ketchup, brown
  sugar, vinegar, thyme and hot- pepper sauce. Cook, stirring, over medium
  heat until the sugar completely dissolves. Remove from the heat and cool to
  room temperature. Place the chicken in a single layer in a 13-by-9-inch
  baking pan. Pour about half of the cooled ketchup mixture over the chicken,
  turning once to coat both sides. Cover and refrigerate both the chicken and
  the remaining ketchup mixture for 4 to 24 hours. Coat a grill rack with
  nonstick spray. Then light the grill according the manufacturer's
  directions. Check the temperature for grilling; the temperature should be
  medium-hot (see the Test Kitchen Tip below). Place the rack on the grill.
  Remove the chicken from the ketchup mixture; discard whatever ketchup
  mixture remains in the baking pan. Coat the chicken pieces with nonstick
  spray and brush them with some of the remaining ketchup mixture. Place the
  chicken on the rack and grill, uncovered, for 8 minutes. Turn the chicken
  over and brush with the remaining ketchup mixture. Grill for 7 to 10
  minutes, or until the chicken is tender and cooked through. Discard any
  remaining ketchup mixture.
  
  TEST KITCHEN TIP: When grilling, here's how to test the temperature of the
  coals: Place your hand 4 inches over the heat source. Count the number of
  seconds that the palm of your hand can withstand the heat before you have
  to remove your hand. For a hot temperature, that should be 2 seconds. For a
  medium-hot temperature, it should be 3 seconds. Medium heat would be 4
  seconds, and low would be 5 seconds.
  
  To broil the chicken instead of grilling it, coat the rack of a broiling
  pan with nonstick spray. Remove the chicken from the ketchup mixture;
  discard whatever ketchup mixture remains in the baking pan. Coat the
  chicken pieces with nonstick spray and brush them with some of the
  remaining ketchup mixture. Place the chicken on the rack. Broil 4 inches
  from the heat for 5 minutes. Turn the chicken over and brush again with the
  remaining ketchup mixture. Broil for 4 to 6 minutes, or until the chicken
  is tender and cooked through. Discard any remaining ketchup mixture.
  
  Makes 6 servings. Posted to Digest eat-lf.v097.n184 by "Tina D. Bell"
  &lt;tdbell@altair.csustan.edu&gt; on Jul 20, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
