<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Apple Turnovers</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Apples</cat>
        <cat>Desserts</cat></categories>
      <yield>8</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Raisins</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Peeled apples; diced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Chopped pecans</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar; or to taste</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh lemon juice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground cinnamon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Sheets frozen puff pastry; thawed and chilled</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Egg</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Confectioner's sugar; for dusting</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Plump the raisins in boiling water to cover while you prepare the apples.
  Combine the apples, nuts, sugar, lemon juice, and cinnamon in a bowl and
  toss well. Drain the plumped fruit, stir it in with the other ingredients,
  and let their flavors marry while you prepare the pastry.
  
  On a lightly floured board, one at a time, roll the pastry sheets out to
  approximately 12 inches square. Trim the outer edges (this is essential for
  the puff pastry) and cut each sheet into four 6-inch squares, making eight
  in all. Place a generous 1/3 cup of fruit filling just off center in each
  square. Moisten the edges of two adjacent sides, fold the opposite sides
  over, and press to seal. Crimp the edges closed with the tines of a fork.
  Repeat with the remaining turnovers and chill thoroughly.
  
  Preheat the oven to 425 degrees. Beat together the egg and water and brush
  lightly on top of the turnover without letting the egg wash drip down the
  cut sides. Place the turnovers on cookie sheets (for puff pastry, spread a
  little cold water on the sheets but do not grease; for flaky pie pastry,
  grease the sheets). Bake until they are puffed and golden, about 20
  minutes. Serve them warm or at room temperature dusted, if you like, with
  confectioners' sugar.
  
  NOTES : Turnovers can be made in squares or circles of any size and filled
  with any fruit alone or in combination, savory as well as sweet. They are a
  fine way to use up leftover bits of this and that, including pastry, and
  their handy self-packaging makes them excellent picnic fare.
  Recipe by: A Feast Of Fruits
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest V1 #1042 by "Marie Smith" &lt;craftee@sprynet.com&gt;
  on Jan 24, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
