<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Apple Strudel Wrap</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>packages</unit></amt>
        <item>Pepperidge Farm frozen Puff Pastry Sheets (1 sheet); thawed</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg; beaten</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>All-purpose flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground cinnamon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Granny Smith apples; peeled, cored, and thinly sliced (about 3 cups)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Raisins; (optional)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Tempt your friends and family members this holiday season with this easy
  and delicious recipe from Pepperidge Farm Puff Pastry. Before preparing
  your simple strudel, be sure to return to the Puff Pastry site for helpful
  baking tips in our Chef Secrets section!
  
  1. Thaw pastry sheet at room temperature 30 minutes. Preheat oven to 375°F.
  Mix egg and water and set aside. Mix sugar, flour, and cinnamon. Add apples
  and raisins and toss to coat. Set aside.
  
  2. Unfold pastry on lightly floured surface. Roll into 16- by 12-inch
  rectangle. With short side facing you, spoon apple mixture on bottom half
  of pastry to within 1 inch of edges. Starting at short side, roll up like a
  jelly roll. Place seam-side down on baking sheet. Tuck ends under to seal.
  Brush with egg mixture. Cut several 2-inch-long slits 2 inches apart on
  top.
  
  3. Bake 35 minutes or until golden. Cool on baking sheet on wire rack about
  30 minutes before serving. Slice and serve warm. If desired, sprinkle with
  confectioners’ sugar and garnish with fresh mint.
  
  Makes 6 servings. Thaw Time: 30 minutes. Prep Time: 30 minutes. Cook Time:
       35    minutes.
  
  For more delicious holiday recipes, visit http://www.puffpastry.com
  
  By Pepperidge Farm Puff Pastry &lt;webmaster@puffpastry.com&gt; on Dec 10, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
