<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Apple Tart</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Desserts</cat>
        <cat>Fruits</cat>
        <cat>Cyberealm</cat></categories>
      <yield>8</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>PASTRY</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>All-Purpose Flour</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Unsalted Butter, cut up</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Milk</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Egg Yolk</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>APPLE FILING</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>28</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Golden Delicous Apples,</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Peeled, cored, and sliced</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>1/4" thick (6 cups)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Lemon Juice</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>APRICOT GLAZE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Apricot Jam</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Apricot Brandy</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Pastry: In a food processor combine flour, 2 ts sugar and salt. Add butter
  and pulse with on/off turns until mixture resembles fine cornmeal. Ib a 1
  cup measure, whisk milk and egg yolk until blended. With processor running,
  pour in egg mixture, processing until dough pulls away from sides of bowl
  and forms a ball. Form dough into a flat rectangular shape. Wrap in plastic
  wrap. Refrigerate for 20 minutes.
  
  Apple Filling: In a large bowl, toss sliced apples with lemon juice. Set
  aside.
  
  Assembly: Preheat oven to 425øF. On a heavily floured surface, roll out
  pastry to 16x12" rectangle. Arrange pastry flat on a large baking sheet.
  Overlap apple slices in 3 lengthwise rows atop pastry, leaving a 1" border
  of pastry on all sides. Fold edge of pastry up to, and slightly overlapping
  apples. Press together seams of pastry at corners to seal. Pinch together
  and cracks in pastry along edges to hold in juices. Sprinkle apples with 2
  tb sugar. Bake at 425øF for 25-30 minutes until apples are tender and crust
  is browned. Remove from oven and dust with 1 tb sugar, then brush with warm
  glaze. Cool tart on baking sheet set on rack.
  
  Apricot Glaze: While tart is baking, in a small saucepan stir apricot jam
  and apricot brandy over medium heat until melted. Press through a sieve.
  
  Source: Victoria Magazine, January 1994 Typed by Katherine Smith Cyberealm
  BBS and home of Kook-Net, Watertown, NY 315-786-1120
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
