<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Apricot Tea Ring</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Breads</cat>
        <cat>Yeast</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>DOUGH</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Cake compressed yeast; or... Dry yeast</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Lukewarm water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Milk; scalded</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Brown sugar, firmly packed</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Shortening</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sifted all-purpose flour (plus more as necessary)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Egg; beaten</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Quaker Oats, uncooked (quick or old-fashioned)</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>FILLING</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>12</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Dried apricots</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Lemon juice</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  For dough, soften yeast in lukewarm water.  (Use warm water for dry
  yeast.)  Pour scalded milk over sugar, salt and shortening.  Cool to
  lukewarm.  Stir in 1 cup flour and egg.  Add softened yeast and oats.
  Stir in enough more flour to make a soft dough.
  
  Turn out on lightly floured board or canvas; knead until smooth and
  satiny; about 10 minutes.  Round dough into ball; place in greased bowl;
  brush lightly with melted shortening.  Cover and let rise in warm place
  until double in size, about 1 hour.
  
  While dough is rising, prepare filling.  For filling, combine apricots,
  water, lemon juice and sugar in medium-sized saucepan.  Cook over low
  heat, stirring occasionally until thickened.  Cool.
  
  Punch dough down; cover; let rest 10 minutes.  Roll to form an 18x12-inch
  rectangle.  Brush with melted butter; spread with filling.  Starting with
  long side, roll up as for jelly roll.  Form into circle on greased cooky
  sheet, sealed edge down.  Make cuts 2/3 of way through ring at 1-inch
  intervals.  Turn one section to left and next to right. Repeat around
  ring. [Cut edges showing a spiral of filling will be exposed, and parallel
  with the work surface. --K.M.]  Brush lightly with melted shortening.
  
  Cover; let rise in warm place until nearly double in size, about 45
  minutes.  Bake in preheated moderate oven (350 F.) 20 to 25 minutes.
  Drizzle with confectioner's sugar frosting while still warm.  Makes one
  large tea ring.
  
  Source: Our Favorites for family and friends
  Reprinted with permission from The Quaker Oats Company
  Electronic format courtesy of Karen Mintzias
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/quaker01.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
