<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Apricot-Raisin Jam</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Apricot</cat>
        <cat>Jams</cat>
        <cat>Gift</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Dried apricot halves, coarsely chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Golden raisins</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Juice and grated rind of 1 lemon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Orange juice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  I received a great little book for Christmas called
  "From My House To Yours" that has gift recipes, ideas
  and lots of little tid-bits. The following recipe is
  from that book.  I'll include the notes the author
  wrote and will follow this message with the recipe for
  English Muffin Loaf that he makes note of. Sonya
  
  "This is delicious with toasted thin slices of English
  Muffin Loaf. Dried apricots sold in bulk are usually
  more flavorful than the prepackaged kind; natural food
  stores are a good source."
  
  1. Place the apricots and raisins in a bowl and add
  water to cover. Cover the bowl tightly and let it
  stand overnight. Drain the liquid into a large, heavy
  saucepan and chop the apricots coarsely. Add the
  apricots, raisins, lemon juice and rind, and orange
  juice to the pan, place over low heat, and bring to a
  simmer. Cook 20 minutes, stirring occasionally.
  
  2. Add the sugar and continue cooking, stirring
  frequently until the mixture of fruit is very soft and
  the syrup sheets when dropped from the side of a spoon
  (220 degrees on a candy thermometer), 15 to 20
  minutes. Spoon the jam into sterilized half-pint jars.
  Seal the jars, process in a boiling-water bath for 10
  minutes and cool. Store in a cool, dark place.
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
