<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Apricots - Halved or Sliced</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Fruits</cat>
        <cat>Canning</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients/>
    <directions>
      <step>  Quantity: An average of 16 pounds is needed per canner load of 7 quarts; an
  average of 10 pounds is needed per canner load of 9 pints. A bushel weighs
  50 pounds and yields 20 to 25 quarts-an average of 2-1/4 pounds per quart.
  
  Quality: Select firm, well-colored mature fruit of ideal quality for eating
  fresh.
  
  Procedure: (Optional--Dip fruit in boiling water for 30 to 60 seconds until
  skins loosen. Dip quickly in cold water and slip off skins). Wash fruit.
  Cut in half, remove pits and slice if desired. To prevent darkening, keep
  peeled fruit in ascorbic acid solution. Prepare and boil a very light,
  light, or medium syrup or pack apricots in water, apple juice, or white
  grape juice. Raw packs make poor quality apricots.
  
  Processing directions for canning apricots in a dial or weighted-gauge
  canner are given in Table 1 and Table 2.
  
  Table 1. Process Times for Apricots (Halved or Sliced) in a Dial-Gauge
  Pressure Canner.
  
  Style of Pack: Hot and Raw.  Jar Size: Pints or Quarts. Process Time: 10
  min. Canner Pressure (PSI) at Altitudes of 0 - 2,000 ft: 6 lb.
                                  2,001 - 4,000 ft: 7 lb.
                                  4,001 - 6,000 ft: 8 lb.
                                  6,001 - 8,000 ft: 9 lb.
  
  Table 2. Process Times for Apricots (Halved or Sliced) in a Weighted-Gauge
  Pressure Canner.
  
  Style of Pack: Hot and Raw.  Jar Size: Pints or Quarts. Process Time: 10
  min. Canner Pressure (PSI) at Altitudes of 0 - 1,000 ft: 5 lb.
                                    Above 1,000 ft: 10 lb.
  
  ======================================================= ===== * USDA
  Agriculture Information Bulletin No. 539 (rev. 1994) * Meal-Master format
  courtesy of Karen Mintzias
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
