<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Apricot Dumplings</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>DOUGH</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Medium-size potatoes</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Beer or water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3/4</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Stick butter; cut into small pieces</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Eggs</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Baking powder</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>FILLING</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>10</qty>
            <unit>small</unit></amt>
          <item>Fresh apricots or canned whole apricots, pitted (up to 12)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>7</qty>
            <unit>quarts</unit></amt>
          <item>Salted water; Approximately (up to 8)</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>TO SERVE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Bread crumbs sauteed in:</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Stick butter</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  1. Boil the potatoes until tender. Drain and push through a food mill or
  sieve. Let cool.
  
  2. Bring the beer, butter, and salt to a boil, and boil gently until butter
  has melted.
  
  3. Pour in the flour all at once and beat with a wooden spoon until the
  dough forms a mass and leaves the sides of the pan.
  
  4. Off the heat, beat in the eggs, one at a time, beating until completely
  blended. (If you have a food processor, transfer the dough to the food
  processor bowl and beat in the eggs one by one, using the steel blade.)
  
  5. Beat in the potatoes, sugar, and the baking powder.
  
  6. Remove to a well-floured board and roll the dough out to a thickness of
  1/8 inch. Cut into rounds with a 2 1/2-inch cookie cutter.
  
  7. Place an apricot in the center of each round and bring up the dough to
  enclose the apricot. Roll into a ball and dust with flour.
  
  8. Bring the water to a boil. Drop the dumplings into the boiling water and
  simmer until they rise to the top. Remove with a slotted spoon and arrange
  them in a buttered ovenproof dish.
  
  9. Pour buttered bread crumbs over the apricot dumplings and bake on a 375
  degree oven until golden brown. Serve immediately. Yield: About 10 to 12
  dumplings.
  
  Posted to EAT-L Digest  by Bonnie &lt;solomon1@KCSNET.COM&gt; on Sep 6, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
