<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Ari's Bread Machine Notes and Basic Bread Recipe</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Digest</cat>
        <cat>Feb95</cat>
        <cat>Fatfree</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Text Reference</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Here are my favorite tips and basic bread recipe:
  
  1.  Don't by those tiny packets of active-dry yeast.  Get it in bulk in a
  health-food store.  They charge at least 10x more for those tiny packets --
  you're paying almost entirely for the packaging.  (Store yeast in the
  fridge.)  1 packet = 1 TB.
  
  2. Wheat gluten is very useful in helping the dough rise.  I add around 1
  TB per cup of non-bread flour ingredients.
  
  3. Oil is NOT necessary and actually detracts from the taste.  All you
  really need for good bread is flour, salt, yeast, and water. Everything
  else is optional.
  
  4. The best breads are simply a mix of flours (whole wheat, rye, oats,
  corn, buckwheat, rice, or whatever you like).  Remember thought that wheat
  flours are necessary for the gluten content, unless you add gluten
  separately.  Adding fruits and herbs and flavored liquids are interesting
  but I prefer "pure" breads.  I prefer graham flour over regular whole
  wheat.
  
  5.  Each machine is different and my recipes are usually not exact -- if
  the dough looks sticky and isn't forming a ball then it's too wet: add more
  flour; if it looks dry (ball doesn't have a relatively smooth surface, for
  example) add more liquid a tablespoon or two at a time.
  
  OK, so with all that idealism taken care of here's my basic bread recipe:
  
  1 TB  active dry yeast 1 1/2 cup bread flour 1 1/2 cup graham (whole wheat)
  flour 1/2 cup rye flour (use the coarse grind, preferably) 2 TB wheat
  gluten (sometime called vital wheat gluten) 1 tsp salt 1 TB honey 1 2/3 cup
  water
  
  Add ingredients in order suggested by your bread machine manual.
  
  This is intended for a 3 cup bread maker, if your machine is smaller just
  scale it accordingly.  Similarly, your bread maker may suggest using less
  than 1 TB yeast.
  
  For a particularly festive bread try adding 1 TB basil 1 TB tarragon 1 tsp
  rosemary chopped garlic...
  
  Posted by Ari Kornfeld &lt;ari@perspective.com&gt; to the Fatfree Digest [Volume
       15    Issue 23] Feb. 23, 1995.
  
  Individual recipes copyrighted by originator. FATFREE Recipe collections
  copyrighted by Michelle Dick 1995. Formatted by Sue Smith,
  SueSmith9@aol.com using MMCONV. Archived through kindness of Karen
  Mintzias, km@salata.com.
  
  1.80รก
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/fatfreex.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
