<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Ari's Bread Machine Notes</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Help</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>No ingredients; help file</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Date: Thu, 21 Mar 1996 14:22:39 -0500
  
  From: Dotnapier@aol.com
  
  Posted by Ari Kornfeld &lt;ari@perspective.com&gt; to the Fatfree Digest [Volume
  15 Issue 23] Feb. 23, 1995. Here are my favorite tips and basic bread
  recipe:
  
  1. Don't by those tiny packets of active-dry yeast. Get it in bulk in a
  health-food store. They charge at least 10x more for those tiny packets --
  you're paying almost entirely for the packaging. (Store yeast in the
  fridge.) 1 packet=1 TB.
  
  2. Wheat gluten is very useful in helping the dough rise. I add around 1 TB
  per cup of non-bread flour ingredients.
  
  3. Oil is NOT necessary and actually detracts from the taste. All you
  really need for good bread is flour, salt, yeast, and water. Everything
  else is optional.
  
  4. The best breads are simply a mix of flours (whole wheat, rye, oats,
  corn, buckwheat, rice, or whatever you like). Remember thought that wheat
  flours are necessary for the gluten content, unless you add gluten
  separately. Adding fruits and herbs and flavored liquids are interesting
  but I prefer "pure" breads. I prefer graham flour over regular whole wheat.
  
  5. Each machine is different and my recipes are usually not exact -- if the
  dough looks sticky and isn't forming a ball then it's too wet: add more
  flour; if it looks dry (ball doesn't have a relatively smooth surface, for
  example) add more liquid a tablespoon or two at a time.
  
  MM-RECIPES@IDISCOVER.NET
  
  MEAL-MASTER RECIPES LIST SERVER
  
  MM-RECIPES DIGEST V3 #83
  
  From the MealMaster recipe list.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
