<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Arizona Sunset Cheesecake</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Kooknet</cat>
        <cat>Cyberealm</cat>
        <cat>Cheesecake</cat>
        <cat>Cakes</cat>
        <cat>Desserts</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>(Shortbread Crust):</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Finely ground pecans</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Egg, separated</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter, softened</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>(Cranberry Glaze Filling)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>can</unit></amt>
        <item>Whole berry cranberry- sauce OR 2 cups cranberry orange relish</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Cornstarch</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Grated lemon zest</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Lemon juice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>(White Chocolate Filling):</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh orange juice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>1-3 Inch x 1 inch piece- of orange peel (orange part only)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>8 oz pkgs cream cheese</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2/3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Grated orange zest</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Cranberry Liqueur (such- as Crantasia Schnapps)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>8</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>White chocolate, melted</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>(Candied Oranges Topping):</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Seedless oranges (unpeeled)- cut into paper-thin slices</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>(Garnish):</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Whipped Cream</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Shortbread Crust: Preheat the oven to 400 degrees F. Working on a large
  flat surface, such as a pastry board, place flour, pecans, and sugar in the
  center of the surface and mix together. Form a small depression or well in
  the center of the mound. Add the egg yolk and the softened butter to the
  well, then blend these with the dry mixture. Mix the ingredients thoroughly
  using your hands -- there is no substitute for warm hands. Shape the dough
  into a ball and wrap in plastic wrap. Chill for at least 10 minutes. Roll
  out the dough to a thickness of about 1/4-inch. You should have a circle of
  about 11 inches in diameter. For best results, roll out your dough between
  2 sheets of waxed paper, then peel away the paper and cut the crust in a 9
  inch circle. Place the circle inside a 9 inch springform pan. Prick the
  crust several times with a fork to keep the crust from puffing up during
  the baking. Place the springform pan in the oven and bake for 15 to 20
  minutes, or until light brown. Allow to cool. Using the leftover dough,
  line the sides of the springform pan. Press the dough against the sides of
  the pan, smoothing it so as to have a continuous layer of crust all the way
  around the sides of the pan. Make sure that the side crust meets the bottom
  crust all the way around. Brush the reserved egg white onto the shell,
  covering the bottom and sides. This will seal the dough and keep it from
  becoming soggy. Set aside until ready to use.
  
  Cranberry Glaze Filling: Mix the sugar and cornstarch together in a small
  saucepan. Stir in the cranberry sauce. Cook over medium heat, stirring
  constantly, until thick. Stir in the lemon zest and lemon juice. Set aside
  to cool slightly.
  
  White Chocolate Filling: Reset the oven to 350 degrees F. Boil the orange
  juice and piece of orange peel in a heavy medium saucepan until the juice
  is reduced to 3 Tbsp - about 12 minutes. Remove and discard the strip of
  orange peel and set aside the reduced orange juice. Using an electric
  mixer, beat the cream cheese, sugar, grated orange zest, Crantasia, and
  reduced orange juice until smooth. Beat in the melted white chocolate and
  then the eggs, one at a time, beating just until combined. Pour the
  cranberry glaze filling into the prepared crust, spreading evenly. Pour the
  white chocolate filling over the cranberry layer and bake about 50 minutes
  (the top will be dry and the sides puffed slightly - the center will not be
  set). Move cheesecake to a wire rack and cool completely to room
  temperature. Chill in the refrigerator overnight.
  
  Candied Oranges Topping: Cover a wire rack with waxed paper. Set aside.
  Combine the water and sugar in a heavy shallow wide skillet. Stir over
  medium heat until the sugar dissolves. Simmer 5 minutes longer. Add the
  orange slices 1 at a time and adjust the heat so that the syrup bubbles
  only around the edges of the pan. Cook the oranges for one hour. Turn over
  the top layer of oranges and cook until the oranges are translucent and the
  orange peels tender, about another one hour longer. Lift and drain each
  orange slice out of the syrup, and arrange the slices in a single layer on
  the prepared rack. Let dry 1 hour. Boil the orange-sugar syrup until thick,
  about 6 minutes.
  
  Loosen and remove the sides of the springform pan. Set the cheesecake on a
  serving dish. Overlap the candied orange slices around the top of the
  cheesecake. Reheat the orange syrup, if necessary, and brush over the
  orange slices. Drizzle any remainder over each serving. Garnish: whipped
  cream NOTE: You may substitute grapefruits for the oranges in the Candied
  Oranges Topping if you prefer.
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
