<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Arnaud's Creme Brulee</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>8</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Heavy cream</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>12</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg yolks; large</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Vanilla bean</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Pecans</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Whole butter</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>dashes</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Sheet frozen puff pastry</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Heat 3 1/2 cups heavy cream and 1/2 cup sugar over medium heat in a gallon
  sauce pot and bring to a boil.
  
  Meanwhile, combine egg yolks, 1/2 cup sugar and 1/2 cup cream in the top of
  a double boiler. over medium heat Whip until a light lemon color and ribbon
  stage is reached. Remove cream from the heat, and take the pan with the
  yolk mixture out of the double boiler.
  
  Slowly pour the cream into the yolk mixture, stirring to blend. Return the
  pan to the double boiler and continue to heat until mixture becomes thick
  (approximately 178×). Remove from heat and allow to cool, stirring
  occasionally.
  
  Mix the pecans, butter, 1/4 cup sugar and salt in a small bowl. Spread on a
  baking sheet and roast at 400× until pecans begin to brown. Remove from
  oven and cool.
  
  Roll out the puff pastry very thin. Use a fork or docker to dock the dough.
  Conform pastry to the inside of large muffin tins and line each cup with
  foil and fill with dried beans or pastry weights. Blind bake at 375× for
  approximately 10 minutes. Remove from the oven, take out the foil. Leave in
  the tins and set aside to cool.
  
  When cool, place about 1 tablespoon of pecan mixture in each cup and top
  with creme brulee mixture. Refrigerate for about 25 minutes to set up.
  Sprinkle generously with white sugar. Using a butane torch, broil tops
  until golden brown. Return to refrigerator to chill for about 15 minutes.
  source: Arnaud's Restaurant Home Page
  
  Posted to recipelu-digest Volume 01 Number 510 by jecraig@lan-inc.com on
  Jan 13, 98
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
