<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Arni Lemonato (Lemon Lamb)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Greek</cat>
        <cat>Lamb</cat>
        <cat>Ceideburg 2</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Text Only</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Simple ethnic recipes, unchanged for generations, often have an
  authority that the latest food fashions cannot begin to match.  The
  following Greek lemon lamb dish is a case in point.  Faithful to its
  frugal origins. this recipe works equally well with cheap cuts like
  lamb shanks. breast of lamb or best end of neck.  If you do use these
  fattier meals, make the dish a day ahead, refrigerate it and remove
  the fat that coagulates on top. if anything, the dish gains added
  depth of flavour when made ahead and reheated.
  
  Trim skin and ail excess fat from a boned shoulder or leg of lamb.
  Squeeze enough lemons to provide 1/3 cup of juice.  Open out the meat
  and rub both inside and outside surfaces with some of the lemon juice
  and sprinkle them with salt and pepper.  On the inside surface of the
  meat, sprinkle a teaspoon of dried oregano or 1/2 a tablespoon of
  chopped fresh oregano. Roll the meat up and tie securely.
  
  Heat a tablespoon of olive oil in a pot large enough to take the roll
  comfortably and brown the meat on all sides.  Turn the heat down to
  low and add to the pot the rest of the lemon juice, 2 cloves of
  garlic, crushed, and another teaspoon of dried oregano or 1/2
  tablespoon of fresh.
  
  Cover the pot and simmer very gently, turning occasionally, for about
  2 1/2 hours, till very tender.  If you like, add small new potatoes
  to the pot about an hour before serving.
  
  To serve, remove the string and slice the meat into the centre of a
  heated serving platter.  Surround with potatoes and pour lemony
  juices over the meat.
  
  Makes 6 servings.
  
  From "Raw Materials" by Meryl Constance, The Syndey Morning Herald,
  10/6/92.  Courtesy Mark Herron.
  
  Posted by Stephen Ceideberg; October 30 1992.
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/cberg2.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
