<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Arroz De Sabato (Sabbath Rice Pilav with Saffron)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>PLAIN RICE PILAV</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Long grain white or brown rice</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Olive oil</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>(scant) salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Chicken stock or vegetable stock; (up to 5)</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  RFCJ Reposts (from rec.food.cooking.jewish
  
  &gt;From: Lita (alotzkar@direct.ca)
  
  Source: "The Sephardic Kitchen" by Rabbi Robert Sternberg HarperCollins
  Publishers
  
  Servings: 6 - 8
  
  Follow the directions below for Plain Rice Pilav, adding 1 bay leaf and 1/4
  teaspoon saffron threads dissolved in 1/4 cup boiling water to the rice
  together with the stock. Cook as directed. The rice gets a beautiful yellow
  color and a heady aroma from the saffron and bay leaf. The bay leaf will be
  resting on top of the rice at the end of cooking. Remove and discard it
  before serving. Serve as a side dish with a meat, fish, or vegetarian
  entree.
  
  Plain Rice Pilav:
  
  1. Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F.
  
  2. If using white rice, you will need 4 cups stock. If using brown rice you
  will use 5 cups stock.
  
  3. If using white rice, place the rice in a colander and rinse it in the
  sink in cold water until the water runs clear. Allow the rice to drain and
  dry for 20 minutes. If using brown rice, skip this step.
  
  4. Over medium heat, heat the olive oil in a casserole with a tight fitting
  lid. Saute the rice in the oil until it starts to brown.
  
  5. Sprinkle the salt over the rice and pour in the stock. Cover tightly and
  place in the oven. Bake for 35-40 minutes (white rice) to 1 hour (brown
  rice). When the pilaf is done, all of the liquid will have been absorbed. A
  lovely aroma will fill the room when you open the lid of the pot. Serve
  immediately as a side dish with a meat, fish or vegetarian entree.
  
  Posted to JEWISH-FOOD digest V97 #316 by Jeff Freedman
  &lt;jefffree@eskimo.com&gt; on Dec 03, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
