<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Arroz Con Leche (Mexican Rice Pudding)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Desserts</cat>
        <cat>Puddings</cat>
        <cat>Mexican</cat>
        <cat>Dairy</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Cinnamon stick, 2"</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Lime zest, 2" strip x 3/4" wide</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Rice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>quart</unit></amt>
        <item>Milk</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Egg yolks</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Vanilla extract</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Raisins</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter, sweet; cut into bits</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Ground cinnamon; for garnish</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  The rice.  Bring 2 c water to boil in med saucepan, add cinnamon stick and
  lime zest, cover and simmer over med heat for 5 min. Pour in rice, let mix
  return to boil, stir once, then cover and cook over med-low heat for 20
  min, until all the liquid is absorbed and the rice is tender.
  
  The pudding.  Stir in milk, sugar, and salt and simmer over med to med-low
  heat, stirring frequently, until the liquid shows the FIRST signs of
  thickening, 20-25 min. Take from the heat and remove the cinn stick and
  zest.  Beat the egg yolks until runny, stir in the vanilla and a few T of
  the hot rice, the stir yolk concoction back into the rice mixture, Mix in
  HALF the raisins, then spoon the rice pudding into a decorative 8"square
  baking dish.
  
  Browning and finishing the pudding.  Preheat the broiler and dot the rice
  pudding w/butter.  Set the dish under the heat long enough to brown the
  top, 3 or 4 min. Sprinkle with remaining raisins and the ground cinnamon,
  and serve warm or at room temperature.
  
  COOK'S NOTES:
  
  Timing and Advance Preparation The rice pudding can be ready in an hour,
  much of which won't involve your direct participation. It may be prepared
  through Step 2 a day or two in advance, then buttered and broiled shortly
  before serving.
  
                               -- The Cuisines of Mexico
                                  Diana Kennedy
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
