<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Art's Stuffed Jalapeno Peppers</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Appetizers</cat>
        <cat>Hot and spi</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>12</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Jalapeno peppers</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Cream cheese; room temperature</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Onion; finely chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Cheddar cheese; shredded</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Black pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Granulated garlic</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Dried parsley</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Dried chives</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Old Bay Seasonings (TM) [Seafood Spice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Mixture]</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Ham; cooked bacon, or other leftover meat, finely chopped</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  In a two-quart sauce pan, bring one quart of water to a rolling boil. While
  it is reaching a boil, Cut a long flap in each jalapeno, starting from the
  shoulder and running close to the tip; this should be an elongated "V"
  shaped flap. Lift the flap and clean out the fibers and seeds (this is
  where most of the heat is); I use either a round-tipped peeling device or a
  teaspoon. When water reaches boiling point, immerse cleaned peppers in the
  water and reduce heat to medium. Let peppers parboil for about 10
  minutes.... better that they be a little undercooked then overcooked.
  
  Mix the rest of the ingredients together, turning and blending until the
  cream cheese is well mixed into the rest of the ingredients. If the mixture
  seems too dry, add a little sour cream, pickle juice, vinegar, anything in
  the fridge you think might add a touch of individuality.
  
  Remove peppers, dump into a strainer, and run cold water over them. Lift
  the flap of each pepper and stuff the cheese mixture into the pocket; fold
  the flap back down over the stuffing. A little overstuffing is OK.
  
  Place the peppers on a sprayed pan and bake at 400 degrees for about 10 0
  15 minutes; just until the cheese begins to melt out of the peppers. Remove
  and let cool for about 4 - 5 so the cheese sets up a little. Serve with a
  few crackers or tortilla chips.
  
  Parboiling the peppers removes a substantial portion of the raw heat, but
  leaves enough to give a nice burn to the mouth. I fixed this as an
  appetizer for Doris and I tonight. They serve 2 - 3 people, depending on
  how soon dinner is to be served! Left over filling can be saved for several
  days for another batch or to eat on crackers, in celery, on (when no one is
  looking) by the forkful!
  
  NOTES : This recipe is my own creation.... tested, tasted, tested, tasted,
  etc. and true.
  Posted to TNT - Prodigy's Recipe Exchange Newsletter  by Art Guyer
  &lt;Beach_Bum@usa.net&gt; on Nov 20, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
