<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Artichokes Stuffed with Lemon-Garlic Breadcrumbs</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh breadcrumbs from French bread; crustless</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Olive oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh lemon juice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh oregano; chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Cloves garlic; minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Lemon peel; grated</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit>medium</unit></amt>
        <item>Artichokes*</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter; (1/4 stick) cut into 6 pieces</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Water; (or more)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Lemon wedges</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  *To prepare the artichokes: Squeeze juice from 2 lemon halves into large
  bowl of cold water; add squeezed lemon halves. Cut off top half of each
  artichoke and discard. Cut off stem of artichoke. Starting at base, bend
  tough outer leaves back and snap off where they break naturally, leaving
  tender inner leaves. Using small sharp knife, trim outside of base until no
  dark green areas remain. Scoop out fibrous choke and small purple-tipped
  leaves, using spoon. Rub exposed areas with lemon half. Place in lemon
  water until ready to use or up to 2 hours.
  
  Heat oven to 400øF. Mix breadcrumbs and oil in medium bowl. Spread mixture
  on large rimmed baking sheet. Bake until golden on edges, stirring
  occasionally, about 10 minutes. Transfer to large bowl. Mix in lemon juice,
  oregano, garlic and lemon peel. Season with salt and pepper.
  
  Drain artichokes. Gently pull leaves outward from center until leaves open
  slightly. Fill artichoke cavities with bread stuffing. Pack stuffing
  between leaves. Place artichokes in 13x9x2 glass baking dish. Dot tops with
  butter. Pour 1/2 cup water into dish.
  
  Cover dish with foil; bake until wooden skewer pierces artichokes easily;
  adding more water as necessary, about 40 minutes. Remove foil. Continue
  baking until tops are golden, about 20 minutes.
  
  Serve with lemon wedges.
  
  Printed in Bon Appetit April 1998
  
  Note: Joanne Weir, a San Francisco-based cookbook author, food write and
  chef, is currently working on a 26-part PBS television series called Now
  Weir Cooking, scheduled to air nationally in 1999.
  
  Typed and Busted by Carriej999@AOL.com 4/98
  
  Recipe by: Joanne Weir
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest by Carriej999 &lt;Carriej999@aol.com&gt; on Apr 5,
  1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
