<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Asantewa's Stew</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>package</unit></amt>
        <item>(16-oz) dried black-eyed peas</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Onion; chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Cayenne pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Curry powder</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Seasoned salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Tomato; sliced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>can</unit></amt>
        <item>(6-oz) tomato paste</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>can</unit></amt>
        <item>(15-oz) boned and skinned salmon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>packages</unit></amt>
        <item>(10-oz) frozen chopped spinach; thawed and drained</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Re the request for a black-eyed pea recipe, this one was in the Los Angeles
  Times holiday section today. I haven't tried it, but it sounded good. It
  doesn't have any meat, but it does have fish. For this reason, it might be
  more "non-bean-eater friendly."
  
  Soak black-eyed peas in water to cover overnight. Drain. Add water to
  cover, bring to boil, reduce heat and simmer 30 minutes. Drain and reserve
  cooking liquid. Set aside.
  
  Pour oil in large pot. Add onion, cayenne, curry powder, seasoned salt and
  salt to taste and cook over medium-high heat until onion begins to brown, 5
  to 7 minutes. Add tomato slices and cook 3 minutes. Stir in tomato paste.
  Stir in 1/2 cup water and simmer 5 minutes. Add salmon, including juice,
  and break into bite-size pieces with back of wooden spoon. Simmer 3
  minutes.
  
  Add black-eyed peas and reserved cooking liquid and water if necessary to
  make 4 to 5 cups. Simmer 5 minutes. Add spinach and cook 20 minutes. Add
  more reserved cooking water if needed to keep stew moist but not soupy.
  Season with salt to taste. Serve over rice.
  
  8 servings. Each serving without rice: 357 cal; 307 mg sodium; 26 mg
  cholesterol; 8 g fat; 43 g carbohydrates; 31 g protein; 3.71 g fiber; 20%
  CFF.
  
  Maybe I'll try cooking it for New Years. Who can say no to good luck?
  
  Posted to Digest eat-lf.v097.n323 by bgaerlan@ucla.edu (Barbara Gaerlan) on
  Dec 21, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
