<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Asiago Bagels</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Bagels</cat></categories>
      <yield>12</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>packages</unit></amt>
        <item>Active dry yeast</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flour; approximately</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Asiago Cheese; or parmesan cheese</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Egg yolk</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Combine yeast and 2 cups warm (110@) water in a large bowl; let stand 5
  mins. Stir in sugar, salt and 5 1/2 cups flour til moistened.
  
  Spread 1/2 cup flour on a board and scrape dough onto it. Knead dough til
  very smooth and elastic, 10 to 15 mins; add more flour as required to
  prevent sticking. Place dough in a lightly oiled bowl, cover with plastic
  wrap and let rise in a warm place til almost doubled, about 40 mins.
  
  When dough is almost risen, bring 3 quarts water to boiling in a covered 4
  to 5 qt pan over high heat. Meanwhile knead dough on a lightly floured
  board to expel air then divide into 12 equal pieces. To shape bagel, knead
  each piece into a smooth ball. Holding the ball with both hand, poke you
  thumbs thru the center to form a hole. With 1 thumb in the hole, work
  around the bagel to make it smooth and evenly thick.
  
  Set bagels on lightly floured 12 x 15" baking sheets; let stand covered
  with plastic wrap just til they are slightly puffy, about 10 mins. With
  your hand, gently slip bagels into boiling water, adding 4 at a time to
  pan. Adjust heat to maintain a gentle boil and turn bagels often til they
  feel firm but are still slightly spongy, 3 to 5 mins. Chill remaining
  bagels til ready to use. With a slotted spoon transfer bagels to a towel;
  drain briefly, then place bagels slightly apart on 2 lightly oiled 12 x 15"
  baking sheets.
  
  In a food processor or with a knife, coarsely chop cheese. Beat egg yolk to
  blend with 1 tbsp water and brush mixture over bagels. Then pat cheese onto
  bagels, pressing gently to make cheese stick. Bake bagels in a 375@ oven
  til browned, 30 to 35 mins. Cool on racks. Serve warm or cool.
  
  Recipe by: Sunset Magazine
  
  Posted to KitMailbox Digest  by Cairn Rodrigues &lt;cairnann@yahoo.com&gt; on Apr
  18, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
