<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Asian-Poached Salmon with Warm Cucumber Salsa</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>POACHING LIQUID</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Garlic cloves; peeled, sliced</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Shallot; peeled, sliced</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>2-inch piece fresh ginger; thinly sliced</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>can</unit></amt>
          <item>(14 1/2 ounces) Oriental broth or low-sodium chicken broth</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 3/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Seasoned rice vinegar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Soy sauce</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Dry hot mustard</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>SALMON</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Salmon fillets; roughly same thickness, about 6 ounces each</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Cucumber salsa; recipe follows</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Preparation time: 10 minutes Cooking time: 15 minutes Yield: 4 servings
  
  &gt;From Abby Mandel. Special to the Tribune. (Copyright) 1997, Abby Mandel.
  Poached fish, whether whole (wrapped in cheesecloth to help transfer it
  from pan) or fillets, can be served hot or chilled. To serve this salmon
  hot, poach it until just cooked as desired. To serve chilled, stop poaching
  before it's cooked completely; the salmon will cool down in the liquid,
  which cooks it further.
  
  1. For poaching liquid, put ingredients in non-aluminum, 10-inch saute pan.
  Heat to boil over high heat; simmer over medium heat, uncovered, 10
  minutes.
  
  2. For salmon, place single layer of fillets in poaching liquid. Place a
  piece of parchment paper or foil directly over salmon. Simmer until cooked
  as desired, about 3 to 6 minutes, depending on thickness of fish. If
  serving hot, use spatula to transfer fish from liquid to warm serving
  dishes. If serving chilled, let fish cool in liquid. When cool, use spatula
  to transfer to storage container. Strain poaching liquid and pour about 1/2
  cup over salmon to keep it moist. Store remaining poaching liquid in
  refrigerator up to 3 days or freezer as long as 3 months to use again for
  fish and/or shellfish, adding liquid and more ingredients as needed. 3. To
  serve hot, spoon warm salsa on salmon. To serve cold, let salsa chill in
  refrigerator. Remove poaching liquid from around chilled salmon. Top salmon
  with chilled salsa.
  
  Nutritional information (per serving): 314 calories, 1 g carbohydrates, 37
  g protein, 17 g fat, 105 mg cholesterol, 235 mg sodium.
  Posted to TNT - Prodigy's Recipe Exchange Newsletter  by Roserairie@aol.com
  on Nov 10, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
