<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Asian Beef and Noodle Toss</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Asian</cat>
        <cat>Beef</cat></categories>
      <yield>2</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground beef</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>packages</unit></amt>
        <item>(3-oz) Oriental flavor instant Ramen noodles</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Oriental vegetable mixture; frozen</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/8</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground ginger</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Green onion; thin, or chives</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  In large, nonstick skillet, brown ground beef over medium heat 8 to 10
  minutes or until beef is no longer pink, breaking up into crumbles. Remove
  with slotted spoon to plate lined with paper towels; pour off drippings.
  
  Put beef onto plate and season it with one seasoning packet from noodles;
  set aside.
  
  In same skillet, combine water, vegetables, noodles (broken into several
  pieces), ginger, and remaining seasoning packet. Bring to a boil; reduce
  heat. Cover; simmer 3 minutes or until noodles are tender, stirring
  occasionally.
  
  Return beef to skillet; heat through. Stir in green onion before serving.
  
  Mitch's notes: Quick, easy, and good. The original recipe called for 1 cup
  vegetables. I used two, and you could use more. I used 3/4 pounds of ground
  beef. That was plenty and could be cut more if you're trying to avoid meat.
  Chicken or pork should work just fine for this also. Original recipe called
  for 3/4 inch "crumbles" of meat. I think that's too large. I think I'll use
  just a little more ginger next time, but this was just fine with the
  seasoning packets. I added the chives option, since I had those and had no
  green onions. Works just fine. Original recipe says this serves four. No it
  doesn't.
  
  Recipe by: Mitch's adaptation from Nat. Cattlemen's Beef Assoc.
  
  Posted to TNT Recipes Digest, Vol 01, Nr 942 by MJSpence &lt;MJSpence@aol.com&gt;
  on Jan 15, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
