<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Asian Fondue</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>5</qty>
            <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
          <item>Beef bones with marrow; cleaned and soaked overnight</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>5</qty>
            <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
          <item>Oxtails; cut into small pieces</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Water to cover</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Onions; unpeeled, halved and studded with cloves</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Shallots unpeeled</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Whole fresh ginger; unpeeled</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>8</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Star anise</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Garlic cloves; (up to 5)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Cinnamon stick</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>5</qty>
            <unit>medium</unit></amt>
          <item>Parsnips cut into 2-inch chunks</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>pound</unit></amt>
          <item>Tripe and tendons</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
          <item>Flank steak</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
          <item>Beef brisket</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>GARNISHES</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Green onions; sliced thinly on the bias</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Chiffonade of cilantro</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>medium</unit></amt>
          <item>Onions; julienned</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Fish sauce; (nuoc mam)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>pound</unit></amt>
          <item>1/4-inch wide dried rice noodles; soaked in warm water for 30 minutes and drained</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>pound</unit></amt>
          <item>Beef sirloin; sliced paper-thin</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Fresh ground black pepper</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Fresh bean sprouts</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Fresh jalapenos pepper; julienned</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Limes; cut into wedges</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>bunch</unit></amt>
          <item>Chinese basil; chiffonade</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>6</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Pairs chopsticks; (up to 8)</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  EMERIL LIVE SHOW #EMIA33
  
  Place the beef bones and oxtails in a large stockpot, cover with water.
  Bring the liquid up to a boil and cook for 10 minutes. Remove from the heat
  and drain. Rinse the pot and bones. Return the bones to the pot and cover
  with 6 quarts of water. Bring the liquid up to a boil and skim often to
  remove the foam. When the foam stops rising to the surface, add 3 quarts of
  water and return to a boil. Char the onions, shallots, and ginger, directly
  over a gas burner or under the broiler, about 5 to 6 minutes. Tie the
  charred vegetables, star anise, garlic cloves, and cinnamon stick in a
  damped cheesecloth. Add the spice bag and parsnips to the simmering broth.
  Season the broth with salt and pepper. Simmer the liquid for 1 hour. Add
  the tripe and tendons to the broth and simmer uncovered for 5 hours. Two
  hours after adding the tripe, add the flank steak and brisket.
  
  GARNISHES FOR ASIAN FONDUE: In a small bowl, combine the green onions,
  cilantro and onions together. Season the vegetables with salt and pepper.
  When the broth is ready, remove and discard the oxtails and bones. Reserve
  the tripe, flank steak, and brisket. Strain the broth into a clean pot
  through a strainer with a double layer of dampened cheesecloth. Add the
  fish sauce to the broth. Bring to a boil and reduce to a simmer. Slice the
  tripe, flank steak, and brisket, into small pieces. In a pot of boiling
  water, drop in the drained noodles and remove immediately and drain. Mound
  the noodles in the center of an oversized bowl. Bring the broth to a
  rolling boil and ladle the broth over the noodles Arrange the remaining
  ingredients on small plates around the bowl of broth.
  
  Yield: 8 to 10 servings
  
  Posted to recipelu-digest by molony &lt;molony@scsn.net&gt; on Mar 13, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
