<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Assorted Individual Danish Pt 1</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Breakfasts</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Recipe Danish dough</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Egg wash</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Remonce; cinnamon and plain Fillings---</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Jam; (raspberry and apricot)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Homemade chunky apple or pear sauce or cranberry conserve</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>CHEESE FILLING</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>12</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Cream cheese; softened</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Yolk; slightly beaten</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Lekvar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Chopped chocolate mixed with sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Lemon curd; (puff tart Cinnamon Sugar---</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Cinnamon</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Recipe; with 2/3 cup sugar instead of 1/2)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Pastry cream Toppings---</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Toasted sliced almonds Streusel---</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Melted butter; approximately Apricot Glaze---</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Apricot jam</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Water; approximately Sugar Icing---</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Confectioner's sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>About 1 tablespoon milk Remonce---</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Butter; softened</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Cinnamon; optional (up to 1/2)</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  *Egg wash (one egg, lightly beaten with 2 teaspoons milk) Preheat oven to
      350    degrees
  
  On a lightly floured surface, roll the dough out to a rectangle measuring a
  little larger than 20 x 10 inches when relaxed. Brush off any excess flour.
  Square off the edges with a pizza cutter. Cut the rectangle into 10 5-inch
  squares. Spread each with remonce and/or the filling. Form the pastries.
  Place on a sheet tray lined with parchment paper. Proof, in a warm
  draft-free place, covered with a dish towel, until they are a little puffy
  and a finger pressed lightly into the dough leaves a slight indentation.
  Brush lightly with egg wash and sprinkle with sugar or topping. Bake about
  20 minutes or until golden brown. Cool on a rack. While still warm, brush
  lightly with warm apricot glaze or drizzle with icing.
  
  Yield: 10 pastries
  
  Pinwheels: Spread with remonce. Sprinkle on some extra cinnamon sugar.
  Brush the of the square with egg wash. Cut a slit from each corner almost
  into the center, stopping just short of the center. Fold every other tip
  into the center, overlapping them, and press firmly. Place on a baking
  sheet lined with parchment paper. Proof, covered, about 1/2 hour. Press the
  center down with your finger where the tips overlap and fill with 1/2
  rounded teaspoon jam or filling.
  
  Eggwash, sprinkle with coarse sugar, and bake about 20 minutes, or until
  nicely colored.
  
  Envelopes: Spread square with remonce. Sprinkle with finely chopped
  chocolate mixed with sugar. Turn the square so that a point is at the top.
  Put and elongated mound of about 2 tablespoons of cheese filling from top
  to bottom. Egg wash the side corners. Fold one corner over the filling and
  press firmly. Fold the other end over the top and press very firmly to
  seal. Place on lined baking sheet and proof, covered, about 1/2 hour. Brush
  with egg wash and sprinkle with sugar and chopped chocolate. Bake about 20
  minutes, or until nicely browned. (Or spread with lemon curd and then
  cheese filling and garnish before baking with toasted sliced almonds.)
  
  Cheese pockets: Spread the square with remonce. Place a rounded tablespoon
  of cheese filling in the middle of the square. Brush the corners with egg
  wash. Fold two opposite sides up and press firmly, as in the envelopes
  above. Bring the bottom corner up and press firmly over the fold. Lastly,
  bring the top corner up and across the fold and pinch it to seal. Proof,
  covered, as above. Egg wash and sprinkle the top with streusel. Bake about
  25 minutes, until nicely browned.
  
  Turnovers: Spread with remonce. Place a big dollop of chunky homemade
  applesauce or pear sauce on one side of the square. Egg wash the edges and
  fold over into a triangle. Press around the edge with a fork to seal.
  Proof, etc. Before baking, egg wash and sprinkle with coarse or pearl
  sugar.
  
  Streusel: Whisk together the flour and sugar. Drizzle in the melted butter
  as you mix with your fingertips or a rubber spatula.
  continued in part 2
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
