<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Athenian Walnut Cake</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Cake</cat></categories>
      <yield>12</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Butter</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>5</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Ground cinnamon</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Eggs</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>8</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Walnuts; chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>8</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Sifted flour</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>SYRUP</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>6</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>10</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>(fl) water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>(fl) brandy</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  From: Doreen Randal &lt;ynnuf@yetti.wanganui.gen.nz&gt;
  
  Date: Mon, 16 Oct 1995 13:21:59 GMT
  This maybe served with coffee or as a dessert.
  
  Pre-heat the oven to 350 F.  Grease a med-sized loaf or cake tin with a
  little butter and dust with flour.
  
  In a med-sized mixing bowl, beat the butter and sugar together with a
  wooden spoon until they are well cream. Separate the yolks from the whites
  aside. Add the yolks, one at a time, to the creamed butter and sugar and
  mix thoroughly.
  
  Beat the egg whites until they are stiff.  Add half the egg whites and the
  cinnamon to the creamed mixture and mix well.  Set aside 2 Tbs of the
  crushed walnuts. Mix the rest off the walnuts and flour together and
  gradually to the creamed mixture, mixing thoroughly. Fold in the remaining
  egg whites.  Put the mixture in the loaf or cake tin and sprinkle the top
  with the remaining 2 Tbs of crushed walnuts. Bake for 1 1/4 hrs. or until
  the cake is cooked when a skewer comes out dry when tested. If skewer is
  clean the cake is done.
  
  Remove the cake from the tin and place it upside down in a deep dish.  With
  a skewer, pierce the bottom of the cake all over.  Pour the hot syrup
  slowly over the cake while it is still hot.
  
  TO MAKE THE SYRUP, dissolve the sugar in the water in a small saucepan over
  a low heat and boil rapidly until the syrup thickens.  Remove from the heat
  and mix in the brandy.  Set the cake aside to cool and to absorb the syrup.
  Turn tne cake right side up and serve cold.
  
  REC.FOOD.RECIPES ARCHIVES
  
  /CAKES
  
  From rec.food.cooking archives.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
