<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Auge Valley Chicken Stew</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>France</cat>
        <cat>Poultry</cat>
        <cat>Soups/stews</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Chicken, quartered</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Carrots, peeled and diced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Shallot, sliced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Pippin apples**</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>White mushrooms, washed and minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Onions - one sliced, one studded with cloves</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Dry white wine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Clove garlic</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Thyme leaves</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Bay leaves</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Salt and fresh ground black pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Creme fraiche or whipping cream**</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Shot glass (1 Tablespoon) Calvados**</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg yolks</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  **For the apples I used Granny Smith's. For the creme fraiche or whipping
  cream, I used the whipping cream. For the Calvados - which would have been
  too expensive to use, even if I had located it over here, I substituted an
  apple flavored liqueur and just added a little brandy. (Calvados is a dry
  apple brandy from Calvados in Northern France - very good, but I couldn't
  find it locally) In a cast iron casserole, lightly brown the chicken in
  half the butter and 2 Tablespoons oil. When all the pieces are nice and
  golden. add the carrots, shallots and the sliced onion and cook for a few
  minutes. Pour the white wine and 1 cup of water over the chicken, then add
  the clove studded onion and the garlic. Add some thyme leaves and bay
  leaves and season with salt and pepper. Cover and simmer over low heat for
  40 minutes. (While this was cooking the 40 minutes, I peeled and minced the
  mushrooms - I know everyone tells me there is no need to peel the
  mushrooms, but I always do &lt;g&gt;) Remove the chicken from the heat, arrange
  the pieces of chicken in an ovenproof serving dish and keep warm. Pass the
  cooking liquid through a sieve. Set the vegetables aside and keep warm.
  Meanwhile melt the remaining butter in a skillet with the oil, add the
  apples and cook until just lightly brown on all sides. Remove the apples
  from the skillet and arrange them around the chicken. Keep the dish warm in
  the oven. Saute the mushrooms until they have lost all their juices. Set
  aside to add to the sauce. To make the sauce: Pour the strained cooking
  liquid into a saucepan and set over medium heat. With a whisk, beat in the
  cream, the calvados and the egg yolks in that order. Simmer in a double
  boiler until it has thickened to a light cream. Stir in the mushrooms and
  the vegetables, discarding the clove-studded onion. Adjust seasoning.
  Remove the dish from the oven, spoon some of the sauce over the chicken and
  pour the remaining sauce into a sauceboat and serve. From The Cookie Lady's
  Files
  
  Submitted By   O'LEARY'S
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/mmdja006.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
