<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Aunt Sadie's Brisket of Beef</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Main dish</cat>
        <cat>Beef</cat>
        <cat>Jewish</cat>
        <cat>Holiday</cat></categories>
      <yield>8</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Large onions*</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>8</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Whole allspice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Salt and pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Garlic powder</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Hungarian paprika</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  5,6     lb brisket; 1st cut *Sliced paper thin (3 is not a typo) &gt;&gt;&gt; The
  following is my favorite brisket recipe and it really does come from my
  Aunt Sadie's kitchen: Remove any excess fat from brisket, but leave a
  little on top. Place one half of the onions on bottom of pan. Season the
  onions with a little salt, pepper, garlic powder and lots of Hungarian
  paprika. Place brisket on top of onions, then other half of onions and
  allspice on top of the brisket. Cover and roast in a 300 degree F. oven for
        3    hours.
   Test your brisket and when it is fork tender, take it out. Let it cool and
  then slice it very thin.  Strain juice and either thicken it with a little
  cornstarch or serve it au jus. You will have a very dark brown juice. NOTE:
  Best when made one day in advance.  Aunt Sadie almost always served this
  with savory noodle kugel. I also serve it with roasted, boiled or mashed
  potatoes.  Use a good roasting pan with a lit that fits well or covered
  with heavy duty aluminum foil.
   Spray pan and inside of lid with Pam.&gt;&gt; I serve this at Passover sans
  cornstarch and serve it any time I wish to serve something festive, special
  and easy. Enjoy, FROM: ANN PUCKETT (HGPS48A)
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
