<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Aunt Elsie's Cream Cheese Dough Cookies</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Cookies</cat></categories>
      <yield>12</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter; Softened</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Cream cheese</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>All Purpose Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Assorted Canned Fruit Fillings; Such As Solo Brand Pastry Fillings</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Cream butter and cream cheese together. Gradually blend in flour until a
  slighty soft dough forms. Wrap dough in plastix wrap, and refrigerate about
  2 hours, or until firm. On a floured board, roll dough out to a thickness
  of about 1/3 inch.Using 2-3 inch round cookie cutter, cut out several
  circles. Either using a doughnut cutter the same diameter, or a canape
  cutter or bottle cap, cut out center of half the circles.
  
  On an ungreased cookie sheet, place the solid circles, being careful to
  leave adequate space between cookies. (These do not spread much but they do
  puff up in height.) Using circles tha thave the centers cut out, place on
  top of solid circles. Using a small spoon, fill each cookie with the fruit
  filling of your choice.Filkl just up to top of dough.
  
  Bake at 375 degrees, about 12-15 minutes, or until puffed up and beginning
  to turn golden. Let cool on cookie sheeys for about three minutes and then
  transfer to rack to complete cooling.
  
  Seaqsonal hoilday shape cutters may be used as well. Bottle caps or
  matching canape cutters can be used to cut out the centers.
  
  These do not store doe more than a couple of days at room temperature.
  Refrigerate in the unlikely event that there are a lot of leftovers.
  
  Serving Ideas : Thse look very attrractive when arramged on a platter.
  
  NOTES : For those who are careful about sugar consumption - the cookies can
  be filled with all fruit spreads as well as canned fillings. Actually,
  almost any thick preserves will do. Just don't use any jelly or any spread
  that is too thin, as they melt and run all over in the oven. Do not use pie
  fillngs as these are also too thin. Recipe may be doubled or more.
  Recipe by: Elsie Goldberg
  
  Posted to KitMailbox Digest  by Supersew &lt;Supersew@aol.com&gt; on Dec 22, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
