<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Autumn Leaves</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Cookies</cat>
        <cat>Holiday</cat></categories>
      <yield>40</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter; (no substitutes)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Packed brown sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Baking powder</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Pure maple syrup or maple-flavor syrup</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Vanilla</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>All-purpose flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Orange paste food coloring</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Red paste food coloring</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  1. BEAT butter in a medium mixing bowl with an electric mixer on medium to
  high speed for 30 seconds. Add brown sugar, baking powder, and salt; beat
  till comhined. Beat in egg, maple syrup, and vanilla. Beat in as much of
  the flour as you can with the mixer. Stir in any remaining flour with a
  wooden spoon.
  
  2. DlVlDE dough into thirds. Leave one portion plain. Knead orange paste
  food coloring into another portion. Knead red paste food coloring into
  remaining portion. Chill dough for 1 hour or till easy to handle.
  
  3. ROLL about a third of each color dough into I0-inch ropes on a lightly
  floured surface. Twist ropes together; fold in crosswise and flatten
  slightly. Roll 1/8 inch thick (keep remaining dough refrigerated). Cut with
  leaf-shape cookie cutters . Place cutouts 1 inch apart on greased cookie
  sheets. Score veins with a table knife or skewer. Gently gather and reroll
  scraps. Repeat with remaining dough.
  
  4. BAKE in a 375 degree oven 7 to 9 minutes or till edges begin to brown.
  Cool on wire racks.
  
  NOTES : Be sure to use paste food coloring.  Liquid coloring softens the
  dough so it's hard to handle and cutouts lose there shape.
  
  Recipe by: Better Homes Christmas Book 1997
  
  Posted to recipelu-digest Volume 01 Number 506 by Marie Smith
  &lt;craftee@sprynet.com&gt; on Jan 12, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
