<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Avocado-Cream Sauce for Pasta</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Main course</cat>
        <cat>Pork*</cat>
        <cat>Pasta*</cat>
        <cat>Quick dishe</cat></categories>
      <yield>2</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>8</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Pasta with shape (e.g., penne or spirals)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Lemon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Avocado</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>80g pkg Boursin with herbs</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>deciliters</unit></amt>
        <item>Koffieroom</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>50</qty>
          <unit>grams</unit></amt>
        <item>Achterham</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Bakje tuinkers</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Salt and freshly ground pepper; to taste</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Translations: "achterham" is a nice sliced lunchmeat-type ham. For a
  vegetarian dinner, omit this; or, maybe, replace with mushrooms.
  
  "tuinkers". Hmmm...I really don't know the English name for this, or recall
  seeing anything similar. It's in the cress family, but smaller-leaved than
  watercress. You buy a little box (the bakje) that is filled with a
  sponge-like block. The tuinkers are sprouting from that, maybe one inch
  high. You take you kitchen shears or a knife and cut off what you want.
  Anybody know what this is? They're good sprinkled in a salad. I suppose you
  could use some kind of sprouts, maybe mixed, with radish sprouts included
  for the peppery taste.
  
  Peel the avocado and remove the seed. Cut into chunks and place in food
  processor (or blender).
  
  Wash the lemon. Into the processor, finely grate half the peel, avoiding
  the white part. Add the juice from half the lemon to the processor (other
  half not used).
  
  Add the Boursin and koffieroom to the processor. Whiz till smooth.
  
  Pour into a small saucepan. Warm over low heat from about 10 minutes.
  
  Meanwhile, cut the ham into strips. Cut the tunikers from their bed. Stir
  into sauce. Add S&amp;P to taste.
  
  Serve over a shaped pasta. Penne was good, but maybe try something a bit
  smaller.
  Recipe By     : TIP Magazine
  
  Posted to EAT-L Digest 11 November 96
  
  Date:    Tue, 12 Nov 1996 08:55:39 +0100
  
  From:    Kaye Sykes &lt;Sykes.Kaye@UNIFACE.NL&gt;
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
