<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Avocado-Zucchini Pizza</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Cooking liv</cat>
        <cat>Import</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Cornmeal</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Grated zucchini or crookneck squash</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Serrano chiles; minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>5</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Garlic cloves; minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh lime juice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Kosher salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Black pepper in a mill</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>12 inch pizza shell; (recipe above)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Extra virgin olive oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>(8 ounces) grated or shredded cheese; such as monterey jack, st george, fontina or mozzarella</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Minced italian parsley or cilantro</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Ripe avocado</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Crushed red pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Lime; cut into wedges</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Preheat the oven to 475 degrees. Place a baking stone in the oven or
  sprinkle a baking sheet or pizza pan with cornmeal.
  
  Toss together the zucchini, chiles, garlic, and lime juice in a small bowl.
  Taste, and season with salt and pepper. Dust a work surface with cornmeal,
  and place the pizza shell on it. Drizzle the olive oil over the shell, then
  spread the zucchini mixture on top. Top with the cheese, spreading it
  evenly over the zucchini. Scatter the parsley or cilantro over the cheese.
  
  If you are using a baking stone, sprinkle it with cornmeal. Transfer the
  pizza to the baking sheet, pizza pan, or baking stone. Bake the pizza until
  the crust is lightly golden and the cheese bubbly, 15 to
       20    minutes.
  
  Meanwhile, cut the avocado in half, pit and peel it, and cut it lengthwise
  into thin slices.
  
  Remove the pizza from the oven, and let it rest for 5 minutes. Cut it into
  8 slices, and top each one with avocado slices. Sprinkle salt, pepper and
  crushed red pepper over the pizza, and serve immediately, with lime wedges
  alongside.
  
  Yield: 4 servings
  
  Notes: Recipe courtesy of Michele Jordan, California Home Cooking
  
  Recipe by: Cooking Live Show #CL9069
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest by "Angele and Jon Freeman"
  &lt;jfreeman@comteck.com&gt; on Apr 4, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
