<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Avocado Veloute Soup</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Soups</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>6</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Sweet butter</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Finely minced scallions green part only</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Garlic cloves, mashed</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/2</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Ripe avocados</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Lemon, juice of</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>6</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Hot chicken stock</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Freshly ground white pepper</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Egg yolks</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Heavy cream</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Few drops Tabasco</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>GARNISH</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Finely minced fresh chives</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Heavy cream, whipped and slightly salted</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  In a small heavy saucepan melt 2 T butter.  Add the scallions and garlic
  and cook, covered, over low heat for 5 minutes or until the scallions are
  very soft but not browned. Remove them to the top part of a blender. Add
  the coarsely mashed pulp of 1 large avocado. Sprinkle with 1/2 of the lemon
  juice and blend the mixture at high spped until it becomes a smooth puree.
  Set aside. In a large saucepan melt the remaining butter. Add the flour and
  cook the mixture, stirring constantly, for 2 minutes without browning. Add
  the hot chicken stock and whisk until the soup becomes slightly thick and
  very smooth.  Season the soup with salt and pepper and let it simmer,
  partially covered, for 30 to 40 minutes. In a mixing bowl combine the egg
  yolks, Tabasco and cream and blend them well. Fold the avocado puree into
  the cream and yolk mixture. Pour the mixture into the soup and, stirring
  constantly, heat the soup through without letting it come to a boil.
  Correct the seasoning and keep the soup warm. Peel the remaining 1/2
  avocado and cut it into tiny cubes. Sprinkle with remaining lemon juice and
  add them to the soup just before serving. Serve the soup garnished with
  chives and a spoonful of whipped cream. NOTE: You may serve the soup cold
  and vary it by substituting Creme Fraiche for the whipped cream and fresh
  chervil for the chives.
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
