<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baba Ganoush</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Crowd</cat>
        <cat>Kitpath</cat>
        <cat>Moosewood</cat>
        <cat>Vegetarian</cat></categories>
      <yield>24</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>9 1/2</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Eggplants</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh lemon juice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Tahini</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>12</qty>
          <unit>medium</unit></amt>
        <item>Garlic cloves; minced, or more to taste</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh parsley; finely chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt to serve---</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Leaf lettuce</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>12</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Pita bread rounds; lightly toasted and halved</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Feta cheese; crumbled (3 qts)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  1. Pierce the skins of the eggplants several times and place them on a
  baking sheet. Bake at 400F for 40 minutes to 1 hour, or until the outsides
  crinkle and the insides become very soft.
  
  2. When the eggplants are cool enough to handle, scoop out the insides.
  
  3. Using a food processor puree the pulp with the lemon juice, tahini,
  garlic, parsley, and salt until smooth. Cool to room temperature.
  
  4. Line a warmed pita pocket with leaf lettuce, spoon in the baby and serve
  as is, or, if desired, top with a sprinkling of feta cheese.
  
  Meal Planning: *preparation Time: 15 minutes; Baking Time: 40 minutes.
  Serve with soup or salad. *Smoky eggplant flavor and creamy texture of
  tahini with lemon also makes a good dip with crudites. Prepare as a side
  dish for a Middle Eastern Combo Plate with Hummus (79) or White Bean Dip
  (87) and Carrot Salad (p321) *For a nondairy alternative, top with chopped
  fresh tomatoes, chopped black olives, and alfalfa sprouts. Per 6-oz serving
  with pita: 247 cals, 11.3 g fat, 496 mg sodium.
  
  Recipe From: Moosewood Restaurant Cooks for a Crowd: Recipes with a
  Vegetarian Emphasis for 24 or More, by The Moosewood Collective, John Wiley
  &amp; Sons, (1996). | 07/13/97 Contact kitPATh phannema@wizard.ucr.edu
  
  Recipe by: Moosewood for a Crowd
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
