<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Babka (Yeast Cake)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Bread</cat></categories>
      <yield>20</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>TOPPING</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Margarine</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>BREAD</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Yeast cakes</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Warm water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
          <item>Margarine</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>White raisins</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>6</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour (stir before measuring)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Milk</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>9</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Egg yolks</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>COTTAGE CHEESE FILLING FOR</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>BABKA</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Egg; slightly beaten</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Cottage cheese</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Granulated sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Vanilla</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Grated lemon rind</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  From: dianew@sdsc.edu (Diane M. Wojewocki)
  
  Date: Thu, 24 Feb 94 11:11:26 PST
  This recipe came from a small book simply called "Polish Cook Book" written
  by the children of Anna Dziengiel Pieklo and dedicated to her.  I have made
  it and it is absolutely delicious. Having grown up in a VERY Polish family,
  this is the closest recipe I've found to the Babka I grew up on!
  
  TOPPING:  Melt 2 tbs. margarine in a pan.  Remove from heat and add 2 tbs.
  sugar and 1/4 cup flour.  Stir with a spoon to combine, then work with your
  fingers until you achieve a crumb topping.  Set aside.
  
  Break up yeast in a bowl and mix in 1 tbs. sugar.  Combine well until it
  liquefies.  Stir in water.  Set aside.  Combine margarine with milk and
  heat to scald. Cool to lukewarm.
  
  Use a large bowl to beat egg yolks with sugar and then add the milk
  mixture. Stir in the salt, raisins and yeast. Add the flour all at once.
  Beat with a wooden spoon until smooth. Add additional 1 1/4 to 1 1/2 cups
  of flour and mix it in well with your hand. Knead on a lightly floured
  surface about 10 minutes.
  
  Round up the dough in a greased bowl, turn greased side up.  Cover with
  damp towel and let rise in a warm area approximately 2 1/2 hrs. (bulk will
  double.) Punch down and let rise 1 1/2 hrs. or until double. Grease 10"
  tube pan. Punch down dough and place it in tube pan, cover, and let rise
  for an hour or until double. Brush top with 1 egg yolk beaten with 2 tsp.
  water.
  
  Distribute crumb topping lightly and bake at 300 degrees for 1 1/2 hrs.
  Cool in pan 10 minutes.
  
  COTTAGE CHEESE FILLING FOR BABKA: Combine all ingredients.  When Babka
  dough has been punched down after the second rising, spread or roll dough
  into rectangle. Spoon filling along center of dough. Fold dough over
  filling making ends meet. Place in pan and bake according to Babka
  directions. Filling should be at room temperature. Fills one Babka.
  
  REC.FOOD.RECIPES
  
  From rec.food.cooking archives.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
