<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Babsie's Tarts</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>*</cat>
        <cat>The grillin</cat>
        <cat>Davidson</cat>
        <cat>Desserts</cat></categories>
      <yield>24</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Unsalted butter; softened</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg yolks</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Vanilla</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Finely grated lemon zest; * see note</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground cinnamon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground cloves</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Baking powder</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Slivered almonds; blanced and ground*</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Seedless red raspberry jam</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  *Note--Citrus zest and nuts are easily ground in a clean coffe grinder.
  
  Beat butter until creamy. Add sugar and beat until throughly incorporated.
  
  Beat egg yolk slightly with vanilla and lemon zest. Add to creamed mixture,
  stirring throughly. Sift dry ingredients together, then stir into creamed
  mixture. Stir in almonds.
  
  Preheat oven to 350 degrees. Spray 2 nonstick cupcake pans. Using a 2
  tablespoon scoop, place one scoop of batter into each cupcake pan. Pat the
  batter gently to cover bottom of each cup. Do not indent the dough or the
  jam will leak through. Place 2 teaspoons of jam in the centre of each
  cupcake.
  
  Bake for about 15 mins. until the batter around the jam has risen and
  turned golden. After the pans have been removed from the oven, use a sharp
  knife to loosen the edges of each tart. Allow tarts to cool in the pan
  until cool to the touch, at least 1 hour. Using a kichen knife, gently
  lever the tarts out on to cookie recks and allow to cool completely. You
  may serve them plain or sprinkle with powdered sugar and a scoop of
  icecream.
  
  Source The Grilling Season by Diane Mott Davidson Formatted for Mastercook
  by Carol Floyd--c.floyd@arnprior.com
  
  Recipe by: Diane Mott Davidson, The Grilling Season
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest by Carol &amp; Bob Floyd &lt;c.floyd@arnprior.com&gt; on
  Mar 11, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
