<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Bagels</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Breads</cat></categories>
      <yield>12</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>packages</unit></amt>
        <item>Active dry yeast</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Warm water -- 110-115 F</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  In mixer bowl combine 1 1/2 cups flour and the yeast. Combine warm water, 3
  Tbls. sugar and the salt. Pour over flour mixture. Beat at low speed for 30
  seconds, scraping sides of bowl constantly. Beat 3 minutes on high speed.
  
  Stir in as much of the remaining flour as you can mix in with a spoon. Turn
  out onto lightly floured surface. Knead in enough remaining flour to make a
  moderately stiff dough. Continue kneading until smooth and elastic, 6 - 8
  minutes. Cover; let dough rest 10-15 minutes.
  
  Cut into 12 portions; shape into smooth balls. Punch a hole in the center
  of each with a floured finger. Pull gently to enlarge hole to 1 1/2 to 2
  inches. Place on a greased baking sheet. Cover; let rise 20 minutes. Broil
  5 inches from heat for 1 1/2 - 2 minutes on each side. Tops should not
  brown.
  
  Heat 1 gallon water and 1 tablespoon sugar to boiling; reduce heat. Cook
  bagels, 4 or 5 at a time, for 7 minutes, turning once. Drain. Place on
  greased baking sheet. Bake in 375 degree oven 25 - 30 minutes.
  
  Posted by "R. S. Koss" &lt;rskoss@bronze.coil.com&gt; to the Fatfree Digest
  [Volume 14 Issue 6] Jan. 6, 1995.
  
  Individual recipes copyrighted by originator. FATFREE Recipe collections
  copyrighted by Michelle Dick 1995. Formatted by Sue Smith,
  SueSmith9@aol.com using MMCONV. Archived through kindness of Karen
  Mintzias, km@salata.com.
  
  1.80รก
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
