<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Bagels</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Breads</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>8</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Water; 80 F</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Bread Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter Or Margarine; Cut In 6 Pieces</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Active Dry Yeast Or 1 1/2 T Fast Rise</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>quarts</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Poppy or sesame seeds for garnish</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  1. Add water to bread pan.
  
  2. Add bread flour, 2 tablespoons sugar and salt to pan. Tap pan to settle
  dry ingredients, then level dry ingredients, pushing some of the flour
  mixture into the corners. Place pieces of butter around outer edges of pan
  on top of dry ingredients.
  
  3. Make a slight well in center of dry ingredients and add the yeast.
  
  4. Place bread pan into oven chamber, twist to lock pan in place and close
  cover. Program Break Select for DOUGH, Press START-STOP button to turn
  bread maker on. Press LOCK button to lock program into control. When dough
  is done, audible alert will sound and bread maker will turn off
  automatically. Remove pan from bread maker, then remove dough and place
  into a lightly greased bowl, cover and refrigerate for 20 minutes.
  
  5. Remove dough from refrigerator and place on lightly floured surface.
  Roll out into a rectangle, about 1/2 inch thick. For bagels, divide dough
  into 8 equal pieces: for bagelettes, divide dough into 16 equal pieces.
  
  6. Form each piece of dough into a ball. punch hole in center with finger,
  then stretch dough until center hole is 1 or 2 inches in diameter,
  depending on size bagel being made. Place formed bagels on greased cookie
  sheet about 2 inchs apart. Brush lightly with cold water, cover and let
  rise in warm draft-free place for 30 - 40 minutes or until almost double in
  size.
  
  7. Bring 3 quarts water to boil in 5 quart dutch oven. Add sugar and stir
  to dissolve. Reduce heat to simmer and carefully add 2 - 3 bagels or 4 - 5
  bagelettes to hot water. Simmer for 3-4 minutes on each side. Remove with
  slotted spoon, drain, then place on greased baking sheet, about 1 inch
  apart. Sprinkle with poppy seeds or sesame seeds if desired, or leave
  plain. Bake in preheated 450 degree oven for 12-15 minutes. Remove, turn
  bagels over and bake on second side for 12-15 minutes or until golden
  brown. Cool slightly before serving.
  
  NOTES : I brown onions and garlic, drain good and put on bagels before
  cooking, great.
  Recipe by: Westbent Auto Dough Break and Dough Maker
  
  Posted to TNT - Prodigy's Recipe Exchange Newsletter  by
  ksmith3001@juno.com (Katherine L Smith) on Sep 11, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
