<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Bagels</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Breads</cat></categories>
      <yield>12</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>package</unit></amt>
        <item>Active dry yeast</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Warm water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>All-purpose or bread flour (I prefer the high gluten)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Milk</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg beaten with a little water, (for glaze)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Coarse salt, (optional),</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Poppy or sesame seeds (opt.)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  1. Sprinkle the yeast over the warm water, stir, and let dissolve. 2. Put
  the salt, flour, and 4 tsp of the sugar in food processor bowl with dough
  blade. Pulse several times to mix well and aerate. 3. Combine yeast mixture
  and milk in a measuring cup. With processor motor running, piur through
  feed tube. Knead until mixture balls together and is no longer sticky,
  about 60 seconds. Lightly flour alarge plastic bag, place the dough in it,
  squeeze out the air, and close the end of the bag with a twist tie. Let the
  dough rise until doubled, about 45 minutes. Punch it down. (At this point
  the dough can be refrigerated for up to 4 days. Bring it to room
  temperature before proceeding.) 4. Let the dough rest for ten minutes. Pull
  of pieces of dough to form 12 two inch balls. Poke a finger through the
  ball, making a hole the size of a golf ball. With fingers, shape the bagel
  evenly. Put the bagels on a cookie sheet, cover with oiled plastic wrap,
  and let them rise until puffy, about 30 minutes. Preheat oven to 400
  degrees F. 5. Bring 4 qts. water to boil in a wide pot. Add the remaining
  two teaspoons sugar. Poach the bagels, 3 or 4 at a time, for 30 seconds.
  Turn them and poach for 30 seconds more. Remove with slotted spoon, let
  drip briefly on towel and the place 1 inch apart on baking sheets. Brush
  each bagel with a little of the egg glaze. (At this point sprinkle on any
  of the optional salt or seeds.) Bake until golden brown, about 15 minutes.
  Cool on racks.
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
