<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Bagels</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Warm water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>packages</unit></amt>
        <item>(scant 1-1/2 t) active dry yeast (see note)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Malt syrup or sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Vegetable oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Bread flour; (see note) (up to 8)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Flour; for dusting work top</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Oil; for greasing bowl and baking sheets</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Malt syrup or sugar to add to water when boiling; (see note)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  (Source: Secrets of a Jewish Baker, by George Greenstein)
  
  In a large bowl sprinkle the yeast over the warm water to soften; stir to
  dissolve. Add the 2 tablespoons malt syrup, oil, 6 cups flour and salt. Mix
  thoroughly until the dough forms up and comes away fro the sides of the
  bowl.
  
  Turn out the dough onto a floured work surface and knead, adding small
  amounts of flour as necessary. Bagel dough should be stiff. Work in as much
  extra flour as you can comfortably knead. When using bread flour the dough
  will soften slightly as the gluten develops. Knead until smooth and elastic
  (12 to 15 minutes).
  Rising: Roll the dough into a ball, place it in a large oiled bowl, and
  turn to coat. Cover and let fully rise until an impression made with your
  finger remains and does not sink into the dough (about 1 hour). Punch down,
  cut into thirds, and roll each piece between your palms into a rope.
  
  Shaping: Cut each rope into 4 equal pieces and shape into balls. Roll the
  first ball into a rope 2 inches more than the width of your hand. Flip the
  rope around your fingers to form a ring, with the ends overlapping about
  1/2 inch. Seal the ends by rolling with your palms on a work top. If the
  dough slides and resists rolling, dab on a drop of water with your fingers.
  
  Evenly space the bagels on 2 nonstick baking pans or very lightly oiled
  baking sheets. I apply a thin film with my fingers. Cover and let stand
  until puffy (about 20 minutes).
  
  Boiling: Bagles are boiled before they are baked. While they are proofing,
  fill a 4-quart saucepan two-thirds full with cold water; add the 1
  tablespoon malt syrup and bring to a boil. Have ready pans or dishes
  contianing poppy seeds, sesame seeds, coarse salt, or other toppings (see
  note).
  
  When ready to cook the bagels, drop two or three at a time into the boiling
  water and wait until they rise to the top. Cook for a total of 1 minute,
  turning once. If they have been proofed too long, they will float instead
  of sinking but you can continue without too much difference.
  
  Carefully lift out each bagel with a slotted spoon or skimmer. Drain
  momentarily, then turn them over into the dish of prepared seeds. You may
  prefer to leave some plain. Evenly space the bagels on 2 baking sheets,
  topping side up.
  
  Baking: Bake with steam (see note) in a preheated 500F oven until well
  browned (15 to 20 minutes). Turn them over when the tops begin to brown.
  Continue baking until done.
  
  Makes 1 dozen large bagels.
  
  Note: (from author) Malt syrup adds gloss and a subtle flavor to the
  finished bagel. If you can find malt syrup in your supermarket or natural
  foods store, use it. The toppings for bagels are virtually unlimited. Try
  poppy seeds, sesame seeds, coarse salt, poppy seeds and coarse salt
  combined, minced onion flakes, or chopped or granulated garlic.
  
  To bake with steam: Place an empty roasting pan or other heavy pan on the
  floor of the oven 5 to 10 minutes before baking, so it gets hot. When ready
  to bake, place the bread/bagels in the oven and carefully toss six to eight
  ice cubes into the hot pan, or pour in 1 cup boiling water and immediately
  close the oven door.
  
  Note: (from Peggy M.) I use high-gluten flour instead of the bread flour
  for this recipe. It can be purchased through several flour companies - I
  get it from King Arthur's Baking Catalog.
  
  I also use 1 TABLESPOON of yeast, rather than the amount he calls for. It
  is the amount called for in another bagel recipe I used to make, and I've
  found it works better in this one, as well.
  
  Also, I use malt powder and corn syrup in place of the malt syrup. Both
  malt powder and malt syrup are available through catalogs, again I order it
  through King Arthur's Baking Catalog.
  
  Posted to TNT Recipes Digest, Vol 01, Nr 923 by "Peggy L. Makolondra"
  &lt;pmakolon@mail.wiscnet.net&gt; on Jan 09, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
