<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baguettes</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Yeast; (more if you want it to rise faster but the slow rising times are what makes this taste authentic)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2 1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flour; (I use King Arthur's Unbleached Bread Flour)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Bran or oats; (I use oats)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  This is better than I can buy in stores. I am told that if you spritz with
  water while loaves are rising and early in the cooking process that it gets
  a heavier crust but that's too much work for me. I think it is one I wrote
  down from Frugal Gormet.
  
  I mix the water, yeast, salt, oats and some of the flour in a mixing bowl.
  Slowly adding more flour until it cleans the bowl and most of the flour is
  worked in. (I have bread thingys, without them you dump it out earlier and
  keep working in flour)
  
  When it is smooth, oil the bottom of a big bowl, put the dough in and turn
  so that the oiled surface is on top. Cover with cling wrap or a damp cloth.
  Let rise for 5 or 6 hours.
  
  Form loaves. (Four long, thin ones or 2 long fat ones) I use the supports
  with holes in them for french loaves. Let them rise again. (don't forget to
  spritz)
  
  Cook at a high heat for 15-20 minutes, depending on loaf size. (don't
  forget to spritz)
  
  I have also used this dough for breadsticks which were a lot of work but
  impressed the heck out of people.
  
  Oh yes, don't cover these loaves with plastic or anything. They dry from
  the outside in. By day 3 or 4 you need to toast them. Brush with garlic and
  olive oil and enjoy!
  
  Posted to FOODWINE Digest  by Esther Czekalski
  &lt;esther_czekalski@BAYNETWORKS.COM&gt; on Apr 6, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
