<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baileys Banana Cream Torte</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>NORMA WRENN</title></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>BANANA CAKE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>14</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Pkg carrot cake mix</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Eggs</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Vegetable oil</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Hot tap water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Bananas; mashed</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Baileys mousse</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Whipping cream</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Baileys original irish cream</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Envelopes unflavored gelatine</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>6</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Egg white; room temperature</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Super fine sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Bananas; sliced</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Crushed toasted almonds to taste; (up to 2)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Chocolate truffle cups to fill with bailey's original irish cream; optional</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Banana Cake: Preheat oven to 350~, grease and flour a straight sided 9"
  cake pan. Beat last 4 ingredients well. On low speed or by hand; stir in
  carrot cake mix until nearly smooth. Don't over stir. Pour into prepared
  pan and bake for 20-30 minutes or until cake springs back when lightly
  touched in the center. Cool in pan for 15 minutes. Remove from pan. Cool
  completely on wire rack. Slice horizontally into 3 layers. Served with
  Baileys Mousse: Soften gelatine in Baileys Original Irish Cream for 5
  minutes. Then dissolve over very low heat, or in microwave for 1 minute,
  stirring every 20 seconds. Whip cream until peaks form, not too stiff. Fold
  Baileys Original Irish Cream mixture into cream. Set aside in refrigerator.
  In a double boiler over (not in) boiling water, using hand held electric
  mixer, beat the egg whites with the sugar on high for seven minutes. Fold
  together with Baileys and whipped cream mixture. Divide into thirds. To
  Assemble: Start with layer of cake, then Baileys mousse, then sliced
  bananas. Do this using all three layers. On sides of cake, press toasted
  almonds. Chill overnight. If desired, decorate each serving with a rosette
  of mousse topped with a chocolate truffle cup filled with Baileys Original
  Irish Cream. By Chef Susan Morrow, Jax Cafe, Minneapolis, Minnesota
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest by "M. Hicks" &lt;nitro_ii@email.msn.com&gt; on Feb
  12, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
