<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baked for Dinner Potatoes (Mf)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Potato-</cat>
        <cat>Sd</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Idaho or russet potatoes; each weighing about 8 ounces</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Olive oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Red bell peppers; seeded and finely julienned</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Mushrooms; stemmed and finely sliced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Pesto; to taste, sun dried tomato or black olive paste</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Salt and pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Yogurt or chunk parmesan cheese, optional</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Preheat oven to 450 degrees. Wash the potatoes, prick them and bake for
  about an hour or until done. (If kids don't like very crunchy exterior,
  scrub the potatoes clean, wrap them in foil and then bake; they will then
  steam rather than bake.)
  
  Meanwhile, heat olive oil and saute peppers and mushrooms until tender.
  Remove from heat and stir in pesto, or other paste to taste and season with
  salt and pepper.
  
  When potatoes are done, split them almost all the way to the bottom and
  squeeze up some of the potato flesh; spoon vegetable topping over and
  around potatoes. If you did not add pesto or other paste, top with yogurt;
  if you added pesto or other paste, top with shaved Parmesan. Yield: 4
  servings
  
  Variations:
  
  Fresh chopped tomatoes, mixed with olive oil and chiffonade of basil 2 cups
  pureed cottage cheese mixed with 1/4 cup chopped sun dried tomatoes or 1
  tablespoon prepared pesto Bean or meat chili Smoked salmon, chives and sour
  cream Twice baked Southwest: scoop out filling from potatoes which are
  baked, mix with cheddar cheese, sour cream, green chilis or jalapenos and
  scallions, refill and reheat for 15 minutes or in microwave if you don't
  mind losing crisp texture of outside skin.
  
  Copyright, 1996, TV FOOD NETWORK, G.P., All Rights Reserved
  
  Busted by Gail Shermeyer &lt;4paws@netrax.net&gt;
  
  Recipe by: COOKING MONDAY TO FRIDAY SHOW #MF 6649
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest V1 #793 by 4paws@netrax.net (Shermeyer-Gail) on
  Sep 19, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
