<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baked Turkey and Giblet Gravy</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Poultry</cat></categories>
      <yield>12</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Turkey (hen or tom)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Pepper</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Pam</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Cheesecloth; turkey size</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
          <item>Melted butter</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>GIBLET GRAVY</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Turkey neck; liver and gizzard</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Broth</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Turkey drippings</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Pepper</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>   Thaw turkey in refrigerator for several days or in a large grocery sack
  for 24 hours. Remove liver, gizzard and neck from insides. Salt and pepper
  the bird, inside and out. Spray roasting pan with Pam and line the bottom
  with a large piece of heavy duty foil. Dip cheesecloth in melted butter and
  wrap around turkey to cover completely. Cook at 300ø to 350ø for
  approximately 25 minutes per pound. Baste turkey often with butter while
  cooking until it is gone, then baste with pan drippings. Turkey is done
  when leg moves easily.
  
   To make gravy, put flour in pie pan. Heat oven to 350ø. Brown flour,
  watching it carefully. Shake and stir the pan often. Cook flour. Wrap in
  waxed paper and store in a jar until ready to use. Boil turkey neck, liver
  and gizzard in water to cover for approximately 15 minutes. Save broth. In
  a food processor with plastic blade or in a bowl, put flour and enough
  turkey drippings to make a paste. Put into a skillet and add drippings and
  broth. Add chopped liver and gizzard if desired. Cook until thick and
  season with salt and pepper.
  
  DEBBY BRANSFORD COATES
  
  (MRS. WAYNE)
  
  From &lt;Traditions: A Taste of the Good Life&gt;, by the Little Rock (AR) Junior
  League.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
