<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baked Stuffed Eggplant</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Cheese</cat>
        <cat>Eggplant</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>small</unit></amt>
        <item>Eggplants; cut lengthwise</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>small</unit></amt>
        <item>Tomatoes; Red Ripe, halve/seed/dice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Mozzarella Cheese; diced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>5</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Fresh Basil Leaves; shredded (5 to 6)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh Parsley; chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Cloves Garlic; finely minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Extra Virgin Olive Oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pinch</unit></amt>
        <item>Dried Red Pepper Flakes</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Preheat oven to 350F.
  
  With a tablespoon, scoop out some of the pulp from the eggplant halves,
  making sure not to break the skin. Place the eggplant halves on a large
  platter and sprinkle generously with slat. Let stand about 20 minutes to
  allow the salt to draw out the eggplant's bitter juices. Pat the eggplant
  dry with paper towels.
  
  Dice the pulp of the eggplant and put it in a bowl with the tomatoes,
  mozzarella, basil, parsley, garlic, and olive oil. Season with salt and
  pepper flakes. Fill the eggplant's cavities with this mixture.
  
  Oil a baking dish lightly, and put the eggplant halves into the dish. Bake
  until they are lightly golden, soft to the touvh, and easily pierced with
  the tip of a thin knife, 15 to 25 minutes, depending on the size of the
  eggplants. Serve hot or at room temperature.
  
  NOTES:
  
  This is from Biba Caggiano's _Trattoria Cooking_ cookbook. It is easy to do
  and can be doubled and frozen for an additional meal later on.
  
  One of Biba's notes is that she will dice any leftover eggplant and toss it
  quickly in a skillet with extra virgin olive oil and freshly diced tomatoes
  and serve it over penne, shells, or rigatoni.
  
  Recipe by: Janet Morrissey &lt;janetm@MAGNUS1.COM&gt;
  
  Posted to recipelu-digest Volume 01 Number 178 by RecipeLu
  &lt;recipelu@geocities.com&gt; on Oct 29, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
