<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baked Party Dip</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Dips</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Round loaf dark bread (about 2 poun</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>bunch</unit></amt>
        <item>Scallions, chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Garlic cloves, finely minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter or margarine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>package</unit></amt>
        <item>(8 ounces) cream cheese, cut into s</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>(16 ounces) sour cream</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>(12 ounces) grated mild or medium c</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>can</unit></amt>
        <item>(14 ounces) artichoke hearts (water</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  From: Mr. Food Cookbook (subtitled: Ooh It's So GOOD!) Posted in FidoNet
  Cooking Echo by Sonya Whitaker-Quandt  1/92
  
  "Your party will be the best one of the year when you serve this special
  dip baked inside a loaf of bread. It will be the centerpiece of the table
  and the centerpiece of the party, too."
  
  drained and cut into quarters Garlic bread for serving
  
  Preheat oven to 350 degrees. Cut a hole about 5 inches in diameter in the
  top of the bread. (If you wish, make a decorative zigzag pattern.) Reserve
  crusty part to make top for loaf. Scoop out most of the soft inside portion
  of the loaf and save for another purpose, such as stuffing or bread crumbs.
  In a skillet, saute' the scallions and garlic in the butter until scallions
  wilt. Do not burn! Place the cream cheese in a medium sized bowl; add the
  scallions, garlic, sour cream, and Cheddar cheese. Mix well. Fold in the
  artichoke hearts. Fill hollowed-out bread with this mixture. Replace top of
  bread and wrap in a double thickness of heavy-duty aluminum foil. Bake for
  about 1-1/2 to 1-3/4 hours. Remove foil and top of bread and serve, using
  thin slices of warm garlic bread as dippers.
  
  Note: The best part of this dish is when the dip is gone and all you have
  left is the breadd, which is soaked in all those delicious ingredients.
  Just break the bread up and pass it around!
  Posted to recipelu-digest Volume 01 Number 325 by P&amp;S Gruenwald
  &lt;sitm@ne.infi.net&gt; on Nov 29, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
