<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Bake and Baste Chicken (Baston Chicken)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Poultry</cat>
        <cat>Copycat</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Canola oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Honey</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Lime juice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Paprika</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Chicken breast halves; washed and patted dr</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Preheat oven to 400 degrees. In a small bowl, combine canola oil, honey,
  lime juice and paprika. Place chicken, skin side up, in a 7x11 inch baking
  dish. Apply mixture to chicken pieces in a single layer. Bake in over for
  35-40 minutes, basting every 8-10 minutes or until well browned and juices
  run clear when you cut into the thickest part of chicken. Remove from oven.
  Cover with foil for 15 minutes. This softens chicken and keeps it hot until
  served. Serves 4.
  
  CREAMED SPINACH (like at Boston Chicken) 10 3/4 can cream of celery soup 1
  tbs. flour 1/4 cup butter or margarine or canola oil 1/2 tsp. garlic salt
  or to taste Salt to taste Pepper to taste 20 oz. frozen chopped spinach,
  cooked according to package directions, well drained OR 2 pounds fresh
  spinach, cleaned, stems removed, chopped, cooked and drained 1 tbs. dry
  onion, chopped, or 1 small onion, peeled, ends removed, diced In a large
  saucepan over medium heat, whisk together celery soup, flour, butter or
  margarine or canola oil, garlic salt, salt and pepper until smooth and
  piping hot. Add cooked and drained spinach, dry chopped onion or diced
  onion. Serve. Serves 4-6 as a side dish. From Gloria Pitzer, The Detroit
  Free Press, March 10, 1993 From: SUZZE TIERNAN Refer#: NONE
  Posted to MM-Recipes Digest V4 #272 by Silkia@aol.com on Oct 17, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
