<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baked Barbecued Pork Buns (Cha Sui Bao)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Chinese</cat>
        <cat>Pork</cat></categories>
      <yield>20</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Stephen Ceideburg</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Grated ginger</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Oyster sauce</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Hoisin sauce</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Dark soy sauce</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Peanut or corn oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Finely chopped onion</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Cantonese barbecue pork, in 1/2-inch dice (about 1-lb.)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Cornstarch mixed with 1 tablespoon water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Sesame oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg yolks</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Chinese Baked Sweet Bread Dough (recipe follows)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>package</unit></amt>
        <item>Active dry yeast (1 tablespoon)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Warm milk (100 to 110)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Vegetable oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>All-purpose flour, + more for dusting and kneading</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Reheat in a 350 degree F. oven for 5 minutes, or microwave at high about 1
  minute.
  
  Prepare bread dough. Cut out twenty 3-inch squares of parchment paper. Mix
  together ginger, oyster sauce, hoisin, dark soy, sugar and water in a bowl.
  
  Heat a wok over medium-high heat. Add oil. When hot, add onion; stir-fry
  until soft. Don't brown. Add pork and stir-fry 30 seconds. Pour in sauce
  mixture, bring to a boil. Stir cornstarch/water into a smooth mixture. Add
  to pork; cook, stirring until thick, about 15 seconds. Add sesame oil.
  Remove to bowl; refrigerate until thoroughly chilled.
  
  Cut dough in half. Form each half into a 12-inch long log; cut into 10
  pieces. Roll each piece into a 4-inch circle. Roll outer inch of each
  circle 1/8-inch thin; leave middle slightly thicker.
  
  If right-handed, place a dough circle in palm of your left hand. Put a big
  tablespoon of pork mixture in the ; middle; put left thumb over the pork.
  With your right hand, bring up edge and make a pleat in it. Rotate circle a
  little and make a second pleat. As you make each pleat, gently pull it up
  and around as if to enclose your thumb. Continue rotating, pleating and
  pinching, then gently twist into a spiral. Pinch to seal. Place bun pleated
  side down on a parchment square. Repeat with remaining dough and filling.
  Put buns 1 1/2 inches apart on a baking sheet. Let rise until doubled in
  size, 30 minutes to 1 hour.
  
  Preheat oven to 350 degrees F. Beat egg yolks with water and sugar; brush
  over buns. Bake 20 minutes.
  
  Makes 20 buns.
  
  CHINESE BAKED SWEET BREAD DOUGH
  
  Chinese bread dough is quite sweet compared with Western breads (the
  further south you go in China, the sweeter the dough becomes). Most Chinese
  breads are steamed, which is why they look pale and uncooked to the Western
  eye.
  
  Put the yeast and 1 tablespoon of the sugar in a small bowl. Add 1/4 cup of
  the warm milk. Let stand 5 minutes, then stir to dissolve. If should foam
  and bubble. If it does not, discard and use a fresh package of yeast. Stir
  in the egg, oil and remaining milk.
  
  Put the flour and remaining sugar in the work bowl of a food processor
  fitted with the metal blade. Process 2 seconds. With the machine running,
  pour the warm milk mixture down the feed tube in a steady stream. Process
  until it forms a rough ball. If ball is sticky and wet, add a little more
  flour. Process a few seconds longer, or until dough pulls away from the
  sides of the bowl. Remove dough to a lightly floured board.
  
  Knead dough, dusting with flour to keep it from sticking, until smooth and
  elastic, about 2 minutes. Place in a large oiled bowl, cover with plastic
  wrap and let rise in a warm spot until doubled, about 1 hour.
  
  Punch down dough and place on a lightly floured surface. It is now ready to
  form into rolls, buns or loaves.
  
  Makes enough for 20 barbecued pork buns. Joyce Jue, San Francisco
  Chronicle, 1/8/92 Posted by Stephen Ceideburg
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
