<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baked Custard-Style Rice Pudding</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>6 To 8</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>(1 1/2 quarts) milk</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Vanilla bean, split lengthwise, -or-</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Pure vanilla extract</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2/3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Long-grain white rice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Egg</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Egg yolks</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Raisins</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Ground cinnamon, for sprinkling</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  1. Rinse a heavy saucepan with cold water; leave wet. Place 4 cups of the
  milk, the sugar, salt and vanilla bean in the pan (if using vanilla
  extract, do not add it now). Cover and bring slowly to a boil. Stir in the
  rice with a large fork. Cover and simmer gently, stirring occasionally,
  until the rice is quite tender, about 40 minutes. Remove the vanilla bean;
  scrape the seeds into the rice mixture and stir in.
  
  2. Preheat the oven to 400 F, with a rack in the center. Butter a 12-inch
  oval pudding or gratin dish or other large shallow baking dish. In a bowl,
  beat the egg, egg yolks and the remaining 2 cups milk until combined (if
  you are using vanilla extract, add it now). Add this mixture and the
  raisins to the rice and stir to combine. Pour into the prepared baking
  dish. Set the baking dish in a roasting pan, and place in the oven. Pour
  enough hot tap water into the roasting pan to reach about halfway up the
  sides of the baking dish.
  
  3. Bake for 25 minutes. Stir the pudding gently with a fork to redistribute
  the rice. Bake for another 25 minutes. Stir again; lightly sprinkle the
  surface of the pudding with the cinnamon. Bake until the top of the pudding
  has crusted over lightly and is spotted with gold; the pudding should still
  be slightly liquid, another 25 minutes. (The total baking time is about 1
  1/4 hours. The timing can vary based on the depth and size of the baking
  dish; do not overbake.)
  
  4. Remove the pudding from the water bath and cool on a wire rack. Serve
  lukewarm or slightly chilled.
  
  Both recipes are from _Classic Home Desserts_ by Richard Sax.
  
  Posted to EAT-L Digest 28 Aug 96
  
  From:    Felicia Pickering &lt;MNHAN063@SIVM.SI.EDU&gt;
  
  Date:    Thu, 29 Aug 1996 18:25:30 EDT
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
