<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baked Pork Buns</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>DOUGH</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Warm milk; (110 degrees f)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Warm water; (110 degrees f)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Active dry yeast</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>1/2 cups all-purpose flour; up to 2</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>dash</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>FILLING</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>8</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Dried mushrooms; up to 10</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Vegetable oil</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Minced green onions; (including tops)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Cloves garlic; minced</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Hoisin sauce</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Oyster sauce</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Cornstarch; mixed with 1 tablespoon water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Chinese bbq pork; chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Egg yolk; lightly beaten</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Sweet, soft toasty-brown buns surround a tangy barbecued pork filling.
  Makes 12 buns. Cooking time: 30 minutes.
  
  Preparation :
  
  In a large bowl, dissolve 2 tablespoons of the sugar in milk and water.
  Sprinkle yeast over top of the milk mixture and let stand at room
  temperature for 10 minutes or until frothy. Gradually mix in remaining 2
  tablespoons sugar, flour, and salt. On a lightly floured surface, knead
  dough for about 5 minutes or until smooth and elastic. Shape into a ball
  and place in a lightly greased bowl. Cover with a damp cloth and let rise
  in a warm area for about 1 hour or until doubled. Meanwhile, soak mushrooms
  in enough warm water to cover for 30 minutes; drain. Cut off and discard
  stems; coarsely chop caps. Set aside. Cooking
  
  Place wok or wide frying pan over high heat until hot. Add oil, swirling to
  coat sides. Add green onions, garlic, and mushrooms; stir-fry for 1 minute.
  Stir in water, hoisin sauce, and sugar; mix well. Add cornstarch solution
  and cook, stirring until sauce boils down and thickens. Add pork, mix well.
  Remove from heat and let cool. Punch down dough, then roll on a lightly
  floured surface into a 12-inch long cylinder. Cut cylinder crosswise into
  1-inch pieces. Shape each piece into a ball; let rest for 5 minutes. To
  shape each dumpling flatten one ball with a rolling pin to make a 4 to
  6-inch circle, keeping dough covered to prevent drying. Place 1 heaping
  tablespoon of filing in the center fo each circle (see illustration).
  Gather the edges of the circle over the filing; close top by pleating,
  pinching and twisting edges together. Place buns, pleated side down, on a
  baking sheet, allowing enough room for rising. Cover with a damp cloth and
  let rise in a warm place for about 30 minutes or until light and puffy.
  Brush tops of buns with egg yolk. Let rise for 15 more minutes.
  
  Bake in a 350 degree F oven for 18 to 20 minutes or until golden brown.
  Tips: Traditionally, these buns are steamed over boiling water, pleated
  side up, for 12 to 15 minutes rather than baked. Follow the same procedure
  for preparing dough except do not brush tops of buns with egg yolk. Try
  other fillings, such as minced chicken, pork or shrimp.
  
  Recipe by: Martin Yan
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest by "Mega-bytes" &lt;mega-bytes@email.msn.com&gt; on
  Feb 22, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
