<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baked Yeast Doughnuts</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>packages</unit></amt>
        <item>Active dry yeast</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Lukewarm water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Milk; scalded</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter or margarine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Nutmeg (up to 2)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4 3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flour (up to 5)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Melted butter or margarine</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Dissolve yeast in the lukewarm water. Add butter to scalded milk and cool
  to lukewarm. Add yeast. Beat eggs; add sugar and beat again; add to milk.
  Add salt, nutmeg and beat in thoroughly, adding enough flour to make a very
  soft dough. Cover and let rise in warm place until double in bulk. Or let
  rise in refrigerator until double in bulk, about 3 1/2 hours.
  
  Cut with a well-floured doughnut cutter or cut in rectangles about 1 1/2
  inch wide and 4 inches long. Place about 2 inches apart on well greased
  cookie sheet. Brush well with the melted butter or margarine. Let rise in
  warm place until double in bulk.
  
  Bake in 425 degree oven about 12 minutes or until lightly browned. Roll in
  sugar or frost with powdered sugar frosting. Makes 3 dozen.
  
  I use the canned frosting a lot. I tint it orange for Halloween or red for
  Christmas or Valentine Day or I use chocolate frosting. I dip them in
  coconut or finely chopped nuts after I frost them, you can also dip them in
  sprinkles for Christmas. If you want to make maple bars , just use maple
  flavoring in the frosting and they taste just like the maple bars you buy
  in the bakery.
  
  Posted to TNT - Prodigy's Recipe Exchange Newsletter  by
  vaughndell@juno.com on Nov 5, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
