<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baked Trout with Garlic-Almond Butter</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Fish</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Trout</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Red onion; sliced very thin</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Fresh basil leaves</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Salt and pepper</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>GARLIC-ALMOND BUTTER</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Slivered almonds (up to)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Cloves garlic</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Stick butter or margerine</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Lemon; juice of</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  From: dferrell@eleven.uccs.edu (Diane M. Ferrell)
  
  Date: 18 Nov 1994 18:31:39 -0500
  The last time we had some fresh trout I baked it with basil and onions and
  everyone loved it.  We didn't filet the trout, so it was baked whole, but I
  imagine you could use the recipe for the filets.
  
  Soak the trout in salt water for 15 minutes.  Rinse well and scrape the
  skin lightly. Rinse again. Salt and pepper the cavity. Thinly slice the
  onion and place several slices inside the cavity. Clean the basil and
  coarsly chop. Place the basil in the cavity also. Use about 4-5 very large
  leaves. Place the trout in a baking pan with just a small amount of water.
  Cover will foil and bake at 350 degrees. These were extremely large trout
  that my brother had caught. They were over a pound each and about 18" long.
  I baked them for about 25 minutes. During the last 10 minutes of baking
  time I spread the garlic-almond butter on top, recoved with the foil and
  baked for 5 minutes more. The last five minutes I removed the foil.
  
  Garlic-almond butter: Puree the garlic and butter together in the processor
  then put in a heavy skillet on medium high heat.  When the butter begins to
  sizzle add the slivered almonds and toast until just beginning to turn
  golden. Remove &gt;from the heat and add the lemon and mix well.
  
  I would think that you could salt and pepper the filets, lay them in a
  baking dish, then cover with basil then onions and the foil.  The filets
  would not take nearly so long to bake--maybe 15 minutes with the last few
  minutes baking uncovered and with the garlic-almond butter on. Fresh water
  trout is done when it flakes easily apart. But, as with all fish, it
  doesn't take very long to cook.
  
  REC.FOOD.RECIPES ARCHIVES
  
  /FISH
  
  From rec.food.cooking archives.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
