<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baked or Grilled Fish with Dijon Glaze</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Seafood</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Fish fillets or steaks; 7 ounce</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Lemon Herb Dijon Glaze</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Dry white wine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Fresh herb; for garnish</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Preheat oven or grill to 500 degrees (or 450 degrees if that temperature is
  just too scary at first). Heat the pan on high heat, until it is very hot.
  While it is heating, brush glaze over all surfaces of the fish,
  particularly all flesh.
  
  To Bake: When the pan is hot (using potholders) put the fish in and brown
  on one side. Turn the fish after 2 minutes and put the pan into the oven.
  Bake for another few minutes. Remember: 5 minutes to the inch of thickness.
  
  To Grill: Put fish on grill and cook, turning only once (for 5 minutes per
  inch). Take the fish out of the oven or off the grill, and immediately
  transfer it to a warmed serving dish or warmed individual plates.Add wine
  to the pan and cook at medium high, whisking constantly until the sauce is
  reduced by half. For grilling, cook wine and 1 tbsp. Dijon glaze in a small
  pan. Pour over the fish, garnish with fresh herb, and serve immediately.
  
  NOTES : You will need a heavy, oven-proof pan, preferably non-stick coated
  or seasoned cast iron. A pan is not necessary for grilling. Before you make
  the sauce or Demi-Glace make a slight separation in the flesh to stop the
  cooking. Most fish is overcooked; its natural moisture is leached out by
  prolonged heat, so its delicate texture becomes stringy or a little tough.
  The less time fish is exposed to moisture-sapping heat, in the oven or on a
  grill, the moister it will be. The hotter the heat, the less time it is
  exposed. Dijon Glaze seals the pores of the flesh so fish can withstand 500
  heat.
  Recipe by: Copyright c 1995 by Heidi Rabel
  
  Posted to recipelu-digest by "Valerie Whittle" &lt;catspaw@inetnow.net&gt; on Feb
  19, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
