<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baking Mix and Uses From Vegetarian Times Pt 2</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Magazine</cat>
        <cat>Mixes</cat>
        <cat>Low-fat</cat>
        <cat>Breakfast</cat>
        <cat>Vegetarian</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>See part 1</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Preheat oven to 425 degrees. In medium bowl, combine baking mix and milk;
  stir until blended. Turn dough out onto lightly floured surface and knead
  briefly (about 10 times). With lightly floured rolling pin, roll dough out
  to 1/2-inch thickness. Using 2 1/2-inch round biscuit or cookie cutter, cut
  out dough. Place biscuits about 2-inches apart on ungreased cookie sheet.
  Bake until golden about 10 minutes. Serve warm. Makes 6 biscuits.
  
  Note: These biscuits can be served as a side dish or quick snack. They are
  also great split and filled with savory ingredients for sandwiches or with
  sliced, seasonal fruit for dessert.
  
  PER BISCUIT: 145CAL.; 4G PROT.; 4G TOTAL FAT (1G SAT. FAT); 23G CARB.; 3MG
  CHOL.; 163MG SOD.; 1G FIBER. LACTO
  
  Abstract: The magazine staff took a traditional Bisquick-style baking mix
  and modified it to include whole grains and less salt. The new recipe can
  be used to make muffins, pancakes and bread.
  
  For moistness, we used light stick margarine, whic also helps to reduce the
  fat content. A vegan variation is as follows: Prepare the mix using vegan
  margarine and omit the powdered milk. When you're ready to prepare
  biscuits, pancakes, etc., add 1/2 cup water, soy or rice milk for every 2
  cups of mix.
  
  The staff found that the baking mix made great biscuits, pancakes and
  muffins. With the use of leftover vegetables, fruit, spices, nuts, cheeses
  and herbs, the possible variations on these themes are endless.
  
  Source: Vegetarian Times, Sep 1997 n241 p32(2). Author: Nancy Berkoff
  
  Retrieved from library electronic database, edited and MC-Busted by
  &lt;adamsfmle@sprintmail.com&gt;; posted lu 3/2/98.
  
  Recipe by: Vegetarian Times Magazine, 9/97
  
  Posted to recipelu-digest by Badams &lt;adamsfmle@sprintmail.com&gt; on Mar 02,
  1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
