<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baklava</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Desserts</cat></categories>
      <yield>60</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Granulated sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Honey</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Lemon rind</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Stick cinnamon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Whole cloves</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/4</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Walnuts &amp; blanched almonds Chopped medium fine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground cinnamon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground cloves</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Commercial filo sheets</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Sweet butter; melted</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Combine 3 cups sugar, the water, honey, whole lemon rind, and whole spices
  in a saucepan and bring to boil. Lower the heat and simmer for 15 minutes,
  then remove the lemon peel and spices and cool.
  
  Meanwhile, in a large bowl, combine the nuts, remaining 1/2 cup sugar, and
  ground spices and set aside. Lay filo sheets flat, cover with waxed paper
  and then a damp towel.  Keep covered except when removing to assemble the
  baklava.  Count 8 filo sheets, fold, cover and refrigerate to reserve for
  the top. Using a large pastry brush, butter an 11 1/2-inch by 15 1/2-inch
  by 3-inch baking pan.  Lay a filo sheet on the bottom of the pan, brush
  with warm butter, and repeat using 8 sheets. Scoop up a handful of the
  nut-spice mixture and sprinkle over the top filo sheet inside the pan. Lay
  on 3 or more filo sheets, brushing each with butter, and sprinkle again
  with the nut mixture. Continue until all the nuts and filo are used. (The
  important things here are to butter each filo and spread the nuts evenly.
  The way to do the latter is to rotate the pan several times during the
  procedure.)  Now you can remove the reserved sheets from the refrigerator
  and spread over the top, brushing on each sheet.
  
  Using a long, very sharp knife, score the baklava from top to bottom into
  diamond shapes planning in advance the size desired. Be sure the knife
  touches the bottom of the pan as you cut. Heat the remaining butter to
  sizzling and pour over the top.  Bake in a 300 degree oven for 1 1/4 hours
  or until golden chestnut in color and flaky. Remove from the oven (in the
  pan) to a rack, and spoon the cooled syrup over the entire pastry. Cool in
  the pan, then serve each piece individually.
  
  Source: "The Food of Greece" by Vilma Liacouras Chantiles Avenel Books, New
  York.
  
  Cutting Diagram: ___________________________________
  |\_____\_____\_____\_____\___\____| |__\_____\_____\_____\____\____\__|
  |____\_____\_____\_____\____\____\| |_\____\_____\_____\_____\____\___|
  |___\____\_____\_____\_____\____\_|
  
  Typed for you by Karen Mintzias
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
