<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Baklava (Papadakis Taverna)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Greek</cat>
        <cat>Desserts</cat>
        <cat>California</cat></categories>
      <yield>12</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 2/3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Cinnamon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Coarsley chopped walnuts</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Sweet butter; melted</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Phyllo pastry sheets</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>40</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Whole cloves</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>2" strip of orange peel</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>2" strip of lemon peel</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Cinnamon stick</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Honey</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Lemon; juiced</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  In a medium bowl place the cinnamon and walnuts, and mix them together.
  
  Brush the bottom of a 14" x 20" baking dish with the butter.  Place one
  pastry sheet in the dish and brush it with the butter.  Repeat this process
  so that 6 pastry sheets line the bottom of the dish.
  
  Sprinkle 1/3 of the nut mixture over the top of the pastry sheets.  Repeat
  this process so that there are 3 layers of the nut mixture and 4 layers of
  6 buttered pastry sheets, ending with 6 pastry sheets.
  
  Cut the baklava into 40 diamond shaped pieces.  Insert a whole clove in the
  top of each piece.
  
  Preheat the oven to 350 F.  Bake the baklava for 40 minutes, or until it is
  golden brown.  In a medium saucepan place the sugar, water, orange peel,
  lemon peel, and cinnamon stick.  Bring the ingredients to a boil and then
  simmer them for 5 minutes.
  
  Add the honey and bring the mixture to a boil.  Remove the pan from the
  heat and add the lemon juice.  Stir the ingredients together and then let
  the syrup cool.  Remove the orange and lemon peels, and the cinnamon stick.
  
  Spread the cool syrup over the hot baklava.  Cover the dish with a towel
  and let it sit for 1 hour before serving.
  
  Source: Papadakis Taverna - San Pedro, California California Beach Recipe -
  by Joan &amp; Carl Stromquist - ISBN: 0-9622807-3-9
  
  Typed for you by Karen Mintzias
  Sent to me by Bill &lt;wight@odc.net&gt;
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
