<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Balfa with Dal</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Indian</cat>
        <cat>Breads</cat>
        <cat>Main dish</cat>
        <cat>Vegan</cat>
        <cat>Anne's</cat></categories>
      <yield>10</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>FOR BAFLA</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour, whole wheat; 225 g</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Ghee; or oil Salt Water for kneading Extra ghee or oil</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>FOR DAL</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>225</qty>
            <unit>grams</unit></amt>
          <item>Mung beans, split; moong dal Water; 1.25 l</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Tumeric powder Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>medium</unit></amt>
          <item>Onions; chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Green chilies</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Bay leaves</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Cinnamon sticks; 2 inches</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Oil</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Coriander, fresh; cilantro chopped</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Rajasthani bread
  
  Put split mung beans (moong dal) with water in a heavy pan over high heat.
  Add half of the chopped onion, salt, sugar, green chilies, bay leaves,
  cinnamon sticks. Sift flour with salt; rub in ghee or oil. Knead to a
  smooth dough. Divide the dough into 10 parts and shape them into round
  balls. Drop these balls in the boiling dal, reduce heat. Cook for 25
  minutes then remove the cooked flour balls one by one from the dal. Place
  the cooked flour flour balls in a greased baking dish. Bake in a preheat
  oven 375F (190 C/ gas mark 5) until the skin of the balls begins to crack
  and the colour turns light brown. Place them in a dish and press each of
  them in the centre with your thumb. Break lightly and put 1 or 2 tsp ghee
  in each bafla. Can be eaten without ghee too.
  
  Heat 3 Tbsp oil in a pan. Fry remaining half of onions until lightly
  broened. Pour cooked dal. Stir well. Let it boil 2-3 times. Remove from
  heat and sprinkle with chopped coriander. Serve baflas with dal.
  
  Note: Dal (beans) should be poured over the baflas, breaking them
  completely. Other vegetable dishes or chutney can be served with it also.
  
  SERVES: 10 SOURCE: _Rotis and Naans of India_ by Purobi Babbar, published
  in Bombay posted, not tested by Anne MacLellan
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
