<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Banana Cream Pie 3</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Diabetic</cat>
        <cat>Desserts</cat>
        <cat>Pies</cat></categories>
      <yield>8</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Vanilla wafer crumb crust (see 2/2)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Granulated gelatin</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Cold water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Hot skim milk</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Of flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Cold skim milk</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs beaten</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Sugar substitute equivalent to 3 tablespoons sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Pure vanilla extract</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Firm-ripe bananas</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Prepare pie crust and chill 2 hours or longer before filling. Soak gelatin
  in cold water and set aside. Heat 1 1/2 cups of milk in the top of a double
  boiler over simmering water. In a small bowl combine flour, salt and 1/2
  cup of cold milk; mix until smooth and without lumps. Slowly pour i/2 cup
  of the hot milk into the bowl with the flour mixture; stir to mix well. The
  slowly pour contents of the bowl back into the pot of hot milk. Cook and
  stir over simmering water until thick and smooth. Pour mixture slowly on
  top of beaten eggs, stirring constantly. Return to top of double boiler.
  Cook and stir over simmering water about 4 minutes; remove from heat. Add
  gelatin, sweetener and vanilla; mix well to dissolve gelatin. Cool and
  chill until mixture begins to gel. Peel bananas, slice thin and measure 1
  1/2 cups. Arrange 1 cup of sliced bananas in bottom of pie shell, then
  carefully spoon and pour filling evenly on top. Arrange remaining 1/2 cup
  sliced bananas on top and garnish with the vanilla crumbs saved when making
  pie shell. Cover whole pie carefully with plastic wrap. Chill 2-3 hours,
  until set and firm.  To serve, cut into eight equal pieces. 9"pie = 8
  servings CHO PRO FAT CAL FIBER SODIUM CHOL (g) (g) (g) - (g) (mg) (mg)
  :24     5  7    174    0.8
      174      79 Food Exchanges per serving 1 fruit exchange plus 1 low-fat
  milk exchange..you can use unsalted margarine to eliminate salt.
  
  Shared by Al Massery
  
  alvism@aol.com Shared by Al
  Posted to MM-Recipes Digest V5 #020 by scotlyn@juno.com (Daniel S Johnson)
  on Jan 19, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
