<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Banana Butterfinger Cake</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>CAKE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2 1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Cake flour</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Baking powder</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>(1 stick) unsalted butter; room temperature</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Eggs</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Dark rum</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Vanilla extract</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sour cream</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Baking soda</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Mashed ripe bananas (about 5)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Finely chopped butterfinger bars (about 6 ounces)</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>GLAZE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Whipping cream</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>7</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Unsalted butter; cut into large pieces</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Light corn syrup</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>14</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Semisweet chocolate; chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Dark rum</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Vanilla extract</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Shopped butterfinger bars (about 7 1/2 ounces)</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  For Cake: Position rack in top third of oven; preheat to 350. Butter two
  9-inch diameter cake pans with 1 and 1/2 inch high sides. Line bottoms with
  waxed paper rounds. Butter and flour paper. Sift flour, baking powder and
  salt into medium bowl. Using electric mixer, beat butter in large bowl
  until fluffy. Gradually add sugar and beat 2 minutes. Add eggs 1 at a time,
  beating well after each addition. Beat in dark rum and vanilla exxtract.
  Combine sour cream and baking soda in medium bowl. Add mashed bananas to
  sour cream mixture and stir until well blended. Add dry ingredients to
  butter mixture alternately with banana mixture, beginning and ending with
  dry ingredients. Stir in chopped Butterfinger bars. Divide batter between
  prepared pans. Bake until center of cake feels firm and tester inserted
  into center comes out clean, about 30 minutes. Cool in pans on rack 10
  minutes. Run small knife around sides of cake to loosen. Turn out cakes
  onto racks and cool. Pull of waxed paper. (Can be prepared 1 day ahead.
  Wrap cakes tightly and store at room temperature.)
  
  For Glaze: Combine cream, butter and corn syrup in heavy medium saucepan.
  Bring to a simmer over medium heat, stirring until butter melts. Remove
  from heat; add chocolate and stir until melted and smooth. Stir in rum and
  vanilla. Pour glaze into small bowl. Cover and refrigerate just until cool
  and thick, stirring occassionally, about
       40    minutes. Transfer 1 cake layer to platter. Slide waxed paper
  strips under edges of cake. Stir glaze until smooth. Spread 1 cup glaze
  evenly over top layer of cake. Spread remaining glaze over top and sides of
  cake. Cover top and sides of cake with chopper Butterfinger bars. Remove
  paper strips.
  note: This came from an article in Bon Appetit called Candy Bar desserts.
  It also contained recipes for Mounds Macaroons, Snickers Pie, Heath Bar
  Brownie Sundaes with Caramel sauce, Frozen Milky Way Mouse with Bittersweet
  Chocolate Sauce and Peanut Butter Cup Cheesecake. I didn't send the others
  because I haven't tried them yet (although I do plan to!) If you want any
  of them, let me know and I'll be happy to post them.
  
  Posted to Bakery-Shoppe Digest V1 #213 by Mandy Bell &lt;mbell@cdsnet.net&gt; on
  Sep 01, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
