<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Banana Cream Pie</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Pies &amp;</cat>
        <cat>Pastry</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Chopped cashews or macadamia nuts</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flaked coconut</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Brown sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg white Filling---</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg yolks</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>5</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Cornstarch</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Granulated sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Milk</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Unsalted butter</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Vanilla</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Heavy cream</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Ripe bananas</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Finely chopped cashews or macadamia nuts</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Preheat oven to 375F. In a bowl, combine nuts, coconut and sugar. Beat egg
  white until stiff. Fold into nut mixture. Press mixture evenly into 8-inch
  pie plate. Build up the sides slightly. Bake for 7 minutes, or until
  lightly browned. Remove from oven and cool on wire rack. Crust will tighten
  up as it cools.
  
  In a heavy medium saucepan, beat egg yolks. Mix in cornstarch and sugar.
  Stir in milk, salt and butter. Cook mixture slowly over medium heat,
  stirring constantly for 5-7 minutes. Filling should be bubbling and thick.
  Remove from heat and stir in vanilla. Transfer custard to a glass bowl,
  cover with plastic wrap, and chill in refrigerator for two hours. Two hours
  before serving, whip heavy cream to stiff peaks and fold into custard. Peel
  and slice one banana. Arrange evenly over bottom of crust. Spoon custard
  filling into crust. Cover with plastic wrap and chill for two hours more.
  Before serving, sprinkle chopped nuts evenly over filling. Peel, slice and
  arrange second banana in a circular fashion on top of the pie. Place a few
  slices decoratively in the center. Serve immediately.
  
  Recipe by: Parade 1979 Posted to EAT-L Digest by Nancy Pallotta
  &lt;nancee@NEO.LRUN.COM&gt; on Jul 7, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
