<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Banana Cream Pie</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Flaky Pie Dough for a 1crust pie; above</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>FILLING</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2 1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Milk</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>pinch</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Cornstarch</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Eggs</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Unsalted butter; softened</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Vanilla extract</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Bananas; sliced</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>TOPPING</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Heavy cream</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Vanilla extract</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Prepare and bake the crust.</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  To make the filling, combine 2 cups milk, sugar and salt in a nonreactive
  saucepan; whisk once to mix and bring to a boil over low heat. Place
  remaining 1/2 cup milk in a mixing bowl and whisk in cornstarch, then eggs.
  Return milk and sugar mixture to a boil over low heat then whisk about a
  third of it into the egg mixture. Return milk and sugar mixture to a boil
  once more and whisk in the egg mixture, whisking constantly until the
  filling thickens and comes to a boil. Allow to boil, whisking constantly,
  for about 30 seconds. Remove from heat, whisk in butter and vanilla; pour
  into a nonreactive bowl. Press plastic wrap against the surface of the
  filling and chill until it is approximately 75 degrees. Fold the bananas
  into the cooled filling and spread it evenly in the cooled crust. To finish
  the pie, whip the cream with the sugar and vanilla until it holds a firm
  peak. Use a hand mixer on medium speed or a heavyduty mixer fitted with the
  whisk. Spread the cream over the filling, making sure it touches the edges
  of the crust all around. COCONUT CREAM PIE: For the 2/3 cup sugar in the
  filling substitute 1/3 cup sugar. Substitute 1/2 cup coconut cream, such as
  Coco Lopez, for the 1/2 cup milk with which the cornstarch is mixed. After
  the filling has cooled, fold in 1/2 cup toastedsweetened coconut. After
  covering the pie with the whipped cream, (you may add up to 1/4 cup coconut
  cream to the cream before whipping it to replace the sugar) sprinkle the
  whipped cream with 1/2 cup toasted sweetened coconut. (To toast coconut,
  place it on a jelly roll pan on the middle rack of a preheated 325 degree
  oven for about 15 minutes. Stir often so that the coconut colors evenly to
  a light golden brown.) Yield: one 9-inch pie
  Recipe By     : BAKERS' DOZEN (NICK MALGIERI) SHOW #1A16
  
  Posted to EAT-L Digest 14 October 96
  
  Date:    Tue, 15 Oct 1996 20:20:24 -0500
  
  From:    Jackie Bordelon &lt;jbord@PREMIER.NET&gt;
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
