<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Bar Room Slaw (The Four Seasons Restaurant)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Salads</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Assorted Vegetables **</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg yolks</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh lemon juice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Dijon-style mustard</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Kosher salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Freshly ground pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>To 1 1/2C olive oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Red wine vinegar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Romaine lettuce leaves</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Belgian endive, separated into leaves, rinsed</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Watercress, rinsed, trimmed</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Alfalfa sprouts</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  1.  Select vegetables according to season, personal preference and
  complementarity of colors, textures and tastes. Cut into very fine julienne
  by hand or shred fine in food processor, using shredding disc. 2. Whisk egg
  yolks, lemon juice, mustards, salt and pepper in medium bowl until well
  blended.  Add oil, drop by drop, whisking continuously, until mixture is
  thick. Then continue whisking in oil in slow steady stream. Stir in
  vinegar. 3. To serve, pour amount of dressing desired over julienned
  vegetables in bowl; toss gently. Line individual salad plates with romaine,
  endive and watercress. Top with dressed vegetables, dividing evenly.
  Sprinkle with sprouts. ** Some vegetables to consider: carrot, zucchini,
  red, green, and yellow bell pepper, celery, celeriac, summer squash,
  chayote, Chinese cabbage, daikon, black radish, turnip, white and red
  cabbage, cucumber, tomato, sugar snap peas, broccoli stems. Julienned
  vegetables can be prepared ahead; refrigerate, wrapped in plastic wrap.
  Make dressing just before serving. Use one cup of julienne vegetables per
  person.
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
