<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Barbecued Chicken #5</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Poultry</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Skinless Boneless Chicken Breasts; (4 oz. or more each)</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>SAUCE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Ketchup</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Cider Vinegar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>White Horseradish; or more to taste</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Brown Sugar; Packed</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Clove Garlic; minced (or more)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/8</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Dried Thyme</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Black Pepper</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  From: kmeade@ids2.idsonline.com (The Meades)
  
  Date: Sun, 30 Jun 1996 18:54:22 -0400
  Recipe By: Lori Varela &lt;lvarela@INSPIRE.OSPI.WEDNET.EDU&gt;
  
  Preheat broiler, heat charcoal grill until coasl form white ask, or preheat
  a gas grill to medium.  (I used my fiberware electric grill)
  
  To prepare sauce, in small sucepan, combine ketchup, vinegar, horseradish,
  brown sugar, garlic, and thyme.  Mix well.  Bring to a boil over medium-low
  heat.  Cook, stirring frequently, until thickened, about 5 minutes.  Remove
  from heat; stir in pepper.
  
  Brush tops of chicken pieces lightly with sauce.  Place chicken, sauce-side
  down, on a foil-lined broiler pan or grill rack.  Brush other sides lightly
  with sauce.
  
  Broil or grill 3 inches from heat, basting with reminaing sauce and turning
  until no longer pink in center, about 5 to 7 minutes per side (mine took a
  lot longer, because of the pieces were fatter and farther away from the
  heat). Let chicken stand for 5 minutes before serving.
  
  I served this with rice (actually I must admit I used Rice Roni... my kids
  love it), tossed green salad, and mixed vegetables.
  
  MC-Recipe Digest V1 #135
  
  From the MasterCook recipe list.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
