<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Barbara's Cinnamon Rolls</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Breads</cat></categories>
      <yield>48</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Lukewarm water (105 F to 115 F)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Envelopes dry yeast</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Milk</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>(3/4 stick) butter</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>5 1/2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>To 6 cups all-purpose flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs, beaten</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>To 3/4 cup (1 to 1 1/2 sticks) butter, melted</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Cinnamon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>Makes</qty>
          <unit>48</unit></amt>
        <item>rolls</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Butter muffin tins; set aside.  Mix together water, yeast and sugar in
  small bowl and let proof until foamy, about 10 minutes.
  
  Combine milk, butter and salt in small saucepan. Place over medium heat and
  bring to boil, stirring occasionally. Pour into large mixing bowl. Add 1/4
  cup sugar and 4 cups flour 1 cup at a time, mixing thoroughly after each
  cup of flour is added.  Add eggs and mix with dough hook on low speed 3 to
  4 minutes. When dough has cooled to lukewarm, add yeast and remaining
  flour.  Mix on medium speed 4 to 5 minutes, scraping bowl several times.
  
  Divide dough in half and roll into rectangular sheets 1/4 inch thick. Brush
  surfaces with melted butter. Combine sugar and cinnamon and sprinkle evenly
  over dough. Roll up each sheet tightly and lay seam side down. Slice into
  1/2-inch rounds and place in muffin tins. Cover lightly and let rise in
  warm draft-free area until doubled in bulk.
  
  About 15 minutes before rolls are ready to bake, preheat oven to 400 F.
  Bake rolls for 10 to 12 minutes, until light golden brown.
  
  The House of Embers - Lake Delton, WI. Bon Appetite
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
