<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Barbecued Pork Strips</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Meat</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Marinade for barbecued pork</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Pork</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>     1. Cut pork in strips 2 inches wide, 2 inches thick and 5 inches long.
  
     2. Prepare any of the marinades for barbecued pork strips (see recipes
  below). Add to pork and let stand 2 hours, turning meat frequently. Drain,
  reserving marinade.
  
     3. Preheat the oven to 425 degrees. Place pork strips on a rack over a
  shallow roasting pan containing a few inches of water; or suspend,
  barbecue-style, in oven. (See HOW-TO SECTION.) Roast 10 minutes.
  
     4. Reduce heat to 325 degrees and roast pork 30 to 40 minutes more.
  (Turn meat several times if not suspended.) Baste strips lightly at
  5-minute intervals with peanut or sesame oil; or glaze with a thin layer of
  honey during the last 10 minutes of roasting.
  
     5. Cut pork against the grain in bite-size pieces. Serve hot with
  reheated marinade; or cold with plum sauce, hot Chinese mustard (see
  recipe) or a soy sauce dip.
  
     NOTE: Barbecued Pork Strips may be used in any dish that calls for roast
  pork. They can be prepared in quantity and refrigerated (they will keep
  about a week) or frozen in foil. (If frozen, reheat in foil without
  defrosting.)
  
     VARIATIONS: Marinate a whole pork tenderloin. Roast 30 minutes at 375
  degrees; 1 hour at 300 degrees. If meat is on a rack, turn at 15-minute
  intervals. (If suspended barbecue-style, turning isn't necessary.)
  
     Roast the marinated pork strips 15 minutes at 350 degrees; then raise
  heat to 450, baste with peanut oil and roast 1o minutes more. (This will
  make pork very crisp.)
  
     Cook the marinated pork strips over a hibachi, or charcoal grill, etc.,
  allowing about 15 minutes on each side.
  
     Broil the marinated pork strips 25 minutes, turning once. (Place about
  1-1/2 inches from flame.) Baste with the marinade at 5-minute intervals.
  
     For marinades, see one of the "marinade" for Barbecued Pork recipes:
  Basic, Sugar-Soy, Spiced, Pineapple-Sherry, Garlic-Onion, Hoisin-Five
  Spices, Hoisin-Chili, Sherry-Brown Sugar, Soy-Sherry, Five Spices,
  Sherry-Honey, Soy-Sugar or Brown Bean.
  
  From &lt;The Thousand Recipe Chinese Cookbook&gt;, ISBN 0-517-65870-4. Downloaded
  from Glen's MM Recipe Archive, http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
