<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Barb's China Chicken Rice</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Maindish</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Chicken breast; boned, skinned cut in bite-size pieces</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>slice</unit></amt>
        <item>Ginger; fresh, diced fine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Clove garlic; pressed</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Soy sauce</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sesame oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Canola oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Onion; chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Mushrooms; fresh, diced fine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Zucchini; cut into cubes</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Cilantro; fresh, chopped fine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Rice; cooked</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Chicken broth; or as needed</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Slivered almonds</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Soy sauce; to taste</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Place chicken pieces in a bowl with the garlic, ginger, sesame oil, and 2
  tablespoons soy sauce. stir to coat and let stand while preparing the
  remaining vegetables.
  
  Put the canola oil into a medium sized skillet (or wok). Saute the onions
  until they are limp.  Add the mushrooms and saute until they give up their
  juice. Remove the vegetables and reserve.
  
  Put the chicken and it's spices in the skillet, being careful to drain most
  of the liquid and cook until it it cooked through and slightly browned. Add
  the zucchini and cilantro, and stir fry 3 minutes. Add the rice, the
  reserved vegetables and enough of the chicken stock to keep the rice from
  sticking.
  
  Cook only briefly to allow everything to heat through. Add the almonds and
  serve immediately.
  
  Note:  This is a dish I often make when I have leftover rice, and I very
  often use up different cooked vegetables in this dish. With cooked
  vegetables, simply cut them into small cubes, or julienne and add them just
  early enough so that they will be well heated. Try not to use vegetables
  that will become mushy with the heating, you will want them to still be
  tender-crisp. We often use carrots, broccoli, even spinach. If you are
  having Denise Bradshaw over to dinner, throw in a few peas.
  
  Date:    6/28/96 7:27 AM
  
  From: dlassiter@atsva.com
  
  MC-Recipe Digest V1 #133
  
  From the MasterCook recipe list.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
