<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Barbecued Spareribs (Or Chicken)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Meat</cat></categories>
      <yield>8</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
          <item>Pork spareribs</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>SAUCE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
          <item>Tomatoe paste</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Instant onion</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Cloves garlic; pressed</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Heinz 57 steak sauce</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Brown sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Vinegar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>:</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>"Cook Forever" BBQ Spareribs (or Chicken)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Barb (Granny) Beck</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>   These ribs are cooked very slowly for 6 to 8 hours and then if desired
  "finished" on the BBQ.  I have tried shortcutting the recipe and boiling
  the ribs. Both times my family complained about the ribs being "fatty".
  
   Put ribs in oven and cook slowly (250 degrees) until they brown and start
  to dry out.  This should take 2 to 3 hours.  Pour off the accumulated fat
  and bursh on both sides with the sauce. Continue cooking another 4 to 6
  hours, brushing on more sauce from time to time. If the ribs start to dry
  out too much turn down the heat and/or cover with foil. If the sauce starts
  to burn on the bottom of the pan the oven is too hot. When done they are
  very tender. They are excellent straight from the oven and even better
  heated or reheated on the BBQ. This recipe also works with chicken but cut
  the cooking time in half. The whole idea is to cook the ribs slowly enough
  to make them moist and tender and not to leave a burned mass of sauce in
  the bottom of the pan which is really difficult to clean. Happy Cooking
  Barb Beck barb@forestburg.forsci.ualberta.ca Edmonton, Alberta, Canada
  
  BARB@FORESTBURG.FORSCI.
  
  UALBERTA.CA (BARB BECK)
  
  REC.FOOD.RECIPES
  
  From rec.food.cooking archives.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
