<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Barley Risotto with Shrimp Eggplant</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Vegetables</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>7</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Olive oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Shallot; minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Pearl barley</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>8</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Vegetable stock</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Japanese eggplant</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>10</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Lg shrimp; peeled cut 4 piec</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Grated pecorino cheese</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  In a large saucepan, heat 2 tablespoons oil over medium-high heat. Add
  shallot and cook, stirring, until translucent. Add barley; stir to coat
  with the oil. Reduce heat to medium. Continue cooking barley, stirring
  occasionally, for 2-3 minutes; take care not to let it brown. While barley
  is cooking, bring vegetable stock to a boil. Add vegetable stock to barley,
  a cup at time. Cook, stirring frequently, until liquid is almost absorbed
  before adding more liquid. Keep adding liquid, stirring frequently until
  barley pearls are al dente, about 45 minutes. Meanwhile, cut eggplant into
  1/2-inch cubes. Heat 4 tablespoons of oil in a large skillet over
  medium-high heat. Saute eggplant, stirring frequently, until soft, about 12
  minutes. Set aside. Using skillet in which eggplant was cooked, add
  remaining tablespoon of oil. Saute shrimp until pink. When barley is done,
  stir in eggplant and shrimp. Add grated pecorino cheese. Serve. Source:
  Odette Fada, Rex Il Restaurante, Los Angeles Fada's barley risotto is easy
  to make. It's a great way to offer the luxury of shellfish. Because the
  shrimp is cut into pieces, you only a half-pound of it to make risotto for
  6-8 people. Despite the shrimp, this dish is predominantly grain. It's high
  in complex carbohydrates and fiber, and low in fat. But it's so exciting
  that one hesitates to label it with the stigma of "healthy eating." Best of
  all, here's a dish that fits the proverbial champagne taste on a beer
  budget; in total, ingredients for this risotto cost about $10. Add a salad
  and a cheese course and you can feed a small dinner party for about $5 a
  head.
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
