<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Barley Risotto with Roasted Tomatoes and Nicoise Olives</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Side dishes</cat>
        <cat>Tomatoes</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Tomatoes (about 1 1/2 pounds); cut crosswise</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>5</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Water; more if needed</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Chicken stock; homemade or canned</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Olive oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Onion; chopped fine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Pearl  barley (about 11 ounces)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Parmesan cheese; grated</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Heavy cream; optional</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Nicoise olives; chopped</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Heat the oven to 300 degrees.  Put the halved tomatoes, cut-side up, on a
  baking sheet.  Dry the tomatoes in the oven until shriveled but still
  juicy, not hard and dry, about 2 hours. Let cool and then cut into 1/2-inch
  pieces.
  
  In a medium saucepan, bring the water and stock to a boil.  Remove from the
  heat and keep covered.
  
  In another medium saucepan, heat the oil over moderate heat.  Add the onion
  and cook, stirring occasionally, until translucent, about 5 minutes.
  
  Add the barley and stir to coat.  Add about a third of the hot stock
  mixture and cook at a gentle boil, stirring occasionally, until absorbed.
  Add another third of the stock and cook, stirring frequently, until
  absorbed.  Add the remaining stock and the salt and cook, stirring
  frequently, until the barley is tender, about 1 hour and 15 minutes total
  cooking time.  Any stock that has not been absorbed should be thickened by
  the starch from the barley.
  
  Stir the barley vigorously to make the texture creamier.  If it is dry, add
  more water.  Stir in the butter, Parmesan, the cream, if using, and three
  quarters of both the tomatoes and the olives.  Serve the barley risotto
  topped with the remaining tomatoes and olives.
  
  Chef's Notes:  This is a "Dean's Quisine Recipe" from Dean Fearing's weekly
  cooking segment on KDFW-TV in the Dallas/Ft. Worth area.  Dean Fearing is
  the Executive Chef of the Mansion on Turtle Creek in Dallas.
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest V1 #204
  
  Date: 17 Aug 96 15:14:58 EDT
  
  From: Paul &amp; Terri Law &lt;103366.1520@CompuServe.COM&gt;
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
