<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Barm Brack (Irish Yeast-Risen Tea Cake)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Cooking liv</cat>
        <cat>Import</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>SPONGE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Milk</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Envelopes; (1 tablespoon) active dry yeast</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Unbleached; all-purpose flour</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>DOUGH</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Golden raisins</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Currants</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Diced candied orange or lemon peel; or a combination</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>6</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Soft unsalted butter</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Ground cinnamon</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Freshly grated nutmeg</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/8</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Ground cloves</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/8</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Ground allspice</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Eggs</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Unbleached; all-purpose flour</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  To make the sponge, in a small saucepan over low flame, heat the milk and
  water until just warm, about 110 degrees. Pour into a small bowl, whisk in
  yeast and stir in flour. Cover the bowl with plastic wrap and allow sponge
  to rise for 30 minutes, or until doubled in bulk.
  
  Combine the raisins, currants and candied peel in a saucepan, cover with
  water and bring to a boil over medium heat. Drain fruit and spread it in a
  single layer on paper towels to cool and dry slightly while preparing the
  dough.
  
  To mix the dough by hand, beat butter with sugar, salt and spices until
  soft and smooth. Beat in eggs, one at a time, then continue beating until
  smooth and light. Stir in sponge and remaining flour. Place the dough on a
  lightly floured surface and knead it until it is smooth and elastic, about
       10    minutes.
  
  To make the dough in a mixer, use a heavy-duty mixer fitted with the paddle
  and beat butter with sugar, salt and spices until soft and smooth. Beat in
  eggs, one at a time, then continue beating until smooth and light. Beat in
  sponge and remaining flour. Continue to mix until dough is smooth and
  elastic, about 5 minutes.
  
  To mix the dough in the food processor, place butter, sugar, salt, spices
  and eggs in work bowl fitted with metal blade. Pulse 10 or 12 times at
  1-second intervals to mix smooth. Remove metal blade and attach plastic
  blade; add sponge and remaining flour and pulse to form a dough. Process
  continuously for 15 seconds.
  
  Place dough in a buttered bowl and cover with buttered plastic wrap, butter
  side down. Allow dough to rise until doubled in bulk, about 1 hour.
  
  Punch dough to deflate and turn it out onto a lightly floured surface.
  Distribute fruit on dough
  
  and knead it in evenly by continuing to fold dough over onto itself. Cover
  with plastic wrap or a dry towel and allow to rest 30 minutes.
  
  Butter two 8-inch diameter by 2-inch deep cake pans and line the bottom of
  each with a piece of parchment or butter waxed paper, cut to fit. Place
  half the dough in each and press to make tops flat and even. Cover pans
  with buttered plastic wrap or a dry towel and allow Bracks to rise until
  doubled, up to 1 hour.
  
  Once the Bracks have begun to puff visibly, set a rack at the middle level
  of the oven and preheat to 400 degrees. When the Bracks are completely
  risen, bake them for about 45 minutes, or until well risen and a deep
  golden brown. Test by inserting a thin knife or skewer near the center; if
  it is done it will emerge without any raw dough clinging to it. Cool on
  racks for 5 minutes, then unmold and place rack on racks to cool
  completely.
  
  Yield: 2 8-inch cakes, about 20 generous servings
  
  Notes: Recipe adapted from "Maura Laverty's Traditional Irish Cook Book,
  Volume 1: Bread and Cakes"
  
  Recipe by: Cooking Live Show #CL9085
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest by "Angele and Jon Freeman"
  &lt;jfreeman@comteck.com&gt; on Apr 4, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
