<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Basic Steamed Deep-Fried Duck</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Poultry</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Duck; 4 to 5 pounds</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Salt &amp; pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Oil for deep-frying</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Scallions</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>   1. Wipe duck inside and out with a damp cloth. Rub liberally with salt and
  pepper. Let stand 1 hour.
  
   2. Place bird in a deep, heatproof bowl and steam 1-1/2 to 2 hours by the
  bowl-in-a-pot method (see "HOW-TO SECTION").
  
   3. Drain duck and let cool. Wipe dry, then truss (see "HOW-TO SECTION").
  
   4. Heat oil to boiling. Using a wire basket or long-handled Chinese
  strainer, gently lower in duck and deep-fry, basting and turning, until
  golden. Drain on paper toweling.
  
   5. Let duck cool slightly, then chop, bones and all, in bite-size pieces.
  Serve with scallion brushes (see "HOW-TO SECTION"), a plum or hoisin sauce
  dip, or any other dip for deep-fried duck (see recipes).
  
   NOTE: The technique of double-frying can be used here. In step 4, deep-fry
  the duck 5 minutes, lift out; reheat the oil. Then return the bird and
  deep-fry again until crisp and golden.
  
   VARIATIONS:
  
      1. In Step 1, rub duck with any of the following mixtures:
  
         a. 2 teaspoons salt, 1/4 teaspoon anise pepper and 1/8 teaspoon Five
  Spices
  
         b. 2 tablespoons sherry, 2 teaspoons salt, 1/2 teaspoon sugar, 1/4
  teaspoon red pepper
  
         c. 1-1/2 tablespoons soy sauce, 1 tablespoon brown bean sauce,
  mashed; and 1/2 teaspoon Five Spices
  
         d. 1 to 2 scallion stalks and 3 or 4 slices fresh ginger root, both
  minced; 1 tablespoon Szechwan peppercorns, crushed; and 2 teaspoons salt
  
      2. In Step 2, before steaming, add to bowl with duck 2 scallion stalks
  and 2 or 3 slices fresh ginger root.
  
      3. In Step 3, before trussing duck, coat with a mixture of 2
  tablespoons cornstarch and 1 tablespoon soy sauce; or 3 tablespoons flour
  and 1 egg, lightly beaten.
  
  From &lt;The Thousand Recipe Chinese Cookbook&gt;, ISBN 0-517-65870-4. Downloaded
  from Glen's MM Recipe Archive, http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
