<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Basic Yogurt Cheese</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>16</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Nonfat plain yogurt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Coffee filters</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Colander (the larger the better)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Line a large colander with coffee machine filters. Place the yogurt into
  the filters, spreading over as large an area as possible. Place colander
  over a large dish to drain for 24 hours. (refrigerate) The watery whey will
  drain out of the yogurt, leaving a cheeselike substance similar in
  consistency to cream cheese. The longer the yogurt drains, the firmer it
  will become as more whey drains out. (Although many people drain it only
  for 24 hours, I like to start early and let it drain a little longer for
  firmer consistency.) And though it's not essential, I think I get better
  results if I replace the coffee filters once or twice during the process
  (the yogurt will be becoming drier and firmer and is usually easy for me to
  remove it from one filter to the next. If you choose to do this, you will
  notice less and less whey draining out each time as the yogurt becomes
  "cheese". This method is easy for me since I have the items on hand and I
  like it better than using cheesecloth. Some people really love the yogurt
  funnels that you can buy at many culinary cookshops.
  
  Plain yogurt cheese is 12 calories per tablespoon and has no fat. Yogurt
  cheese may be used as a substitute in cheese balls, spreads, dips,
  cheesecakes, etc. It is a good alternative to any of the following: ricotta
  cheese, sour cream, cream cheese or mayonnaise. Posted to TNT - Prodigy's
  Recipe Exchange Newsletter  by katiescarlett1@juno.com (L J G) on Aug 16,
  1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
