<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Basic Fresh Salsa Techniques</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Dip</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Fresh; not too ripe tomato, diced fine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Maui or other sweet onion; diced fine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Cilantro to taste - maybe 2 tablespoons</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Fresh Jalapeno or Serrano chiles; diced fine - more to taste</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Limes; juice of -or-</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Lemon; juice of</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  There are of course nearly as many salsa recipes as there are chile-heads,
  but here are a few comments and a basic recipe.
  
  1.  There's a huge difference between cooked and fresh salsas.  Canned
  tomatoes are cooked.  I think you're interested in a basic fresh salsa; you
  can go from there into a variety of red and green fresh and cooked salsas.
  
  2.  I don't much like tomatoes, fresh or otherwise - basically the only
  food I don't like - so if preparing just for myself I leave them out. When
  preparing salsa to share with others, I use under-ripe tomatoes, and
  sparingly. Just my taste, but it seems to run in our family.
  
  3.  No need for sugar.  No way of knowing what "2 green and 1 red chilli"
  means.  No problem with some fresh white onion and some coriander
  (cilantro). Scallions are okay too, but are a bit of a variation. Garlic -
  matter of taste; it's a strong flavor.
  
  4.  A fresh Mexican salsa, often called "pico de gallo," will usually
  include the following, so this might be considered a basic recipe:
  
   1 fresh, not too ripe tomato, diced fine
  
   1 Maui or other sweet onion, diced fine
  
   Cilantro to taste - maybe 2 tablespoons
  
   2 fresh jalapeno or serrano chiles, diced fine - more to taste
  
   juice of 2 limes or a lemon Stir well, keep chilled and covered until you
  serve it, and use within 24 hours (the tomato will start to get weird on
  you after that).  Adding some small cubes or hunks of ripe avocado right
  before serving is a good variation. Will &lt;wdborgeson@ucdavis.edu&gt;
  
  CHILE-HEADS ARCHIVES
  
  From the Chile-Heads recipe list.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe
  Archive, http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
