<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Basic Lomein</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Chinese</cat>
        <cat>Main dish</cat></categories>
      <yield>2</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Dried black mushrooms</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Roast pork</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Celery</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Chinese cabbage</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Bamboo shoots</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Bean sprouts</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Snow peas</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Slices fresh ginger root</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Garlic clove</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Sherry</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Stock (chicken)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Soak dried mushrooms. Slice roast pork, celery, cabbage and bamboo shoots.
  Blanch bean sprouts. Stem snow peas. Shred ginger root and crush garlic.
  Heat oil. Add ginger root and garlic; stir fry to brown lightly. Add pork
  and stir fry a few times. Then add in sherry to blend. Add all vegetables
  except snow peas and stir fry 1 minute more. Add stock and heat quickly.
  Then cook,covered, 3 minutes over medium heat. Stir in snow peas. Combine
  mixture with tossed noodles (*See below) Variations: Substitute cooked
  beef,ham, chicken, duck, crabmeat, lobster or shrimp. You can also add
  shredded green onion to the garlic/ginger mixture. I use Shaoxing wine
  instead of sherry, which is more authentic. *To cook noodles, prepare
  boiling water with a little salt. Add noodles and cook until barely done.
  Drain and rinse with cold water to stop cooking. Separate noodles with a
  fork, then toss them with a little sesame oil or peanut oil and set aside
  until they are ready to go into your stir-fry for the final heat. You will
  want about a pound of noodles for the above recipe. This recipe is simply a
  guideline for a dish that can be varied in a thousand ways!
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
