<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Basic Crepes</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Digest</cat>
        <cat>Dec.</cat>
        <cat>Fatfree</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg substitutes</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Rice milk</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Whole wheat pastry flour or</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Unbleached white flour</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Put all ingredients in a blender or food processor and blend at high speed
  for 1 min.  Refrigerate, covered for 2 hrs. before cooking. Batter should
  have consistency of heavy cream. If necessary, thin with more liquid.
  
  To cook crepes, heat an omelet or crepe pan on low heat for a few minutes.
  No need to add oil, these cook fine without it. Remove from heat, pour in 3
  or 4 tablespoons of batter and tilt pan so batter coats the bottom. Put pan
  on burner, cook crepe for a few minutes over medium low heat until lightly
  browned or batter begins to bubble. Flip crepe over and cook other side for
  about 30 sec.  Gently remove and place on a plate. Repeat process with
  remaining batter, stacking crepes as they're cooked. Use with favorite
  breakfast, dinner or dessert crepe filling.
  
  Note:  I didn't notice this until I started typing this in, but I didn't
  cook mine on med-low heat.  I heated my pan on med-high and turned it down
  a notch when ready to cook. They turned out fine, didn't stick and the
  edges were just a little crispy (the way I like 'em).
  
  Posted by "Von Balson, Kathleen" &lt;VBalson@IT.jea.ci.jax.fl.us&gt; to Fatfree
  Digest [Volume 13 Issue 21] Dec. 22, 1994.
  
  FATFREE Recipe collections copyrighted by Michelle Dick 1994. Used with
  permission. Formatted by Sue Smith, S.Smith34, TXFT40A@Prodigy.com using
  MMCONV.
  
  1.80รก
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/fatfreex.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
