<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Basic Cheesecake Filling</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Polkadot</cat>
        <cat>Faylen</cat>
        <cat>Cakes</cat>
        <cat>Info</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>To 2 lb cream cheese</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Powdered sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>To 3 eggs</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Yogurt or sour cream</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Liqueur or fruit/vegetable puree</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Vanilla</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Or more other flavored extracts, if desired</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Here's where it gets fun.  The more cream cheese you use, the denser the
  cheesecake will be (but not dry!)  The more eggs you use, the fluffier it
  will be.  There's a delicate balance here - 1 lb cheese and 3 eggs will
  give you a fluffy cheesecake, but if you use 2 lbs cheese, 3 eggs is an
  absolute must if you don't want it to be flat. More eggs than 3, and you'll
  taste the eggs.  1 lb cheese and 2 eggs is a nice balance, too, but going
  any lower than that you'll just end up with something flat.
  
  The powdered sugar works best for two reasons - number one, powdered sugar
  contains corn starch, which acts as a thickener, and number two, you don't
  have to worry about the grittiness of undissolved sugar in your cake. The
  yogurt or sour cream adds moistness and a little bit of tang to the cake.
  It's not necessary, but it adds oomph to either a bland cake or a
  citrus-flavored cake.  For liqueur, add no more than 1/2 cup if you're
  using the yogurt or sour cream, and make sure you're using the three eggs.
  If you eliminate the yogurt/sour cream, you can increase the liqueur to 3/4
  cup, and 2 eggs will work (but three is still better - two works best only
  if you're not using the yogurt/sour cream &gt;and&lt; your liqueur is only 1/2
  cup.)  A fruit or vegetable puree should be relatively dry - drain off the
  liquid in a sieve, or put it in a saucepan, mix in some cornstarch, and
  heat it until it's thick. You can use an entire cup of puree if you
  eliminate the yogurt/sour cream. Either mix in the puree with the batter,
  or reserve a cup or so of batter, mix it with the puree, then swirl it into
  the cheesecake.
  
  The vanilla is a must, in my opinion.  Lots of times, I'll throw in an
  extra teaspoon for good measure.  Other extracts can enhance the flavor -
  banana extract in a strawberry cheesecake, coconut extract or almond
  extract in an Amaretto cheesecake, etc.
  
  Another addition would be cocoa or chocolate.  Cocoa mixes in nicely
  without making the cheesecake gooey - 4-6 Tbsp will do it.  Melted
  chocolate or white chocolate chips shouldn't really exceed 6 oz, even 4 oz
  will usually do enough for the flavor.  If you're doing the swirl thing,
  use only 2-3 oz melted chocolate for the batter that's being swirled in.
  Make sure the melted stuff is cooled before you mix it in.
  
  (see also Basic Cheesecake Crust and Basic Cheesecake Method &amp; Toppings)
  
  * The Polka Dot Palace BBS 1-201-822-3627.  Posted by FAYLEN
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest V1 #703 by Lisa Clarke &lt;lisa@gaf.com&gt; on Aug 1,
  9
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
