<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Basic Easy Crust</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Bread</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>All-purpose flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Margarine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Crisco lard</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>White vinegar (up to)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ice water</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>    This is a very easy yet flaky piecrust. I use a pastry blender, for me an
  absolute must. Some people get away with blending with a fork, but I rarely
  have any luck doing this. In the old days lard was used instead of the
  lighter shortenings that we have now. Lard does make a delicious crust, but
  it is really hard on the old heart. I suggest the following:
  
    In a medium-size bowl stir the flour and salt together. Cut in the
  shortenings using a pastry blender. Keep working the flour and shortening
  until the mixture is rather grainy, like coarse cornmeal. Mix the egg and
  vinegar together and, using a wooden fork, stir the mixture into the flour.
  Add enough ice water so that the dough barely holds together. Place on a
  marble pastry board or a plastic countertop and knead for just a few turns,
  enough so that the dough holds together and becomes rollable.
  
    I roll my dough out on a piece of waxed paper. It is easy to handle that
  way. If you have a marble rolling pin this will be easy. If you use a
  wooden one be sure to dust a teaspoon of flour on it a couple of times when
  you are rolling the dough.
  
  NOTE: If you wish to use this recipe for a fruit or sweet pie simply stir
  in 1 tablespoon of sugar along with the flour and salt. This recipe will
  make enough dough for one 9-inch pie with two crusts, top and bottom.
  
  From &lt;The Frugal Gourmet Cooks American&gt;.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe
  Archive, http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
