<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Basic Icebox Sugar Cookies</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>All-purpose flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Baking soda</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/8</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Stick margarine; softened</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2/3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Granulated sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Vanilla extract</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>large</unit></amt>
        <item>Egg white</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Cooking spray</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  (Cooking Light)
  
  1. Combine the first 3 ingredients in a bowl, and set aside. Beat margarine
  at medium speed of a mixer until light and fluffy. Gradually add sugar,
  beating at medium speed of a mixer until well-blended. Add vanilla and egg
  white, and beat well. Add flour mixture, and stir until well-blended. Turn
  dough out onto wax paper, and shape into a 6-inch log. Wrap log in wax
  paper, and freeze for 3 hours or until very firm.
  
  2. Preheat oven to 350°.
  
  3. Cut log into 24 (1/4-inch) slices, and place slices 1 inch apart on a
  baking sheet coated with cooking spray. (For slicing, they recmmend either
  using dental floss, or a sharp knife). Bake at 350° for 8 to 10 minutes.
  Remove from pan, and cool on wire racks. Yield: 2 dozen (serving size: 1
  cookie).
  
  Variations: CHOCOLATE ICEBOX COOKIES: Reduce flour to 3/4 cup and add 1/4
  cup unsweetened cocoa powder with the dry ingredients.
  
  PEANUT BUTTER ICEBOX COOKIES: Reduce margarine to 3 Tablespoons, add 2TB
  peanut butter, and change the 2/3 cup sugar to 1/2 cup brown sugar +
      1/4    cup granulated sugar.
  
  BROWN SUGAR ICEBOX COOKIES: Instead of the granulated sugar, use 2/3 cup
  brown sugar.
  
  LEMON-CORNMEAL ICEBOX COOKIES: Reduce flour to 3/4 cup and add 1/4 cup
  yellow cornmeal with the dry ingredients. Also, increase the 2/3 cup
  granulated sugar to 3/4 cup, and add 2 tsp grated lemon rind with the wet
  ingredients.
  
  There are even additional variations listed in the magazine under each of
  the above categories which I won't include - but they all sound yummy! I
  highly recommend this double issue - thumb through it at the store. I am
  not affiliated with Cooking Light, I'm just a happy subscriber.
  
  CALORIES 59 (31% from fat); FAT 2g (sat 0.4g, mono 0.8g, poly 0.6g);
  PROTEIN 0.7g; CARB 9.6g; FIBER 0.1g; CHOL 0mg; IRON 0.2mg; SODIUM 50mg;
  CALC 2mg
  Posted to Digest eat-lf.v097.n296 by Darby Stanfill
  &lt;dstanfill@integrityonline.com&gt; on Nov 21, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
