<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Basic Tamales</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Meat</cat></categories>
      <yield>8</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>24</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Dried corn husks</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Lard</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Masa harina mix</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Warm pork or poultry broth filling (turkey in green mole sauce or pork in red tomato sauce--see recipes)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  This is a simplified recipe for tamales but they still should have a fairly
  authentic taste.
  
  To soak corn husks, cover with warm water; weigh down.  Let soak at least 3
  hours or overnight.
  
  For tamale dough: Beat lard and salt until fluffy.  Slowly beat in masa
  harina mix alternately with broth until very light and fluffy.
  
  To assemble tamales: Drain corn husks, pat dry.  Spread 2 tablespoons dough
  on center of husks forming a 3 x 2-inch rectangle and spreading copletely
  to right edge.
  
  Spoon 1 tablespoon filling lengthwise down center of rectangle.  For
  fillings, see recipes "Turkey in green mole sauce" or "Pork in red tomato
  sauce".
  
  To enclose tamales, turn right side over to center of filling; fold left
  side over filling, allowing plain part of husk to wrap around filling. Fold
  top end down over bottom end.  Secure ends by tying a string around center
  of tamale.
  
  To steam tamales, place a rack 2 inches above gently boiling water in
  steamer or 4-quart dutch oven.  Stack tamales, folded side down, on rack.
  Cover, steam about 2 hours or until done.  To test for doneness, remove one
  tamale from center and one from side of steamer.  Open husks; tamales
  should be firm and come away easily from husk. Makes 24.
  
  ARIELLE@TARONGA.COM
  
  (STEPHANIE DA SILVA)
  
  REC.FOOD.RECIPES
  
  From rec.food.cooking archives.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
