<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Basic White Bread #3</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Bread</cat></categories>
      <yield>12</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>packages</unit></amt>
        <item>Active dry yeast</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Milk</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Vvater</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Oil or butter</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Date: Tue, 07 May 1996 10:55:21 -0400
  
  From: theservs@gate.net (Thomas E. Haug)
  QUICK MIX METHOD: Combine 2 cups flour, yeast, sugar, and salt in a large
  mixing bowl.  Heat milk, water, and 2 tablespoons oil in a saucepan over
  low heat until very warm (120 to 130F). Add liquid to flour mixture; beat
  on high speed of elec- tric mixer until smooth, about 3 minutes. Gradually
  stir in more flour to make a soft dough. Tum onto lightly floured surface
  and knead until smooth and elastic (5 to 10 minutes). Cover dough with bowl
  or pan; let rest 20 minutes. For two loaves, divide dough in half and roll
  out two 14x7-inch rectangles; for one loaf roll out to 16x8-inch rectangle.
  Roll up from narrow side, pressing dough into roll at each turn. Press ends
  to seal and fold under loaf. Place in 2 greased 8x4x2-inch loaf pans or 1
  greased 9x5x3-inch loaf pan; brush with oil. Let rise in warm place until
  double in bulk (30 to 45 minutes). Bake at 400F 35 to 40 minutes. Remove
  from pans immediately and brush with oil; cool on wire rack.
  
  CONVENTIONAL METHOD: Heat milk, sugar, oil, and salt; cool to lukewarm. In
  a large bowl, sprinkle yeast in warm water (105 to 115F) stir until
  dissolved. Add lukewarm milk mixture and 2 cups flour; beat until smooth.
  Beat in enough additional flour to make a stiff dough. Turn out onto
  lightly floured surface; let rest 10 to 15 minutes. Knead until smooth and
  elastic (8 to 10 minutes). Place in a greased bowl, turning to grease top.
  Cover; let rise in warm place until double in bulk (about 1 hour). Punch
  down. Let rest 15 minutes. Follow same shaping and baking instructions as
  Quick Mix Method.
  
  MM-RECIPES@IDISCOVER.NET
  
  MEAL-MASTER RECIPES LISTSERVER
  
  MM-RECIPES DIGEST V3 #129
  
  From the MealMaster recipe list.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
