<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Basic Pita</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Breads</cat>
        <cat>Ceideburg 2</cat></categories>
      <yield>24</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Warm water (90 to 100 degrees F.)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Envelopes active dry yeast</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>5</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>To 5 1/2 cups unbleached all-purpose flour, plus flour for kneading</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Pour the water into a large bowl, sprinkle in the yeast and stir to
  dissolve.  Stir the sugar and salt into the yeast mixture thoroughly
  with a wooden spoon.  Gradually add 5 cups of the flour, stirring
  constantly until the dough is smooth.  Slowly work in the remaining
  flour with your hands, kneading until the dough is no longer sticky.
  Turn the dough out onto a well floured board and knead until smooth
  and elastic, about 5 minutes.
  
  Shape the dough into an even rectangle and cut in half, lengthwise.
  Divide each half into 12 portions for small pitas, 6 for larger ones.
  
  Shape each into a smooth ball.  Place balls on a floured surface and
  cover them with a slightly damp towel while you roll out one at a
  time. Gently press each ball flat with your fingers, keeping it well
  rounded. Flour a work surface and a rolling pin.  Roll each round
  from the center to the outside edge, giving the dough a 1/4 turn
  after each roll, to form a perfect circle not quite 1/4-inch thick (5
  to 5 1/2 inches in diameter for small pitas; about 8 1/2 inches for
  larger ones).
  
  Carefully flip the circles over to smooth out any creases that might
  prevent the pockets from forming.
  
  Fifteen minutes before the loaves have finished rising, preheat the
  oven to 500F and place an ungreased baking sheet in the oven to heat.
  As each bread is rolled, place it carefully on a floured surface and
  cover with a clean, dry towel; do not let the surfaces dry out, and
  let rise in a warm, draft-free area for 30 to 45 minutes.
  
  To bake, place 4 small pitas or I large one on the hot baking sheet.
  Bake on the bottom rack of the oven until puffed and lightly browned
  on the bottom, almost white on top, about 4 minutes for small pitas
  and about 3 1/2 minutes for large; the pita will be soft and
  flexible.  If desired, flip the loaves over after they have puffed
  and bake for up to 1 minute longer to brown tops; be VERY careful not
  to let pita get crisp and brittle.
  
  Remove hot pitas from oven and wrap immediately in clean, dry towels
  until cool enough to handle.  Serve warm or at room temperature.
  Repeat baking process until all breads are baked.
  
  Makes 24 small or 12 large pitas.
  
  From "Pita the Great"
  
  From the San Francisco Chronicle, 8/10/88.
  
  Posted by Stephen Ceideberg; November 10 1992.
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/cberg2.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
