<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Basic Soda Bread</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Cake or All-purpose Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Granulated Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Bicarbonate of Soda</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>8</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Buttermilk; (up to 10)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Two main factors have long affected the historic course of Irish bread
  making. The first is related to the climate, in that this land is greatly
  influenced by the gulf Stream to the extent that it is neither hot in the
  summer nor cold in the winter. Hence, the forty shades of green and the
  fact that traditional hard wheats utilized in bread baking do not grow
  well.
  
  At least in the last millennium, Ireland has been relatively plentiful in
  fuel for baking. Various medieval overlords of Ireland were never able to
  exercise tight control over the forest land so firewood could be freely
  poached. As a result, anyone with a hearthstone could afford to bake on a
  small scale.
  
  In Ireland plain soda bread is as likely to be served as a accompaniment to
  a main meal in order to soak up the gravy as it's likely to appear with the
  breakfast in a fry. Soda bread comes in white or brown varieties and is
  served as a cake or a farl, based on regional differences. We'll being
  including all the various Soda Bread variations during our All-Irish
  Cooking month at Recipe-a-Day!
  
  Sift the dry ingredients together several times in a large mixing bowl to
  make sure the bicarbonate of soda is evenly distributed. Create a well in
  the center of the dry ingredients and a pour about three-quarters of the
  buttermilk into the center and start stirring. Continue to mix until you
  achieve a dough that is raggy and very soft. Add more buttermilk sparingly
  is you need it, as local conditions of humidity and temperature greatly
  impact the mixture.
  
  Blend quickly, but not too energetically until the whole mass of dough has
  become a floury, raggy consistency. Turn the contents of the bowl out onto
  a lightly floured surface and start to knead the bread.
  
  Your primary concern is speed in kneading. The chemical reaction of the
  bicarbonate of soda with the acidic buttermilk starts as soon as they meet.
  You need to get the Soda Bread into the oven while the reactions running
  high, so don't over knead. Spend about 30-seconds kneading the dough and
  shape the bread into a slightly domed circle about 6 to 8-inches in
  diameter. Place the dough on a baking sheet that has been lightly dusted
  with flour and use a sharp knife to cut across the circle making sure the
  cut goes about halfway down through the sides of the circle of dough so
  that it will flower properly.
  
  Bake for about 10-minutes in a 350-F to 400-F Degree pre-heated oven, then
  decrease the heat and continue to bake another 30 to 35-minutes until you
  can tap the loaf and a hallowish sound is produced.
  
  For a crunchy crust place the cooked cake on the rack to cool. For a softer
  crust, wrap the cake in a clean dishcloth and store as soon as it’s out of
  the oven. Either way, the soda bread is wonderful sliced or split and
  served hot with sweet butter and the jelly or jam of your choice.
  
  Posted to dailyrecipe@recipe-a-day.com by The Cook &amp; Kitchen Staff
  &lt;dailyrecipe-owner@recipe-a-day.com&gt; on Mar 03, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
