<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Bavarian Stuffed Cabbage Rolls with Onion Sauce</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>6 -8</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>medium</unit></amt>
          <item>Head Cabbage</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>FILLING</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Soy meat; (beef flavor) finely chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>small</unit></amt>
          <item>Onion; diced</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Egg</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>slices</unit></amt>
          <item>White bread</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Milk</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Rice; (brown or white), cooked</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>pinch</unit></amt>
          <item>Pepper</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Salt to taste; ( approximately 1/3 tsp.)</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>SAUCE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Butter or margarine</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Big onion; (1 cup diced)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2 1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Cabbage stock</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Caraway seeds</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>pinch</unit></amt>
          <item>Pepper</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/3</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt or to taste</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Cut the core out of the cabbage. Fill a large pot half-full with water and
  bring to a boil. Put the cabbage with the core-side down into the water.
  Boil for a few minutes, then turn head around so core-side is up. Start to
  carefully remove the outer leaves with a pair of tongs. Try to leave the
  leaves as whole and undamaged as possible. The stem of the leaves should be
  soft enough to roll. Remove about 16-18 leaves and set aside on a plate.
  Leave the rest of the cabbage simmering for about 20 minutes to get the
  stock for the sauce.
  
  Filling: Soak the bread in the milk. Combine soy meat, rice, egg, soaked
  bread, onion, salt and pepper in a blender and mix well to get a thick
  paste. Spread one cabbage leaf out on the table in front of you with the
  stem end towards you. Take 1-2 tablespoons of the filling and place it on
  the stem end. Carefully roll up the cabbage leaf folding in the sides as
  well. Put seam facing down in a baking dish. Roll up all the cabbage leaves
  this way and place tightly next to each other in the dish. Set aside.
  
  Sauce: Melt margarine or butter in a heavy saucepan. Add onions and saut=82
  until golden brown. Add flour and stir continuously until the flour is
  roasted and a light brown color. Add the cabbage stock and the spices and
  bring to a boil. Simmer for a few minutes. The consistency should be thin.
  If needed, add more stock. Pour this sauce over the cabbage rolls in the
  baking dish. Put in a preheated oven at 300=F8F. Bake until the cabbage is
  tender and golden brown. Serve with parslied potatoes and apple sauce.
  
        2    hours to prepare.
  
  Source: Zorba the Buddha Cafe at http://osho.org/news/zorba/
  Posted to MM-Recipes Digest  by "Kathleen Weber" &lt;momqat@ibm.net&gt; on May
  04, 98
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
