<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Bavarian Roast Suckling Pig Part 2</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Meats</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>See below</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Lay pig on a rack or across two long wooden inverted spoons in open
  roasting pan. Pour in enough water to cover bottom of pan. To keep
  pig well greased as it roasts, either brush it every 10 to 15 minutes
  with melted buttr or bacon fat, or lay strips of bacon across its
  back and replace them as they become crisp; or rub pig with a large,
  unsliced chunk of bacon. Place pig in a preheated oven and allow 25
  to 30 minutes per pound for roasting, using either seaing or even-
  temperature method described above. Brush or rub with fat every 10 to
  15 minutes and add more water to pan as needed. When you baste, prick
  skin again to keep fat draining. If pig browns too quicky, cover it
  with greased brown paper or a double thickness of aluminum foil and
  lift this cover for basting. When there is till 1/2 hour cooking time
  left, remove paper from ears and tail, and from pig itself if it has
  been covered. Continue roasting and basted 4 or 5 times with beer to
  give skin a crisp golden glaze.
  
  To serve pig, cut trussing from legs and place pig on a large wooden
  carving board or platter. Remove the block or potato from mouth and
  put in a whole small apple or unpeeled lemon. Show whole pig at the
  table, but unless you are very skilled and experienced, carve in
  kitchen. If you want to carve it at the table, cut a circle around
  the neck, and cover this with a wreath of leaves or, at Christmas,
  holly.
  
  In Bavaria, a very simple gravy is served with this. Skim excess fat
  from pan juices and add some water or stock if there is very little
  gravy left. Bring to a boil in roasting pan on stove and scrape
  coagulated pan juices into gravy with a wooden spoon. Thicken by
  stirring in flour or cornstarch dissolved in cold water and simmer
  for 3 to 5 minutes, or until sauce is smooth and thick. Sour cream
  can be stirred in for creamier sauce. Season as needed and serve in
  heated sauceboat.
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/mmkah001.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
