<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Be Mine Buttermilk Cake (2 of 2)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Desserts</cat>
        <cat>Cakes</cat>
        <cat>Holiday</cat></categories>
      <yield>8</yield></head>
    <ingredients/>
    <directions>
      <step>   For Truffle Cream: Stir chocolate cream and butter in
  heavy medium saucepan over low heat until chocolate
  and butter meld and mixture is smooth. Mix in
  Chambord. Let stand at room temperature till very
  thick and spreadable, stirring occasionally, about 2
  hours.
   For Cake: Position rack in center of oven and preheat
  to 350 degrees F. Butter 9-inch heart-shaped pan with
  1-1/4-inch-high sides. Dust with flour; tap out excess.
  Sift first 4 ingredients into medium bowl. Using
  electric mixer at high speed, beat sugar and butter in
  large bowl till fluffy. Add yolks 1 at a time, beating
  just to combine after each addition. Using rubber
  spatula, mix in dry ingredients alternately with
  buttermilk, beginning and ending with dry ingredients.
  Transfer batter to prepared pan. Bake cake till tester
  inserted into center comes out clean, about 35 mins.
  Turn out cake onto rack and cool. Cut cake
  horizontally in half. Place botttom layer of cake on
  plate. Spread truffle cream over. Arrange top layer
  over and press gently to adhere. Using spatula, smooth
  cream on sides of cake if necessary. Chill until set,
  at least 1 hour. For Glaze: Stir chocolate and butter
  in heavy med. saucepan over lo heat till melted &amp;
  smooth Remove from heat. Add corn syrup and liqueur &amp;
  whisk till smooth. Let glaze stand till slightly
  thickened, stirring occasionally, about 30 minutes.
  Place cake on rack set over baking sheet or large
  piece of foil. Pour glaze over cake, coating
  completely. Chill cake on rack till glaze is set,
  about 30 mins. Transfer cake to platter. (Can be made
  1 day ahead. Cover with cake dome &amp; chill. Bring to
  room temp before serving.)
  Reformatted by: CYGNUS, HCPM52C
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
