<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Bean Lasagne</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Digest</cat>
        <cat>Sept.</cat>
        <cat>Fatfree</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>can</unit></amt>
        <item>Ff vegetarian refried beans</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>12 oz bottle mild taco</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Sauce</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cans</unit></amt>
        <item>Stewed tomatoes, one</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Drained, one not</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Ff cottage cheese</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Corn kernels, frozen is ok</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>10</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>To 12 lasagne noodles,</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Uncooked</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Black olives, sliced</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  In a bowl mix beans with about half the juice from one can of tomatoes and
  a couple of tablespoons of taco sauce. You want the beans to be almost but
  not quite pourable. Mix the rest of the taco sauce and tomato juice and set
  aside.
  
  Put about a quarter of the taco sauce mixture in the bottom of a 9x13"
  lasagne pan. Cover sauce with a layer of noodles. Layer, in any order you
  want, the beans, corn, cheese, drained tomatoes, sauce and noodles, being
  sure to end up with enough beans to cover the top with no noodles showing.
  The resulting mess should be pretty wet.
  
  Cover tightly with foil.  Bake at 350 for about an hour, until the noodles
  are tender. Check every 5-10 minutes after 45 minutes of cooking to see how
  the noodles are doing. Remove foil, sprinkle with olives. Bake another
  couple of minutes. Let sit for about 5 minutes before serving.
  
  Serves 3-4 as a main dish. Tastes even better the next day.
  
  Variation: If you want to pre-cook the noodles, don't use as much tomato
  juice and cook for only about 30 minutes.
  
  Variation: Other veggies would work well in here too. What do you have in
  the frig?
  
  Variation: You could top it with a little ff cheese-stuff in the last few
  minutes. And no doubt you could make it vegan by leaving off all milk
  products altogether.
  
  From Katherine Albitz, kra@sdd.hp.com. Fatfree Digest [Volume 10 Issue 23],
  Sept. 2, 1994. Formatted by Sue Smith, S.Smith34, TXFT40A@Prodigy.com using
  MMCONV.
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/fatfreex.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
