<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Bean Curd and Spinach Soup with Rice</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Asian</cat>
        <cat>Soups</cat>
        <cat>Tofu</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Bean thread noodles -or-</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Cooked rice; or less</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh spinach</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>8</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Tofu Mori-nu lite firm</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>quart</unit></amt>
        <item>Chicken stock or vegetable stock</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Soy sauce</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Rice wine or dry sherry</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  INTRO: Serves 4. This simple but delicious and nutritious soup is one you
  would often find on the table in China. Use soft bean curd: its
  custard-like texture and mild flavor works with the sugar to neutralize the
  metallic edge of the spinach. The bean thread noodles give substance to
  this warming dish.
  
  PREP: Soak the noodles in a large bowl of warm water for 15 minutes. When
  soft, drain them and discard the water. Cut the noodles into 3-inch lengths
  using scissors or a knife. Remove the stalks from the spinach and wash the
  leaves well. Gently cut the bean curd into 1-inch cubes.
  
  Put the stock into a saucepan and bring to a simmer. Add the bean thread
  noodles and simmer for 2 minutes. Add the spinach and the rest of the
  ingredients except the bean curd. Simmer for 2 minutes, then gently put in
  the bean curd. Continue to simmer the soup for 2 more minutes to heat the
  bean curd through and serve at once.
  
  Source: Asian Vegetarian Feast (HardCover 1988) by Ken Hom. William Morrow
  and Company, Inc. New York. ISBN: 0-688-07753-6. Reprint: trade paper 1997.
  Original Title: Soft Bean Curd and Spinach Soup
  
  dec 1997 kitpatH and Buster VARIATION: Substitute 3/4 cup cooked rice for
  the noodles. We served with a Thai Garlic Pepper Sauce, reminded us of
  hot-sour soup. With rice: PER SERVING: 179 cals, 2.5 g fat (13.4% cff)
  
  Recipe by: Asian Vegetarian Feast (1988) Ken Hom
  
  Posted to Digest eat-lf.v097.n312 by KitPATh &lt;phannema@wizard.ucr.edu&gt; on
  Dec 08, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
