<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Beau's Sweet-Sour Chicken Wings</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Appetizers</cat>
        <cat>Family</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>20</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Chicken wings</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>7 1/2</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Tomato sauce (half can)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Orange marmalade</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Honey</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ginger, minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Fermented chili sauce (Summit brand)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Pepper vinegar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Garlic cloves, peeled</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt (scant)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>MSG</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Water (more as needed)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit>dashes</unit></amt>
        <item>Tabasco, to taste (or other hot pepper sauc )</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Cut off spurs from chicken wing-tips and rinse chicken wings. Place in
  pressure cooker with water; bring to pressure and cook at high heat for up
  to five minutes. Remove from pressure cooker and place cooked-out fat in
  wide-mouthed, tapered jar for other uses.
  
  Blend all ingredients except chicken and Tabasco (or hot sauce) until
  fairly even consistency, with no large chunks of ginger or garlic.
  
  Place 3/4 of sauce in pan.  Roll wings in sauce; remove wings to broiler
  pan (with slotted top).  Bake at 325 degrees F. for 20 minutes. Remove from
  oven and spoon about half of remaining sauce on top of each piece; broil
  for 5 minutes.  Add Tabasco or other hot pepper sauces to taste and serve.
  
  Beau's notes:
  
  *  Use vinegar "which has been used to keep a supply of bird's-eye
  peppers."
  
  *  After discarding chicken spurs, wash hands with very warm water and Dial
  soap (and follow up with isopropyl alcohol rinse); wash all utensils with
  bleach.  (One should always regard chickens, even if processed in USA or
  inspected by USDA, as unclean! USDA inspectors are notoriously less than
  thorough, and U.S. packing houses often neglect basic hygienic rules in
  working with chickens, especially in dealing with their entrails, waste
  products un-excreted, etc. And one should not expect much better from
  out-of-country chickens.)
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
