<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Becky Campbell's Chicken with Carambola</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Fruits</cat>
        <cat>Harned 1994</cat>
        <cat>Main dish</cat>
        <cat>Nuts</cat>
        <cat>Poultry</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>3.5 to 4 lb. chicken cut in pieces</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Olive oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Lime juice; freshly squeezed</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Limes; minced zest of</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>small</unit></amt>
        <item>Onions peeled and thinly sliced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Mild honey</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh ginger; minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Fresh serrano or jalapeno with seeds; minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Carambola (4 oz. each)* cut in 1/4" thick slices</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Almonds; raw and whole</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>small</unit></amt>
        <item>Cilantro bunch; to garnish</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  *When you buy carambola, also called star fruit, look for ones that are
  uniformly yellow to orange and have a subtle perfume. If they are green,
  they aren't ripe and won't yield a great deal of flavor. At their ripest,
  their flavor is an unmistakably tropical combination of apple, banana and
  lychee.
  
  Rinse chicken well and pat it thoroughly dry.
  
  In a large bowl, whisk together olive oil, lime juice and zest, onions,
  honey, ginger and minced pepper. Stir in three-fourths of the carambola
  slices.  Then add the chicken, and turn it until it is coated with the
  marinade.  Cover and refrigerate overnight, or up to 2 days, turning the
  chicken occasionally so it marinates evenly.
  
  Arrange chicken in a single layer in a 9 x 13" baking dish; season
  generously with salt.  Add almonds to the marinade, stir, and spoon it over
  the chicken.  Bake at 375 F. in the center of the oven, basting frequently
  with pan juices and turning any chicken pieces that get too brown, about 35
  minutes.  Add remaining carambola, stir, and continue cooking until the
  chicken is golden and a thigh yields clear juice when pricked at its
  thickest part, 15 to 20 minutes. Taste the sauce and adjust the seasoning.
  Just before serving, mince the cilantro if you are using it. Serve chicken
  right from the baking dish, or divide among four warmed dinner plates.
  Spoon sauce over the chicken, garnish with cilantro and serve.
  
  This dish can be prepared up to 2 days in advance. Goes well with a
  semi-dry German Kabinett, such as Deirhard 1989.
  
  Loomis writes:  "Becky Campbell became a tropical fruit aficionado through
  the career of her husband, Carl, who is an internationally known tropical
  fruit expert. He researched and taught at the University of Florida, where
  he is now professor emeritus.  She became an expert on cooking with
  tropical fruits, and lectured and taught cooking classes for years.
  Together they developed a small tropical fruit orchard in the backyard of
  their home near Homestead, Florida.
  
  "Becky refers to the tropical fruit orchard that surrounds their
  single-story home as a 'mini experiment station.' Her husband does the
  experimenting, and she brings the bounty into the kitchen. Their orchard
  produces everything from Key limes and carambola to black sapote and
  mangoes.
  
  "Becky and Carl were recently in Uganda, where carambola is as common as
  green grapes are here. There she picked up valuable tips for using the
  lovely star-shaped fruit, and she set out samples for us to taste: golden
  star-shaped slices of dried carambola, carambola leather and carambola
  preserves, where the stars were suspended in a thick sweet syrup. They were
  all delicious."
  
  From _Farm House Cookbook_ by Susan Herrmann Loomis. New York: Workman
  Publishing Company, Inc., 1991.  Pp. 145-146. ISBN 0-89480-772-2.
  Electronic format by Cathy Harned.
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
