<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Beef and Onion Stew</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>France</cat>
        <cat>Main dish</cat>
        <cat>Soups/stews</cat>
        <cat>Beef/veal</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Leftover beef (preferably</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>From Pot-au-feu, or from</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Roast beef) sliced as thinly</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>As possible</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>medium</unit></amt>
        <item>Yellow onions, sliced thinly</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>And separated into rings</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Plus, red wine vinegar, to</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Taste</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Stock, Pot-au-Feu broth, or</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Canned beef broth.</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>small</unit></amt>
        <item>Bay leaf</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Sprig fresh thyme, or sub-</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Stitute 1 t dried.</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Dijon-type mustard, or to</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Taste</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Fresh bread crumbs</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Chopped fresh parsley</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Lemon, juice MIKE'S KITCHEN-</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  This recipe is an excellent use for leftover beef. Though there are several
  variations possible for a Miroton (mushrooms, tomatoes, garlic), the
  predominate flavor is always onions, which are made into a sharp sauce.
  Preferably, the leftover beef will be from a pot-au-few that has been
  tenderized by long poaching, but roast beef can work as well. It will just
  need more baking time. The following is my favorite variation for a
  Miroton:
        Make sure the beef is chilled for easy slicing. Then, slice as thinly
  as possible. Set aside. In a large skillet, melt the butter and lightly
  saute the onions. When golden and very soft, about 10 minutes, sprinkle
  them with enough flour to make a light roux. Stir the mixture thoroughly
  for 2 - 3 minutes before adding the vinegar and mustard. Continue stirring,
  adding enough stock or Pot-au-Feu broth to make a thin sauce. Add the
  spices. Bring the sauce to a boil, then lower heat and simmer for about 30
  minutes.
        Assembly: Pour a layer of sauce into a shallow baking dish. Layer
  meat slices, always overlapping, alternating with more of the sauce. You
  should end up with a final layer of sauce. Bake, covered, in a 350 degree
  oven for half an hour, if meat was originally poached, or for an hour, if
  roast beef. Check to make sure sauce does not reduce too much. Add more
  stock if necessary.
        When preliminary cooking is finished, sprinkle surface of dish with a
  thick coating of fresh bread crumbs. Spoon just enough butter over crumbs
  to moisten them. Return to oven for about 30 more minutes, or until a
  golden crust forms. Sprinkle the top with the parsley to garnish, and
  squeeze over it the juice of half a lemon. Serve at once.
        Variations: Add tomatoes, garlic, and/or mushrooms. Instead of
  vinegar, use a little grated horseradish. In place of some of the stock,
  use wine. This dish is very flexible. It is also economical, but it doesn't
  taste like it!
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/mmdja006.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
