<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Beef Jerky #1</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Beef</cat>
        <cat>Dehydrator</cat>
        <cat>Snacks</cat>
        <cat>Gift</cat></categories>
      <yield>20</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Rump roast (or similar cut)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Light Japanese soy sauce; I use Kikkomon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Worchestershire sauce</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>White vinegar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground ginger</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground red pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground black pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Onion powder</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Clove garlic; smashed</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  have the butcher cut your roast in 1/8 inch slice against the grain. OR do
  it at home. if you don't have good cutlery, have the butcher do it. it
  won't be worth it!
  
  cut off the slice of fat on the bottom. separate the two distinct sinews.
  (you can tell, the grain goes one way on one, and the other way on the
  other). Trim out the "gristle" that is between them. slice the two sinews
  against the grain into 1/8 inch slices.
  
  Mix the soya, and remaining ingredients to make the marinade. Marinade the
  meat slices for 6 or 8 hours in the fridge. (I usually place in a ziploc
  type bag, and place in a bowl--turning a couple of times to be sure all the
  slices get an equal chance at the marinade)
  
  Note: I use the smoke very spareingly, I've used as much as a 1/4 teas. (10
  drops) in this recipe. Any more is too much IMHO. But you might use more if
  you really like smoke, but a little goes a long way. I prefer Japanese
  soya, cuz it's lighter than the Chinese soya. And I get the Light Japanese
  soya, which has significantly less salt. You could add more red pepper if
  you like it spicey or use fresh ginger instead of bottled. If you like it
  sweeter, replace the water with a cup of Vermont maple syrup. Also when
  choosing your roast, the leaner, the better.
  
  Charlotte Welch the cooking librarian
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest V1 #740 by hurlbert &lt;hurlbert@concentric.net&gt; on
  Aug 13, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
