<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Beef Fajitas</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Beef</cat>
        <cat>Mexican</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Grilled marinated Skirt Steak</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Bell Peppers</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Onions</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Flour Tortillas</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>FOR THE MARINADE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>4</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Garlic cloves; minced and mashed to a paste with 1 teaspoon salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Fresh lemon juice</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1 1/2</qty>
            <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Ground cumin</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Olive oil</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
          <item>Skirt steak; trimmed and cut into large pieces to fit on a grill or broiler pan or in a ridged grill pan</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Vegetable oil</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Assorted colored bell peppers, sliced thin</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Red onion; sliced thin</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Garlic cloves; minced</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  twelve 7- to 8-inch flour tortillas (recipe follows or store-bought),
  warmed (procedure follows) guacamole and tomato salsa as accompaniments
  
  Make the marinade: In a large bowl whisk together the garlic paste, the
  lime juice, the cumin, and the oil.
  
  Add the steak to the marinade, turning it to coat it well, and let it
  marinate, covered and chilled, for at least 1 hour or overnight. Grill the
  steak, drained, on a well-oiled rack set about 5 inches over glowing coals
  or in a hot well-seasoned ridged grill pan over moderately high heat for 3
  to 4 minutes on each side, or until it is just springy to the touch, for
  medium-rare meat. (Alternatively, the steak may be broiled on the rack of a
  broiler pan under a preheated broiler about 4 inches from the heat for 3 to
  4 minutes on each side for medium-rare meat.) Transfer the steak to a
  cutting board and let it stand for 10 minutes. While the steak is standing,
  in a large skillet heat the oil over moderately high heat until it is hot
  but not smoking, add the bell peppers, the onion, and the garlic, and sauté
  the mixture, stirring, for 5 minutes, or until the bell peppers are
  softened. Slice the steak thin across the grain on the diagonal and arrange
  the slices on a platter with th! ! ! e bell pepper mixture. Drizzle any
  steak juices over the steak and the pepper mixture and serve the steak and
  the pepper mixture with the tortillas, the guacamole, and the salsa.
  
  To assemble a fajita: Spread some of the guacamole on a tortilla, top it
  with a few slices of the steak, some of the pepper mixture, and some of the
  salsa, and roll up the tortilla to enclose the filling.
  
  TO WARM TORTILLAS
  
  Can be prepared in 45 minutes or less.
  
  In the oven: Stack 6 tortillas at a time, wrap each stack in foil, and heat
  the tortillas in the middle of a preheated 325°F. oven for 5 minutes for
  corn tortillas and 15 minutes for flour tortillas. (If the tortillas are
  very dry to begin with, pat each tortillas between dampened hands before
  stacking them.)
  
  In the microwave: Stack 6 tortillas at time, wrap each stack in a
  microwave-safe plastic bag, and heat the tortillas in a microwave oven at
  high power (100%) for 30 seconds to 1 minute, or until they are heated
  through and pliable.
  
  Makes 12 fajitas, serving 6 &gt;From Jane Butel's cooking school in
  Albuquerque, New Mexico.
  
  Recipe by: From Jane Butel's cooking school in Albuquerque, New Mexico
  
  Posted to recipelu-digest Volume 01 Number 181 by Diane Geary
  &lt;diane@keyway.net&gt; on Oct 29, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
