<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Beef Chili, Texas Style - James Mcnair</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>12</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Round roast; trimmed</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Safflower oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Yellow onion; finely chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Garlic; minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground chili powder; preferable freshly ground from dried ancho or pasilla peppers</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground cumin</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Unbleached flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Salt and pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Cayenne</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Tomato sauce</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Cooked pinto beans</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Quickly rinse the beef under running cold water and pat dry with paper
  towels. Chop the beef with a sharp knife or food processor, or cut it into
  1/2-inch cubes. Reserve.
  
  Heat the oil in a dutch oven or other heavy pot over medium heat. Add the
  onion and cook until soft, about 5 minutes. Add the beef and garlic and
  cook until the meat is just past the pink stage. Add the chili powder,
  cumin, flour, and salt, black pepper, and cayenne to taste; mix well. Stir
  in the tomato sauce, reduce the heat, and simmer, uncovered, until the
  flavors are well-blended, about 1 hour. Stir in the cooked beans, if using,
  the last 20 minutes of cooking. Add a little water to the pot anytime
  during the cooking if the mixture begins to dry out.
  
  Serves 12.
  
  NOTES : "This easy yet tasty version comes from my sister Martha, who wraps
  it in warm tortillas with an array of toppings (grated jack cheese, chopped
  red onion, chopped tomato, chopped cilantro, shredded lettuce, salsa). It
  is also good served in bowls with the garnishes passed."
  Recipe by: Beef - James McNair
  
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest V1 #1009 by KSBAUM &lt;KSBAUM@aol.com&gt; on Jan 14,
  1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
