<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Beef Fajitas #1</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Meat</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Beef skirt steaks</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Flour tortillas</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>MEAT MARINADE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Olive or other vegetable oil</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Fresh lime juice (or a combination lime juice and white vinegar)</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Pepper to taste</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Minced garlic or garlic</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>ACCOMPANIMENTS</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Salsa</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Raw sliced onions</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Shredded mild cheese</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Diced tomatoes</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Shredded lettuce</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Sour cream</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>   First, marinate the skirt steaks in the oil/lime juice mixture as
  described above. Overnight in the refrigerator works well using a ziploc
  bag.  The amount of marinade depends on the amount of meat. [The lime juice
  imparts an incredibly sweet and fresh taste to the meat; you will love the
  effect.]
  
   Prepare your accompaniments and have them ready for guests to use
  according to their own preferences. Some people fry onions (instead of
  using them raw) and others cook some green pepper as accompaniments. I
  personally think that this detracts from a simple fresh taste, but hey this
  is food, not medicine...
  
   Grill the fajitas outside (over wood charcoal if you can get it)-- over a
  medium hot fire this will require about 10 minutes a side.  After grilling,
  allow the skirt steaks to sit for a couple of minutes, then slice across
  the grain in relatively thin slices.
  
   Warm the flour torillas slightly (microwave will do nicely if you aren't a
  purist).
  
   Allow people to assemble the fajitas themselves:  slices of meat rolled in
  the torillas together with accompaniments of their choice.  You may also
  want to have some hot pepper sauce and cilantro also at the ready.
  
   This is a "can't lose" company dish; the meat when re-heated tastes good
  as left-overs as well.
  
   NOTE:  Beef skirt steaks (you may have to ask the butcher for these
  outside the Southwest; they are inexpensive and readily available in the
  prime fajita areas of the country such as Texas) [Note that you can use
  flank steak if forced to but it just doesn't taste the same.] Michael
  Karchmer MAKARCHMER@gallua.gallaudet.EDU
  
  AT986@FREENET.CARLETON.CA
  
  (WARD TOMLINSON)
  
  REC.FOOD.RECIPES
  
  From rec.food.cooking archives.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive,
  http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
