<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Vindaloo (Goan-Style Hot and Sour Pork)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Indian</cat>
        <cat>Ethnic</cat>
        <cat>Spicy</cat>
        <cat>Main dish</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Whole cumin seeds</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Black pepper corns</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>In stick cinnamon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Fenugreek seeds</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>5</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Vegetable oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>One in cube ginger chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground coriander seeds</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Hot, dried red chilies</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Cardamom seeds</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Black mustard seeds</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>5</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>White wine vinegar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Brown sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Medium onions cut into rings</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Pork cut into 1" cubes</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>8</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Cloves garlic peeled</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Turmeric</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Grind cumin seeds,  red chilies,  peppercorns, cardamom seeds, cinnamon,
  black  mustard  seeds and fenugreek seeds in a coffee-grinder  or  other
  spice grinder.   Put the ground spices in a bowl.  Add the vinegar, salt
  and sugar.  Mix and set aside.
  Heat  the  oil in a wide,  heavy pot over a medium flame.   Put  in  the
  onions.   Fry,  stirring  frequently,  until  the onions turn brown  and
  crisp.   Remove  the onions with a slotted spoon and put them  into  the
  container  of  an  electric blender or food processor.   (Turn  off  the
  heat.)   Add  2-3  tablespoons of water to the  blender  and  puree  the
  onions.   Add this puree to the ground spices in the bowl.  (This is the
  vindaloo paste.  It may be made ahead of time and frozen.)
  Dry  off  the meat cubes with a paper towel and remove large  pieces  of
  fat, if any.
  Put  the ginger and garlic into the container of an electric blender  or
  food processor.  Add 2-3 tablespoons of water and blend until you have a
  smooth paste.
  Heat  the oil remaining in the pot once again over a medium-high  flame.
  When hot, put in the pork cubes, a few at a time, and brown them lightly
  on  all  sides.   Remove each batch with a slotted spoon and keep  in  a
  bowl.   Do all the pork this way.   Now put the ginger-garlic paste into
  the same pot.   Turn down the heat to medium.   Stir the paste for a few
  seconds.  Add the coriander and turmeric.  Stir for another few seconds.
  Add  the  meat,  any  juices that may have accumulated as  well  as  the
  vindaloo paste and the water.  Bring to a boil.  Cover and simmer gently
  for  an  hour  or until port is tender.   Stir a few times  during  this
  cooking period.  Serve with rice.
  
  From the TWSU BBS, 316-689-3779, C. Burdsal, SYSOP
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/mmindian.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
