<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Virginia's Easy Lasagne 8 Servings</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Hamburger</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Or two jars speghetti sauce with garden vegetables already in the jar which saves you adding them) my little change</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Ricotta cheese; (large carton) or large small curd cottage cheese)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Shredded mozzarella cheese; (I used more)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Parmesan cheese</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Eggs; (or one if 2 eggs would make filling too moist)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Chopped fresh parsley; (I used more)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>6</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Uncooked Lasagne noodles; (my notes follow)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  I added 1/2 tsp nutmeg to filling
  
  I added cooked spinach mixed in with the ricotta or cottage cheese mixture
  
  Can brown chopped onion with mince
  
  Can add Italian seasonings to HB and sauce
  
  In large sauce pan (I used a heavy soup pot.) brown HB in a little oil,
  drain. (second time I was in a hurry and did it 5 minutes on high in
  microwave, breaking up meat clods and draining) Add spaghetti sauce and
  water to soup pot. Simmer on stove for 10 minutes.
  
  In bowl, mix together ricotta, (or cottage cheese) one half the mozzarella
  cheese, parmesan cheese, egg(s), parsley, salt and pepper, (squeeze dry
  cooked spinach if using it) Pour about one cup of sauce on bottom of 13 x 9
  inch baking dish.
  
  Arrange 3 UNCOOKED pasta pieces lengthwise over sauce; cover with about I
  cup of sauce. Spread one-half the cottage cheese filling over the sauce.
  Repeat layers of lasagna, sauce and rest of cottage cheese filling. Top
  with layer of lasagna and remaining sauce. Sprinkle with remaining
  mozzarella cheese. Cover with silver foil. Bake 45 minutes at 180. Remove
  foil and bake an additional 15 minutes. Let stand before slicing it into 10
  to 12 servings.
  
  Posted to TNT Recipes Digest by Rayna Knighton &lt;rayna@mail.iconz.co.nz&gt; on
  Mar 13, 1998
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
