<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Walker's Red Hot Chile Con Carne (1918)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Chile peppe</cat>
        <cat>Chili</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Beef; cut in small pieces</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Beef suet; ground fine or lard</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Walker's Mexene</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>medium</unit></amt>
        <item>Onion; minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  In 1918, Walker Austex was producing 45,000 cans of Walker's Red Hot Chile
  Con Carne (with beans) and 15,000 cans of Mexene Chili Powder a day in
  their new factory in Austin, Texas. But Walker had already been selling
  canned Mexican foods for over a quarter century and may have been the first
  to can chili. Gebhardt's didn't start canning chili (as opposed to making
  chili powder) until 1911. Walker's 1918 recipe booklet had recipes for
  "chile huevos" and "chili mac" -- plus something called "combination chili
  con carne" -- one can chili mixed with one can tomatoes.
  
  Genuine Mexican Chile Con Carne. One pound of beef cut in small pieces; 1/4
  lb. beef suet, ground fine (or you can use lard). Add two tablespoons of
  Walker's Mexene, one medium sized onion minced; add water and boil until
  thoroughly cooked. The gravy from this chili con carne is fine for
  macaroni, spaghetti and vegetables. If beans are wanted, use any good red
  bean. For instance -- California Bayous, California Pinks or Pinto Beans.
  When these are not convenient, use French Red Kidney Beans. Boil the beans
  separately and add beans when serving.
  Posted to MC-Recipe Digest V1 #168
  
  Date: Thu, 25 Jul 1996 19:39:47 -0700
  
  From: Garry Howard &lt;g.howard@ix.netcom.com&gt;
  NOTES : MasterCook formatted by Garry Howard, Cambridge, MA
       g.howard@ix.netcom.com
       From the article "Just Another Bowl of Texas Red" by John Thorne
       in the September/October 1990 issue of Chile Pepper Magazine.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
