<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Walnut Phyllo Rounds</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Appetizers</cat></categories>
      <yield>6</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Phyllo pastry</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter, melted</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>FILLING</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Walnut pieces</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Pistachios or slivered almonds</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Chopped candied orange peel</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Granulated sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Orange blossom water, or 1 tsp almond extract</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Each, ground cinnamon and cloves</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>SYRUP</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Lemon</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Granulated sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Water</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  FILLING;  In food processor, combine walnuts, pistachios, candied peel,
  sugar, orange blossom water, cinnamon and cloves; process until finely
  chopped.
  
  Place one sheet of phyllo on work surface, covering remaining phyllo with
  damp tea towel to prevent drying out. Brush sheet with some of the butter.
  Top with another sheet of phyllo; brush with butter. Repeat with 2 more
  sheet of phyllo and butter.  Sprinkle with about 1/3 cup of the nut
  mixture.  Top with 3 more sheets of phyllo, brushing each with butter;
  sprinkle with 1/3 cup of the nut mixture. Repeat with 3 more sheets, then
  nuts to make a total of 9 sheets of phyllo.
  
  Brush the long edges of dough with butter.  Starting at long side, tightly
  roll up jelly-roll fashion. Brush all over with butter; trim edges. Cut
  into 3/4 inch thick slices; place on greased baking sheet. Repeat with
  remaining phyllo and filling to make second roll. Bake in 350 oven for 18
  to 20 minuts or until crisp and golden, turning over halfway through. Let
  cool for 5 minutes on baking sheets.  Remove to racks set on baking sheets.
  
  SYRUP:  Meanwhile, using vegetable peeler, peel lemon into thick strips. In
  saucepan, combie sugar, water and lemon rind; bring to boil. Reduce heat to
  medium-low and simmer for 25 to 30 minutes or until syrupy; strain. Spoon
  half of the hot syrup over phyllo rounds; let stand for 15 minutes. Spoon
  remaining syrup over top; let cool completely.  Makes about 42.
  
  Origin: Canadian Living Magazine, December 1990 issue. Sent by: Sharon
  Stevens
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
