<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Walnut Pie a la Mode</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Desserts</cat>
        <cat>Masterchefs</cat>
        <cat>Frisco</cat>
        <cat>Lec</cat></categories>
      <yield>12</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title>VANILLA ICE CREAM</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>quarts</unit></amt>
          <item>Milk</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>6</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Egg yolks</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>quarts</unit></amt>
          <item>Cream, heavy</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Bean, vanilla</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>WALNUT PIE</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Butter, cooled</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>pinch</unit></amt>
          <item>Salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Egg</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>large</unit></amt>
          <item>Egg yolk</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>pound</unit></amt>
          <item>Walnuts, chopped</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>3</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Cream, heavy</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Vanilla Ice Cream:
  ==================
  
       Cut the vanilla bean lengthwise into 4 sections and place it in a
  saucepan with the milk.  Brink the milk to a boil and remove from heat.
  
       In a stainless bowl, whip the egg yolks and sugar until foamy. Strain
  the milk into the egg mixture.  Place the bowl on a double-boiler and mix
  with a wooden spatula until the mixture thickens and adheres to the
  spatula.  Remove the bowl from the double-boiler and add heavy cream.
  
       Place the mixture in a refrigerator until cold.
  
       Pour the mixture into an ice cream freezer and churn for 30 minutes or
  until stiff.
  
  Walnut Pie:
  ===========
  
       In a large bowl, combine the sugar, cooled butter, and salt.  Add
  flour 1 cup at a time and mix.
  
       Add 1 egg and mix well but do not overwork.
  
       Divide the dough mixture into two portions 2/3 and 1/3 parts of the
  dough.  Let the dough rest in a refrigerator for at least 2 hours,
  overnight if possible.  Roll out the 2/3 portion of dough until it's 13
  inches in diameter.  Place this layer in a buttered 10-inch pie plate.
  Leave any excess dough hanging over the edge of the plate.
  
       Place this dough in the refrigerator.
  
       Roll out the 1/3 portion of dough until it's 11 inches in diameter.
  Refrigerate on waxed paper.
  
  Walnut Filling:
  ===============
  
       In a saucepan over medium heat, boil the heavy cream and sugar until
  reduced by one-half.  Add the walnuts and cook for 5 minutes.
  
       Pour the cooked mixture into a bowl and refrigerate.
  
  Assembly:
  =========
  
       Remove the pie plate from the refrigerator and fill it with cooled
  walnut mixture.  Take 1 beaten egg yolk and brush the pie dough around the
  lip of the plate.  Cover the pie with the top dough, press around the
  edges, and remove any excess dough.
  
       Score the dough with a fork in a crisscross pattern, then bake it in a
  375 F oven for 30 minutes.
  
       Refrigerate until cold and serve topped with ice cream.
  
       Source:  Great Chefs of San Francisco, Avon Books, 1984
  
       Chef:   Max Schacher, Le Coquelicot, Ross, Marin County, CA
  
  File ftp://ftp.idiscover.co.uk/pub/food/mealmaster/recipes/mm-gc-sf.zip
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
