<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>Walnut-Maple Caramels</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Chopped walnuts</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Brown sugar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Whipping cream</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Maple syrup</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Vanilla</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  1. Line an 8x8x2-inch baking pan with foil, extending foil over edges of
  pan. Spray with with vegetable oil. Sprinkle chopped walnuts on the bottom
  of the foil-lined pan; set pan aside.
  
  2. In a heavy 3-quart saucepan melt the butter over low heat. Add the sugar
  cream maple syrup and mix well. Cook over medium-high heat to boiling,
  stirring constantly with a wooden spoon to dissolve sugar. This should take
  6 to 8 minutes. Avoid splashing the mixture on sides of pan. Carefully clip
  candy thermometer to side of pan.
  
  3. Cook over medium heat, stirring frequently, till candy thermometer
  registers 248F, firm-ball stage. Mixture should boil at moderate, steady
  rate over entire surfacce. Reaching firm-ball stage should take 45 to 55
  minutes.
  
  4. Remove saucepan from heat; remove candy thermometer from sauccepan.
  Immediately stir in vanilla. Quickly pour the caramel mixture over the nuts
  in the prepared pan.
  
  5. Cool. When caramel is firm, use foil to lift it out of pan. Use a knife
  to cut candy into 1-inch squares. Wrap each piece in cleaar plastic wrap.
  Makes 64 pieces or about 2 pounds.
  
  Note: I did not wrap them but put them in small bags (10 per bag) and store
  them in the freezer that's how I like them cold and hard. Warning they are
  very rich. Enjoy and happy holidays.
  
  Posted to TNT - Prodigy's Recipe Exchange Newsletter  by
  gladysdinletir@superonline.com (Gladys Dinletir) on Dec 27, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
